<article article-type="Journal Article">
  <front>
    <journal-meta>
      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher">lpbb20</journal-id>
      <journal-title-group>
        <journal-title>Preparative Biochemistry &amp; Biotechnology</journal-title>
      </journal-title-group>
      <issn>1082-6068</issn>
      <issn>1532-2297</issn>
      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Taylor &amp; Francis</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/10826068.2023.2166959</article-id>
      <article-id pub-id-type="pii">2166959</article-id>
      <article-id pub-id-type="wtfid">010428028_0000001_231006024606826733</article-id>
      <article-id pub-id-type="pmid">36756987</article-id>
      <article-id pub-id-type="tdm">taylorfrancis_TDM-10.1080/10826068.2023.2166959</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title>Effects of various pine needle extracts on Chinese hamster ovary cell growth and monoclonal antibody quality</article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <surname>Zhang</surname>
          <given-names>Dingyue</given-names>
          <aff>Anhui University of Chinese Medicine</aff>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <surname>Qiu</surname>
          <given-names>Jinshu</given-names>
          <aff>Thousand Oaks Biopharmaceuticals Co., Ltd</aff>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <surname>Niu</surname>
          <given-names>Qing-Tian</given-names>
          <aff>Thousand Oaks Biopharmaceuticals Co., Ltd</aff>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <surname>Liu</surname>
          <given-names>Tingting</given-names>
          <aff>Thousand Oaks Biopharmaceuticals Co., Ltd</aff>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <surname>Gu</surname>
          <given-names>Rulin</given-names>
          <aff>Thousand Oaks Biopharmaceuticals Co., Ltd</aff>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <surname>Zhang</surname>
          <given-names>Xiaoying</given-names>
          <aff>Thousand Oaks Biopharmaceuticals Co., Ltd</aff>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <surname>Luo</surname>
          <given-names>Shun</given-names>
          <aff>Anhui University of Chinese Medicine</aff>
        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date pub-type="pub">
        <day>3</day>
        <month>10</month>
        <year>2023</year>
      </pub-date>
      <volume>53</volume>
      <issue>9</issue>
      <fpage>1081</fpage>
      <lpage>1091</lpage>
      <abstract>
        <p>Abstract  Chinese hamster ovary (CHO) cells are commonly used as “bio-machines” to pro-duce monoclonal antibodies (mAb) because of their ability to produce very complex proteins. In this study, we evaluated the effects of pine needle water extract (PNWE), pine needle ethanol extract (PNEE), and pine needle polysaccharide extract (PNPE) on the CHO cell growth, mAb production and quality using a Fed-batch culture process. PNPE maintained high VCD and viability, and the titer increase was correlated with its concentration. Three extracts effectively reduced the acidic charge variant and modulated mAb glycosylation. PNPE had the most profound effect, with G0F decreasing by 8.7% and G1Fa increasing by 6.7%. The change in the glycoform was also closely related to the PNPE concentration. This study demonstrated that PNPE could facilitate CHO cell growth, increase the mAb production, decrease acidic charge variants, and regulate mAb glycoforms. To identify the components responsible for the above changes, the sugar and flavonoid contents in the extracts were determined, and the chemical compounds were identified by LC-MS, resulting in 38 compounds identified from PNPE. Rich in sugars and flavonoids in these three extracts may be related to increased CHO cell growth and productivity, and changes in glycoforms.</p>
      </abstract>
      <kwd-group>
        <kwd>Charge variants</kwd>
        <kwd>CHO cell culture</kwd>
        <kwd>glycosylation</kwd>
        <kwd>pine needle extracts</kwd>
      </kwd-group>
      <kwd-group kwd-group-type="MESH Chemical">
        <items>
          <chemical.registryNumber>0</chemical.registryNumber>
          <chemical.name>Antibodies, Monoclonal</chemical.name>
          <chemical.ui>D000911</chemical.ui>
        </items>
      </kwd-group>
      <kwd-group kwd-group-type="MESH Subject Heading">
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Cricetinae</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Animals</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Cricetulus</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Antibodies, Monoclonal</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>Y</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>CHO Cells</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Batch Cell Culture Techniques</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>Y</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
          <meshHeading.qualifier>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.name>methods</meshHeading.qualifier.name>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.ui>Q000379</meshHeading.qualifier.ui>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.qualifier>
        </items>
      </kwd-group>
      <sec sec-type="intro">
        <p>Introduction  With the successful uses of mAb therapeutics to treat human diseases, the identification of suitable supplements for the development of new CHO cell culture media to increase mAb yields have become extremely important.[ 1 ] From the traditional animal serum medium to the chemically defined (CD) medium used today, medium components and their concentrations for increasing the yield of different types of mAbs have been greatly improved. Since the CD medium does not need to add substances, such as fetal bovine serum (FBS), the variation between media batches decreases greatly. As a result, the repeatability of the CHO cell culture increases, and the process becomes more stable and robust.[ 2 ] Recombinant proteins with specific characteristics can be obtained by developing a CHO cell line with a unique gene expression. However, the culture medium components and supplements can impact post-translational modifications of mAb.[ 3 ] In fact, the optimization of medium and supplement composition will affect the cell growth and the quality of protein produced by CHO cells.[ 4–6 ] Supplements are designed to replenish nutrients depleted in the basal medium, relieve cell stress, support cell growth, and ensure better mAb production. These supplements are usually added to media at the different stages during the cell culture processes, such as fed-batch culture.[ 7 , 8 ] Due to the high specificity of nutrients required for cell growth and product quality, it is necessary to evaluate the unique benefits of supplements in combination with culture media.[ 9 ] The results of these studies should provide critical information for designing new CD media and CD supplements to maximize the cell growth, increase the mAb titer, and control the product quality.[ 10 ] Many studies have found that pine needles are extremely rich in flavonoids, vitamins, amino acids, mineral elements, alkaloids, and polysaccharides.[ 11 ] And possess hypoglycemic, lipid regulation, antitumor, anti-aging, and antibacterial properties.[ 12 , 13 ] The natural water-soluble bioflavonoid concentrates and alkaloids from pine needle extracts have antioxidant activity functions, which can effectively remove free radicals.[ 14–16 ] Plant polysaccharides have a wide range of biological activities and desirable functional properties.[ 17 ] It has been reported that some small antioxidant molecules without direct nutritional value added to the cell culture medium can increase the productivity of CHO cells or protect the mAb from being oxidized.[ 18 ] Many infrequently used sugars, and the corresponding cellular response toward them as substrates led to differences in the protein N-glycosylation profile of a recombinant glycoprotein.[ 19 ] It has also been reported that the addition of bioflavonoids to animal cell cultures can effectively reduce the acidic charge variants on recombinant mAbs and their dual variable regions. Besides reducing the acidic charge variants of mAbs, the use of bioflavonoids can improve the structure and function of antibodies to varying degrees,[ 20 ] as well as product quality with less heterogeneity. The antioxidants, bioflavonoids, and polysaccharides in the pine needle extract have potential effects on the growth of CHO cells and the production of mAbs.  In this study, three types of Masson pine needle extracts, water extract (PNWE), ethanol extract (PNEE), and polysaccharide extract (PNPE), were used to evaluate their effects on CHO cell growth, cell metabolism, and titer, charge variant, glycosylation and biological activity of mAb in a fed-batch process. The contents of carbohydrates, flavonoids, and chemical compounds in the pine needle extracts were determined to identify the possible relationship with the components present in these extracts. To our knowledge, there is not a precedent report for the use of pine needle extracts as supplements for CHO cell culture media.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec sec-type="materials|methods">
        <p>Materials and methods  Chemicals, reagents, and pine needle extracts  Dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) and dextrose dry powder were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich (USA). Formic acid, methanol, acetonitrile, water, and trifluoroacetic acid (TFA) were ordered from Thermo Fisher Scientific (USA). Phenol concentrated sulfuric acid, sodium chloride, sodium hydroxide, phosphate-buffered saline (PBS), and aluminum chloride were purchased from Sinopharm Chemical Reagent Co., Ltd., China. Rutin standard was ordered from Chengdu Nakeli Bio-Technology Corp. China. Chemically defined medium CHO 050, and supplement CD Feed were provided by Jianshun Biotechnology Co., Ltd., China, and the cell line used was a stable recombinant CHO K1 cell line provided by Thousand Oaks Biopharmaceuticals Corp., China. PNWE and PNEE were purchased from Shaanxi Sinuote Biotechnology Co., Ltd., China. PNPE was obtained from Lanzhou Wotelaisi Biotechnology Corp., China. PNWE and PNEE were extracted from the pine needle by water and 75% ethanol, respectively. PNPE were obtained from the pine needle by multi-step extraction with water. In PNPE 50% of the active ingredients are the polysaccharides according to the specification. Determinations of carbohydrate and flavonoid contents  The carbohydrate content in the pine needle extracts was determined through the method of phenol-sulfuric acid using glucose as the standard. A stock solution with a glucose concentration of 0.1 mg/mL was prepared in water. A set of the standard solutions ranging from 0.02 to 1.0 mg/mL glucose were made for the standard curve. The sample (1 mg) was added to 10 mL of purified water and sonicated for 30 min. The supernatant was analyzed for the carbohydrate content. After adding 0.5 mL of 6% phenol and 2.5 mL of concentrated sulfuric acid solution to 1 mL of the standard and sample solutions, respectively, they were mixed and cooled at room temperature for 30 min, and absorbance at 490 nm was measured with an Evolution 260 Bio UV-Vis spectrophotometer (Thermo Fisher Scientific, USA). The carbohydrate content in the sample was determined from the standard curve. The flavonoid content in the pine needle extracts was determined by using an aluminum chloride colorimetric method. Rutin dissolved in 50% methanol was used as the flavonoid standard and the standard calibration curve was prepared in the concentrations ranging from 10 and 80 µg/mL. For the extraction of flavornoids, 200 mg of the sample was added in 20 mL of 50% methanol, and sonicated for 30 min. The sample extract (2 mL) was then mixed with 1 mL of 1% aluminum chloride and 7 mL of 50% methanol. The mixtures were allowed to stand for 30 min at the room temperature and the absorbance was measured at 277 nm spectrophotometrically. The flavonoid content in the sample was determined from the standard curve. Identification of chemical compounds  Each of the pine needle extracts (1 g) was accurately weighed into a 50 mL centrifugal tube and 20 mL of 75% methanol solution was added. Sonicated for 30 min, and the solution was filtrated. A 10.0-mL of the filtrate was dried under a reduced pressure. The dried sample was re-dissolved in 5 mL 75% methanol and then filtered with a 0.22 µm Polyether sulfone (PES) membrane. The filtrate was used for the identification of the chemical compounds. Identification was performed using a Zeno TOF 7600 mass spectrometer (SCIEX, USA) equipped with a Sepax GP-C18 analytical column (1.8 µm 2.1 × 150 mm, Sepax Technologies, Inc., China) and an ACQUITY UPLC system (Waters, USA). Mobile phase A was 0.1% formic acid in water and Mobile phase B was 0.1% formic acid in acetonitrile. The mobile gradient was 5% B at the first 3 min, 5–75%B from 3 to 10 min, 75–100% B from 10 to 10.5 min, 100% B from 10.5 to 16.5 min, and 100–5% B from 16.5 to 20 min. The column temperature was 35 °C and the flow rate was 0. 3 mL/min. The ESI ion source was used for the analysis. The ESI ion source settings were as follows: ion source gases 1 and 2 at 60 psi, curtain gas at 35 psi, CAD gas at 9 psi, temperature at 600 °C. TOF start-stop mass between 30 and 1000 Da, declustering potential at −80 V, collision energy at −10 V. MS/MS conditions were as follows: TOF start-stop mass between 20 and 1000 Da, collision energy at −35 V, CE spread at 15 V, accumulation time at 0.15 s, and an injection volume at 3 µL. The compound identification was carried out through the Sciex database and the compound was confirmed with both TIC and MS/MS spectrum matching scores of &gt;70%. Cell fed-batch culture  The stock solutions of the pine needle extracts were prepared in water at a concentration of 10 mg/mL. The stock solutions were sonicated for 30 min to allow the extracts to be dissolved completely and then filtered by 0.22 µm PES membrane before use. The cell line was serially propagated through separate seed train inoculums to generate enough cells for inoculation. Based on the preliminary experimental results, it was decided to use three concentrations of 5, 10, and 15 mg/L as the experimental concentration of the subsequent fed-batch culture for PNWE and PNEE. PNPE has a large concentration span, considering that the polysaccharide components have different effects on the charge variants and glycosylation of subsequent mAbs, three concentrations of 5, 50, and 100 mg/L were determined as the experimental concentrations of fed-batch culture. Nine experimental treatments with one control were used and each treatment including the control replicated three times. Independent cultures were performed in 50-mL cell culture TPP tubes (Switzerland). The working volume in each tube was 25 mL, and the seeding density was 1.0 × 106 viable cells/mL. The extracts were added to the cell culture media on Day 0 and the cells were harvested on Day 14. VCD and cell viability were determined with Vi-cell XR (Beckman Coulter, USA). Glucose, glutamine, lactate, ammonium, glutamate, pH, and osmolarity were determined with a BioProfile 400 (Nova BioMedical, USA). All samples were taken daily and assayed before feeding. The cells were fed with the CD feed on the 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, and 13 days, respectively. The two types of CD feeds were added at 4 and 0.4% of the feeding-day culture volume, respectively. Glucose was always kept at a concentration between 2 and 3 g/L based on the results tested daily. When the VCD exceeded 1.0 × 106 viable cells/mL, the cell density of the sample was diluted in a 1:1 ratio with PBS before measurement. A temperature was shifted from 37 to 32 °C on the 7th day of the culture. After the 14th day, the samples were centrifuged with a high-speed refrigerated centrifuge (Beckman Coulter, USA) at 20 °C, 3900 g for 30 min, and the supernatants were collected, respectively. The mAb titer assay  An e2695 HPLC system (Waters, USA) with a TSKgel Protein A-5PW affinity chromatography column (TOSOH, Japan) was used to determine the mAb titer concentration in the supernatant. The mobile phase A was a 20 mmol/L phosphate buffer (NaH2PO4·H2O + Na2HPO4) at pH 7.0, and the mobile phase B was 20 mmol/L phosphate buffer at pH 2.5. The standard and samples were diluted with the mobile phase A before analysis. The chromatographic conditions were as follows: the sample chamber temperature at 10 °C, the column temperature at 25 °C, and the flow rate at 2 mL/min. The sample was separated by the pH gradient from 0% B to 100% B in 2 min. The eluted titer was detected at a wavelength of 280 nm and the titer concentration was calculated using the standard curve ranging from 0.2 to 4.0 mg/mL. The mAb purification  The samples were purified by affinity chromatography on a 1-mL mAb Purix A65 gravity column (Sepax Technologies, China). The gravity column was washed first with purified water, disinfected with ≥5 mL of the 0.1 M NaOH solution, and rinsed with an affinity equilibrium solution (20 mM phosphate buffer and 150 mM NaCl at pH 7) until the droplets became neutral. The column was then further equilibrated with the affinity equilibration solution. The sample was loaded on the column and washed with the affinity equilibration solution. The mAb was eluted with ≥5 mL of the 25 mM sodium citrate-citric acid buffer at pH 3.5. The eluted mAb was collected, and the concentration was determined. The purified mAb was stored at −80 °C for the purity analyses. The purity analysis by size exclusion chromatography  The purified mAb samples were analyzed using a Vanquish HPLC system (Thermo Fisher, USA) equipped with a TSKgel G3000SWxl molecular size exclusion column (TOSOH, Japan). The 50 mM phosphate and 300 mM NaCl buffer at pH 6.8 was used as a mobile phase. The flow rate was 0.8 mL/min, the injection volume was 10 µL, the column temperature was 25 °C, the acquisition wavelength was 280 nm, and the sample chamber temperature was 10 °C. The level of aggregation was expressed as the relative percentage of peak areas. The purity analysis by strong cation exchange chromatography  The purified mAb samples were also analyzed with a Proteomix SCX-NP analytical column (5 µm, 4.6 × 150 mm, Sepax Technologies) equipped with a Vanquish HPLC system. The samples were first desalted by liquid exchange. The mAb sample (100 µg) was added to a 10 kD ultrafiltration tube, purified water (500 µL) added, vortexed, and centrifuged at 13,000 rpm for 10 min. The mAb concentration in the retentate was measured with a NanoDrop one spectrophotometer. After desalting, the samples were diluted to 5.0 mg/mL with purified water and then mixed by vortex before injection. The HPLC system consisted of four mobile phases: 125 mM sodium dihydrogen phosphate as mobile phase A, 125 mM disodium phosphate as mobile phase B, 1 M sodium chloride solution as mobile phase C, and ultra-pure water as mobile phase D. For the separation, the mobile phases A and B were maintained at constant rates of 9.3 and 40.7%, respectively at the entire duration. The mobile phase C was increased from 4 to 40% in 30 min. The flow rate was 0.5 mL/min. Protein peaks were measured by UV absorption at 280 nm. The glycosylation assay  The GlycoWorks RapiFluor-MS N-glycan kit (Waters, USA) was used for sample preparation of the glycan analysis. First, the sample was diluted to 2 mg/mL with purified water. Then a 7.5 µL of the diluted sample was denatured, cooled, and incubated to release glycosyl groups, and RapiFluor-MS reagents were added to label the glycosyl groups. Finally, the sample was loaded on GlycoWorks HILIC µElution extraction plate for activation, cleaning, elution, and dilution before injection for HPLC analysis. The prepared glycan samples were analyzed by an ACQUITY UPLC system with a glycan BEH amide column (2.1 × 150 mm, 130 Å, 1.7 µm, Waters, USA), using a solution of 50 mM ammonium formate at pH 4.4 as mobile phase A and 100% acetonitrile as mobile phase B. The column temperature was kept at 60 °C, and the flow rate was stabilized at 0.4 mL/min, gradient elution was performed. The separated glycans were detected with a fluorescence detector with an excitation wavelength of 265 nm and the emission wavelength of 425 nm. After the glycosylation profile was obtained, the glycan species of the known glycosylation profile of the antibody protein were calibrated, and the glycosylation changes were analyzed according to the normalized peak areas. The mAb binding activity assay  The relative binding activity of mAb was determined by an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA). IgE (100 µL/well, Shanghai Maitai Junao Biotechnology Co., Ltd., China) was added to the microtiter plate (Corning, USA) for antigen coating, and incubated overnight in a refrigerator at 2–8 °C. The next day, PBST (1000 mL 10 mM PBS and 0.5 mL Tween 20) plus 3%BSA (Sigma, USA) was used as the blocking solution, PBST + 1%BSA as the diluent solution. The sample was diluted to 10 µg/mL, and then further diluted to 12 concentration points at a 3-fold dilution for each consequent point. Goat anti-human Kappa-HRP (Southern Biotech, USA) was used as the secondary antibody. A 3,3′,5,5′-tetramethylbenzidine chromogenic solution (50 µL/well, Kangwei Century, China) was added to develop color and finally, a 0.5 M H2SO4 solution (50 µL/well) was added to stop the color reaction. The SpectraMax iD5 multi-function microplate reader (Molecular Devices, USA) was used to read the absorbance at wavelengths of 450 and 570 nm, respectively. The curve was drawn using the four-parameter fitting regression model with the SoftMax Pro computer software. The half-maximal effect concentration (EC50) from the curve was obtained, and the relative activity was reported by calculating the EC50 ratio of the control to the experimental sample. Statistical analysis  Results were analyzed by GraphPad Prism 9.0 software (GraphPad, United States). The data were expressed as means ± SD of three independent experiments performed in triplicate measurements. An ANOVA analysis was used to evaluate the differences among the treatments.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec sec-type="conclusions">
        <p>Conclusion  In this study, the contents of carbohydrates and flavonoids in the three pine needle extracts were determined, and 38 compounds in the pine needle polysaccharide extract were identified. It has been demonstrated that the pine needle polysaccharide extract can be used to improve the viable cell density and viability of CHO cells and increase the mAb production. Furthermore, the pine needle polysaccharide extract was able to reduce the level of acidic charge variants and modulate the glycosylation profile. The utilization of natural plant extracts is a new research area to develop new raw materials for controlling the quality of biopharmaceutical products, especially biosimilars. Our pioneering exploration provides a new direction for future cell culture process optimization and the development of a culture medium system.</p>
      </sec>
      <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
  <body><![CDATA[<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article"><!--
input file: LPBB_A_2166959_J.xml
processed with: d3p_fulltext_nlm3_from_jats12.xsl
version: 1.19
darts-xml-transformations-20230119T200553 git hash: 724830af20
-->
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-acronym">LPBB</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">lpbb20</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Preparative Biochemistry &amp;amp; Biotechnology</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">1082-6068</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">1532-2297</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Taylor &amp;amp; Francis</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/10826068.2023.2166959</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2166959</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="submission-id">223115154</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group subj-group-type="article-type">
               <subject>Research Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
            <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
               <subject>Research Articles</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effects of various pine needle extracts on Chinese hamster ovary cell growth and monoclonal antibody quality</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <uri content-type="orcid">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-0826-0400</uri>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Dingyue</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="AF0001">
                  <sup>a</sup>
               </xref>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="AF0002">
                  <sup>b</sup>
               </xref>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Jinshu</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Qiu</surname>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="AF0003">
                  <sup>c</sup>
               </xref>
               <xref ref-type="corresp" rid="AN0002"/>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Qing-Tian</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Niu</surname>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="AF0003">
                  <sup>c</sup>
               </xref>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Tingting</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Liu</surname>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="AF0003">
                  <sup>c</sup>
               </xref>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Rulin</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Gu</surname>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="AF0003">
                  <sup>c</sup>
               </xref>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Xiaoying</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="AF0003">
                  <sup>c</sup>
               </xref>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> &amp;amp; </x>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Shun</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Luo</surname>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="AF0001">
                  <sup>a</sup>
               </xref>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="AF0003">
                  <sup>c</sup>
               </xref>
               <xref ref-type="corresp" rid="AN0001"/>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="AF0001">
               <label>
                  <sup>a</sup>
               </label>
               <institution>Anhui University of Chinese Medicine</institution>, <named-content content-type="city">Hefei</named-content>, <country>China</country>
            </aff>
            <aff id="AF0002">
               <label>
                  <sup>b</sup>
               </label>
               <institution>Yangtze Delta Drug Advanced Research Institute</institution>, <named-content content-type="city">Nantong</named-content>, <country>China</country>
            </aff>
            <aff id="AF0003">
               <label>
                  <sup>c</sup>
               </label>
               <institution>Thousand Oaks Biopharmaceuticals Co., Ltd</institution>., <named-content content-type="city">Nantong</named-content>, <country>China</country>
            </aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <author-notes>
            <corresp id="AN0001">
               <bold>CONTACT</bold> Shun Luo <ext-link ext-link-type="email" href="mailto:shun.luo@tobiopharm.com">shun.luo@tobiopharm.com</ext-link>
               <institution>Anhui University of Chinese Medicine</institution>, <named-content content-type="city">Hefei</named-content>, <country>China</country>; <institution>Thousand Oaks Biopharmaceuticals Co., Ltd</institution>., <named-content content-type="city">Nantong</named-content>, <country>China</country>
            </corresp>
            <corresp id="AN0002">Jinshu Qiu <ext-link ext-link-type="email" href="mailto:jinshu.qiu@tobiopharm.com">jinshu.qiu@tobiopharm.com</ext-link>
               <institution>Thousand Oaks Biopharmaceuticals Co., Ltd</institution>., <named-content content-type="city">Nantong</named-content>, <country>China</country>.</corresp>
         </author-notes>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>3</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2023</year>
            <string-date>October 2023</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>53</volume>
         <issue>9</issue>
         <fpage seq="5">1081</fpage>
         <lpage>1091</lpage>
         <history/>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2023 Taylor &amp;amp; Francis Group, LLC</copyright-statement>
            <copyright-year>2023</copyright-year>
            <copyright-holder>Taylor &amp;amp; Francis</copyright-holder>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri content-type="pdf" href="10826068.2023.2166959.pdf"/>
         <abstract>
            <title>Abstract</title>
            <p>Chinese hamster ovary (CHO) cells are commonly used as “bio-machines” to pro-duce monoclonal antibodies (mAb) because of their ability to produce very complex proteins. In this study, we evaluated the effects of pine needle water extract (PNWE), pine needle ethanol extract (PNEE), and pine needle polysaccharide extract (PNPE) on the CHO cell growth, mAb production and quality using a Fed-batch culture process. PNPE maintained high VCD and viability, and the titer increase was correlated with its concentration. Three extracts effectively reduced the acidic charge variant and modulated mAb glycosylation. PNPE had the most profound effect, with G0F decreasing by 8.7% and G1Fa increasing by 6.7%. The change in the glycoform was also closely related to the PNPE concentration. This study demonstrated that PNPE could facilitate CHO cell growth, increase the mAb production, decrease acidic charge variants, and regulate mAb glycoforms. To identify the components responsible for the above changes, the sugar and flavonoid contents in the extracts were determined, and the chemical compounds were identified by LC-MS, resulting in 38 compounds identified from PNPE. Rich in sugars and flavonoids in these three extracts may be related to increased CHO cell growth and productivity, and changes in glycoforms.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
            <title>Keywords</title>
            <kwd>Charge variants</kwd>
            <kwd>CHO cell culture</kwd>
            <kwd>glycosylation</kwd>
            <kwd>pine needle extracts</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <funding-group>
            <funding-statement>The author(s) reported there is no funding associated with the work featured in this article.</funding-statement>
         </funding-group>
         <counts>
            <fig-count count="5"/>
            <table-count count="4"/>
            <page-count count="11"/>
            <word-count count="7270"/>
         </counts>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="S0001" disp-level="1" sec-type="intro">
         <title>Introduction</title>
         <p>With the successful uses of mAb therapeutics to treat human diseases, the identification of suitable supplements for the development of new CHO cell culture media to increase mAb yields have become extremely important.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0001">
               <sup>1</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> From the traditional animal serum medium to the chemically defined (CD) medium used today, medium components and their concentrations for increasing the yield of different types of mAbs have been greatly improved. Since the CD medium does not need to add substances, such as fetal bovine serum (FBS), the variation between media batches decreases greatly. As a result, the repeatability of the CHO cell culture increases, and the process becomes more stable and robust.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0002">
               <sup>2</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup>
         </p>
         <p>Recombinant proteins with specific characteristics can be obtained by developing a CHO cell line with a unique gene expression. However, the culture medium components and supplements can impact post-translational modifications of mAb.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0003">
               <sup>3</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> In fact, the optimization of medium and supplement composition will affect the cell growth and the quality of protein produced by CHO cells.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0004 CIT0005 CIT0006">
               <sup>4–6</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> Supplements are designed to replenish nutrients depleted in the basal medium, relieve cell stress, support cell growth, and ensure better mAb production. These supplements are usually added to media at the different stages during the cell culture processes, such as fed-batch culture.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0007">
               <sup>7</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>,</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0008">
               <sup>8</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> Due to the high specificity of nutrients required for cell growth and product quality, it is necessary to evaluate the unique benefits of supplements in combination with culture media.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0009">
               <sup>9</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> The results of these studies should provide critical information for designing new CD media and CD supplements to maximize the cell growth, increase the mAb titer, and control the product quality.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0010">
               <sup>10</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup>
         </p>
         <p>Many studies have found that pine needles are extremely rich in flavonoids, vitamins, amino acids, mineral elements, alkaloids, and polysaccharides.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0011">
               <sup>11</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> And possess hypoglycemic, lipid regulation, antitumor, anti-aging, and antibacterial properties.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0012">
               <sup>12</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>,</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0013">
               <sup>13</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> The natural water-soluble bioflavonoid concentrates and alkaloids from pine needle extracts have antioxidant activity functions, which can effectively remove free radicals.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0014 CIT0015 CIT0016">
               <sup>14–16</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> Plant polysaccharides have a wide range of biological activities and desirable functional properties.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0017">
               <sup>17</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> It has been reported that some small antioxidant molecules without direct nutritional value added to the cell culture medium can increase the productivity of CHO cells or protect the mAb from being oxidized.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0018">
               <sup>18</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> Many infrequently used sugars, and the corresponding cellular response toward them as substrates led to differences in the protein N-glycosylation profile of a recombinant glycoprotein.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0019">
               <sup>19</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> It has also been reported that the addition of bioflavonoids to animal cell cultures can effectively reduce the acidic charge variants on recombinant mAbs and their dual variable regions. Besides reducing the acidic charge variants of mAbs, the use of bioflavonoids can improve the structure and function of antibodies to varying degrees,<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0020">
               <sup>20</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> as well as product quality with less heterogeneity. The antioxidants, bioflavonoids, and polysaccharides in the pine needle extract have potential effects on the growth of CHO cells and the production of mAbs.</p>
         <p>In this study, three types of Masson pine needle extracts, water extract (PNWE), ethanol extract (PNEE), and polysaccharide extract (PNPE), were used to evaluate their effects on CHO cell growth, cell metabolism, and titer, charge variant, glycosylation and biological activity of mAb in a fed-batch process. The contents of carbohydrates, flavonoids, and chemical compounds in the pine needle extracts were determined to identify the possible relationship with the components present in these extracts. To our knowledge, there is not a precedent report for the use of pine needle extracts as supplements for CHO cell culture media.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="S0002" disp-level="1" sec-type="materials">
         <title>Materials and methods</title>
         <sec id="S0002-S2001" disp-level="2">
            <title>Chemicals, reagents, and pine needle extracts</title>
            <p>Dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) and dextrose dry powder were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich (USA). Formic acid, methanol, acetonitrile, water, and trifluoroacetic acid (TFA) were ordered from Thermo Fisher Scientific (USA). Phenol concentrated sulfuric acid, sodium chloride, sodium hydroxide, phosphate-buffered saline (PBS), and aluminum chloride were purchased from Sinopharm Chemical Reagent Co., Ltd., China. Rutin standard was ordered from Chengdu Nakeli Bio-Technology Corp. China. Chemically defined medium CHO 050, and supplement CD Feed were provided by Jianshun Biotechnology Co., Ltd., China, and the cell line used was a stable recombinant CHO K1 cell line provided by Thousand Oaks Biopharmaceuticals Corp., China. PNWE and PNEE were purchased from Shaanxi Sinuote Biotechnology Co., Ltd., China. PNPE was obtained from Lanzhou Wotelaisi Biotechnology Corp., China. PNWE and PNEE were extracted from the pine needle by water and 75% ethanol, respectively. PNPE were obtained from the pine needle by multi-step extraction with water. In PNPE 50% of the active ingredients are the polysaccharides according to the specification.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0002-S2002" disp-level="2">
            <title>Determinations of carbohydrate and flavonoid contents</title>
            <p>The carbohydrate content in the pine needle extracts was determined through the method of phenol-sulfuric acid using glucose as the standard. A stock solution with a glucose concentration of 0.1 mg/mL was prepared in water. A set of the standard solutions ranging from 0.02 to 1.0 mg/mL glucose were made for the standard curve. The sample (1 mg) was added to 10 mL of purified water and sonicated for 30 min. The supernatant was analyzed for the carbohydrate content. After adding 0.5 mL of 6% phenol and 2.5 mL of concentrated sulfuric acid solution to 1 mL of the standard and sample solutions, respectively, they were mixed and cooled at room temperature for 30 min, and absorbance at 490 nm was measured with an Evolution 260 Bio UV-Vis spectrophotometer (Thermo Fisher Scientific, USA). The carbohydrate content in the sample was determined from the standard curve.</p>
            <p>The flavonoid content in the pine needle extracts was determined by using an aluminum chloride colorimetric method. Rutin dissolved in 50% methanol was used as the flavonoid standard and the standard calibration curve was prepared in the concentrations ranging from 10 and 80 µg/mL. For the extraction of flavornoids, 200 mg of the sample was added in 20 mL of 50% methanol, and sonicated for 30 min. The sample extract (2 mL) was then mixed with 1 mL of 1% aluminum chloride and 7 mL of 50% methanol. The mixtures were allowed to stand for 30 min at the room temperature and the absorbance was measured at 277 nm spectrophotometrically. The flavonoid content in the sample was determined from the standard curve.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0002-S2003" disp-level="2">
            <title>Identification of chemical compounds</title>
            <p>Each of the pine needle extracts (1 g) was accurately weighed into a 50 mL centrifugal tube and 20 mL of 75% methanol solution was added. Sonicated for 30 min, and the solution was filtrated. A 10.0-mL of the filtrate was dried under a reduced pressure. The dried sample was re-dissolved in 5 mL 75% methanol and then filtered with a 0.22 µm Polyether sulfone (PES) membrane. The filtrate was used for the identification of the chemical compounds.</p>
            <p>Identification was performed using a Zeno TOF 7600 mass spectrometer (SCIEX, USA) equipped with a Sepax GP-C18 analytical column (1.8 µm 2.1 × 150 mm, Sepax Technologies, Inc., China) and an ACQUITY UPLC system (Waters, USA). Mobile phase A was 0.1% formic acid in water and Mobile phase B was 0.1% formic acid in acetonitrile. The mobile gradient was 5% B at the first 3 min, 5–75%B from 3 to 10 min, 75–100% B from 10 to 10.5 min, 100% B from 10.5 to 16.5 min, and 100–5% B from 16.5 to 20 min. The column temperature was 35 °C and the flow rate was 0. 3 mL/min. The ESI ion source was used for the analysis. The ESI ion source settings were as follows: ion source gases 1 and 2 at 60 psi, curtain gas at 35 psi, CAD gas at 9 psi, temperature at 600 °C. TOF start-stop mass between 30 and 1000 Da, declustering potential at −80 V, collision energy at −10 V. MS/MS conditions were as follows: TOF start-stop mass between 20 and 1000 Da, collision energy at −35 V, CE spread at 15 V, accumulation time at 0.15 s, and an injection volume at 3 µL. The compound identification was carried out through the Sciex database and the compound was confirmed with both TIC and MS/MS spectrum matching scores of &amp;gt;70%.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0002-S2004" disp-level="2">
            <title>Cell fed-batch culture</title>
            <p>The stock solutions of the pine needle extracts were prepared in water at a concentration of 10 mg/mL. The stock solutions were sonicated for 30 min to allow the extracts to be dissolved completely and then filtered by 0.22 µm PES membrane before use. The cell line was serially propagated through separate seed train inoculums to generate enough cells for inoculation. Based on the preliminary experimental results, it was decided to use three concentrations of 5, 10, and 15 mg/L as the experimental concentration of the subsequent fed-batch culture for PNWE and PNEE. PNPE has a large concentration span, considering that the polysaccharide components have different effects on the charge variants and glycosylation of subsequent mAbs, three concentrations of 5, 50, and 100 mg/L were determined as the experimental concentrations of fed-batch culture. Nine experimental treatments with one control were used and each treatment including the control replicated three times. Independent cultures were performed in 50-mL cell culture TPP tubes (Switzerland). The working volume in each tube was 25 mL, and the seeding density was 1.0 × 10<sup>6</sup> viable cells/mL. The extracts were added to the cell culture media on Day 0 and the cells were harvested on Day 14. VCD and cell viability were determined with Vi-cell XR (Beckman Coulter, USA). Glucose, glutamine, lactate, ammonium, glutamate, pH, and osmolarity were determined with a BioProfile 400 (Nova BioMedical, USA). All samples were taken daily and assayed before feeding.</p>
            <p>The cells were fed with the CD feed on the 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, and 13 days, respectively. The two types of CD feeds were added at 4 and 0.4% of the feeding-day culture volume, respectively. Glucose was always kept at a concentration between 2 and 3 g/L based on the results tested daily. When the VCD exceeded 1.0 × 10<sup>6</sup> viable cells/mL, the cell density of the sample was diluted in a 1:1 ratio with PBS before measurement. A temperature was shifted from 37 to 32 °C on the 7th day of the culture. After the 14th day, the samples were centrifuged with a high-speed refrigerated centrifuge (Beckman Coulter, USA) at 20 °C, 3900 g for 30 min, and the supernatants were collected, respectively.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0002-S2005" disp-level="2">
            <title>The mAb titer assay</title>
            <p>An e2695 HPLC system (Waters, USA) with a TSKgel Protein A-5PW affinity chromatography column (TOSOH, Japan) was used to determine the mAb titer concentration in the supernatant. The mobile phase A was a 20 mmol/L phosphate buffer (NaH<sub>2</sub>PO<sub>4</sub>·H<sub>2</sub>O + Na<sub>2</sub>HPO<sub>4</sub>) at pH 7.0, and the mobile phase B was 20 mmol/L phosphate buffer at pH 2.5. The standard and samples were diluted with the mobile phase A before analysis. The chromatographic conditions were as follows: the sample chamber temperature at 10 °C, the column temperature at 25 °C, and the flow rate at 2 mL/min. The sample was separated by the pH gradient from 0% B to 100% B in 2 min. The eluted titer was detected at a wavelength of 280 nm and the titer concentration was calculated using the standard curve ranging from 0.2 to 4.0 mg/mL.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0002-S2006" disp-level="2">
            <title>The mAb purification</title>
            <p>The samples were purified by affinity chromatography on a 1-mL mAb Purix A65 gravity column (Sepax Technologies, China). The gravity column was washed first with purified water, disinfected with ≥5 mL of the 0.1 M NaOH solution, and rinsed with an affinity equilibrium solution (20 mM phosphate buffer and 150 mM NaCl at pH 7) until the droplets became neutral. The column was then further equilibrated with the affinity equilibration solution. The sample was loaded on the column and washed with the affinity equilibration solution. The mAb was eluted with ≥5 mL of the 25 mM sodium citrate-citric acid buffer at pH 3.5. The eluted mAb was collected, and the concentration was determined. The purified mAb was stored at −80 °C for the purity analyses.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0002-S2007" disp-level="2">
            <title>The purity analysis by size exclusion chromatography</title>
            <p>The purified mAb samples were analyzed using a Vanquish HPLC system (Thermo Fisher, USA) equipped with a TSKgel G3000SWxl molecular size exclusion column (TOSOH, Japan). The 50 mM phosphate and 300 mM NaCl buffer at pH 6.8 was used as a mobile phase. The flow rate was 0.8 mL/min, the injection volume was 10 µL, the column temperature was 25 °C, the acquisition wavelength was 280 nm, and the sample chamber temperature was 10 °C. The level of aggregation was expressed as the relative percentage of peak areas.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0002-S2008" disp-level="2">
            <title>The purity analysis by strong cation exchange chromatography</title>
            <p>The purified mAb samples were also analyzed with a Proteomix SCX-NP analytical column (5 µm, 4.6 × 150 mm, Sepax Technologies) equipped with a Vanquish HPLC system. The samples were first desalted by liquid exchange. The mAb sample (100 µg) was added to a 10 kD ultrafiltration tube, purified water (500 µL) added, vortexed, and centrifuged at 13,000 rpm for 10 min. The mAb concentration in the retentate was measured with a NanoDrop one spectrophotometer. After desalting, the samples were diluted to 5.0 mg/mL with purified water and then mixed by vortex before injection. The HPLC system consisted of four mobile phases: 125 mM sodium dihydrogen phosphate as mobile phase A, 125 mM disodium phosphate as mobile phase B, 1 M sodium chloride solution as mobile phase C, and ultra-pure water as mobile phase D. For the separation, the mobile phases A and B were maintained at constant rates of 9.3 and 40.7%, respectively at the entire duration. The mobile phase C was increased from 4 to 40% in 30 min. The flow rate was 0.5 mL/min. Protein peaks were measured by UV absorption at 280 nm.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0002-S2009" disp-level="2">
            <title>The glycosylation assay</title>
            <p>The GlycoWorks RapiFluor-MS N-glycan kit (Waters, USA) was used for sample preparation of the glycan analysis. First, the sample was diluted to 2 mg/mL with purified water. Then a 7.5 µL of the diluted sample was denatured, cooled, and incubated to release glycosyl groups, and RapiFluor-MS reagents were added to label the glycosyl groups. Finally, the sample was loaded on GlycoWorks HILIC µElution extraction plate for activation, cleaning, elution, and dilution before injection for HPLC analysis.</p>
            <p>The prepared glycan samples were analyzed by an ACQUITY UPLC system with a glycan BEH amide column (2.1 × 150 mm, 130 Å, 1.7 µm, Waters, USA), using a solution of 50 mM ammonium formate at pH 4.4 as mobile phase A and 100% acetonitrile as mobile phase B. The column temperature was kept at 60 °C, and the flow rate was stabilized at 0.4 mL/min, gradient elution was performed. The separated glycans were detected with a fluorescence detector with an excitation wavelength of 265 nm and the emission wavelength of 425 nm. After the glycosylation profile was obtained, the glycan species of the known glycosylation profile of the antibody protein were calibrated, and the glycosylation changes were analyzed according to the normalized peak areas.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0002-S2010" disp-level="2">
            <title>The mAb binding activity assay</title>
            <p>The relative binding activity of mAb was determined by an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA). IgE (100 µL/well, Shanghai Maitai Junao Biotechnology Co., Ltd., China) was added to the microtiter plate (Corning, USA) for antigen coating, and incubated overnight in a refrigerator at 2–8 °C. The next day, PBST (1000 mL 10 mM PBS and 0.5 mL Tween 20) plus 3%BSA (Sigma, USA) was used as the blocking solution, PBST + 1%BSA as the diluent solution.</p>
            <p>The sample was diluted to 10 µg/mL, and then further diluted to 12 concentration points at a 3-fold dilution for each consequent point. Goat anti-human Kappa-HRP (Southern Biotech, USA) was used as the secondary antibody. A 3,3′,5,5′-tetramethylbenzidine chromogenic solution (50 µL/well, Kangwei Century, China) was added to develop color and finally, a 0.5 M H<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub> solution (50 µL/well) was added to stop the color reaction. The SpectraMax iD5 multi-function microplate reader (Molecular Devices, USA) was used to read the absorbance at wavelengths of 450 and 570 nm, respectively. The curve was drawn using the four-parameter fitting regression model with the SoftMax Pro computer software. The half-maximal effect concentration (EC50) from the curve was obtained, and the relative activity was reported by calculating the EC50 ratio of the control to the experimental sample.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0002-S2011" disp-level="2">
            <title>Statistical analysis</title>
            <p>Results were analyzed by GraphPad Prism 9.0 software (GraphPad, United States). The data were expressed as means ± <italic>SD</italic> of three independent experiments performed in triplicate measurements. An ANOVA analysis was used to evaluate the differences among the treatments.</p>
         </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="S0003" disp-level="1" sec-type="results">
         <title>Results</title>
         <sec id="S0003-S2001" disp-level="2">
            <title>Carbohydrate and flavonoid contents</title>
            <p>The carbohydrate and flavonoid contents in the three pine needle extracts are shown in <xref ref-type="table" rid="t0001">Table 1</xref>. PNWE had 4.74% more carbohydrate content than PNEE, and PNPE had the highest carbohydrate content (96.03%). There was no difference in flavonoid content between PNWE and PNEE, and the flavonoid content in PNPE was ∼1% lower than that in PNWE and PNEE (<xref ref-type="table" rid="t0001">Table 1</xref>).</p>
            <table-wrap id="t0001" orientation="portrait" position="float">
               <label>Table 1. </label>
               <caption>
                  <p>Carbohydrate and flavonoid contents in the pine needle extracts.</p>
               </caption>
               <oasis:table frame="topbot">
                  <oasis:tgroup cols="3">
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:thead>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">Sample</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="center">Flavonoid content %</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">Carbohydrate content %</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                     </oasis:thead>
                     <oasis:tbody valign="top">
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNWE</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">3.45 ± 0.11</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char=".">46.69 ± 0.15</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNEE</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">3.54 ± 0.05</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char=".">51.43 ± 0.23</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNPE</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">2.47 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char=".">96.03 ± 0.12</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                     </oasis:tbody>
                  </oasis:tgroup>
               </oasis:table>
               <table-wrap-foot>
                  <fn id="TF1">
                     <p>The values are the mean ± standard deviation (<italic>n</italic> = 3).</p>
                  </fn>
               </table-wrap-foot>
            </table-wrap>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0003-S2002" disp-level="2">
            <title>Chemical compounds identified in PNPE</title>
            <p>The chromatograms of the three pine needle extracts are shown in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0001">Figure 1</xref>. Mass spectrometry data were interpreted by analyzing their accurate mass information and MS/MS spectrum in a negative ion mode. When both accurate mass and MS/MS spectrum of a compound matched to the information in the database by &amp;gt;70% matching score and this compound was considered to be confirmed. With the use of those criteria, 38 compounds were identified from PNPE (<xref ref-type="table" rid="t0002">Table 2</xref>). Some of the bioflavonoids identified may be the compounds that influence the charge variants of mAb.<sup>[</sup>
               <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0020">
                  <sup>20</sup>
               </xref>
               <sup>]</sup> No compounds were identified from PNWE and PNEE by searching the database (results not shown). An additional verification study is needed for the compound identification in PNWE and PNEE.</p>
            <fig id="F0001" position="float" orientation="portrait">
               <label>Figure 1. </label>
               <caption>
                  <p>Mass spectrometric chromatograms of PNWE (a), PNEE (b), and PNPE (c). Blue: MS chromatogram; Pink: MS/MS chromatogram.</p>
               </caption>
               <graphic href="lpbb_a_2166959_f0001_c.jpg" content-type="color" position="float" orientation="portrait"/>
            </fig>
            <table-wrap id="t0002" orientation="landscape" position="float">
               <label>Table 2. </label>
               <caption>
                  <p>Chemical compounds identified in the pine needle polysaccharide extract.</p>
               </caption>
               <oasis:table frame="topbot">
                  <oasis:tgroup cols="9">
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="8" colname="col8" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="9" colname="col9" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:thead>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">No.</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="center">Retention time (min)</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">Molecular formula</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="center">Relative molecular mass</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="center">Measured value (m/z)</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">Adduct ion</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="center">Compounds</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="center">Error (10<sup>−6</sup>)</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="center">Peak value</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                     </oasis:thead>
                     <oasis:tbody valign="top">
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">1</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">0.96</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>30</sub>H<sub>52</sub>O<sub>26</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">827.267</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">827.268</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Maltopentaose</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">0.7</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.33E + 06</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">2</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>36</sub>H<sub>62</sub>O<sub>31</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">989.32</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">989.3211</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Maltohexaose</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">0.9</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">8.80E + 05</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">3</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.13</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>6</sub>H<sub>14</sub>N<sub>4</sub>O<sub>2</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">173.104</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">173.1038</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Arginine</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−3.6</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.20E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">4</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.32</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>12</sub>H<sub>22</sub>O<sub>11</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">341.109</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">341.1091</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">D-sucrose</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">0.5</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.46E + 06</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">5</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.33</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>6</sub>H<sub>12</sub>O<sub>6</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">179.056</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">179.0558</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">D-glucose</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.7</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">2.21E + 05</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">6</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.33</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>12</sub>H<sub>22</sub>O<sub>12</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">357.104</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">357.1028</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Lactobionic acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−3.1</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.92E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">7</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.33</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>6</sub>H<sub>12</sub>O<sub>7</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">195.051</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">195.0509</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Gluconic acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−0.8</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">2.90E + 05</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">8</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.38</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>4</sub>H<sub>8</sub>O<sub>5</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">135.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">135.0293</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">L-threonic acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−4.6</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.89E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">9</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.41</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>7</sub>H<sub>12</sub>O<sub>6</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">191.056</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">191.0563</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">D-(−)-quinic acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">1.0</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">5.41E + 05</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">10</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.45</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>3</sub>H<sub>6</sub>O<sub>4</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">105.019</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">105.0188</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Glyceric acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−4.9</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">6.80E + 03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">11</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.54</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>7</sub>H<sub>10</sub>O<sub>5</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">173.046</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">173.0455</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Shikimic acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−0.1</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.26E + 05</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">12</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.58</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>4</sub>H<sub>6</sub>O<sub>5</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">133.014</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">133.0141</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">DL-malic acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.2</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">3.40E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">13</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.92</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>6</sub>H<sub>8</sub>O<sub>7</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">191.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">191.0195</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Citric acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.3</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">3.54E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">14</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.95</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>9</sub>H<sub>12</sub>N<sub>2</sub>O<sub>6</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">243.062</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">243.0618</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Uridine</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.8</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.29E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">15</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">1.99</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>5</sub>H<sub>7</sub>NO<sub>3</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">128.035</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">128.035</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">L-pyroglutamic acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−2.3</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.53E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">16</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">2.22</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>10</sub>H<sub>13</sub>N<sub>5</sub>O<sub>5</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">282.084</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">282.0841</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Guanosine</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.2</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">4.81E + 03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">17</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">3.07</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>7</sub>H<sub>6</sub>O<sub>5</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">169.014</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">169.0134</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Gallic acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−4.9</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">5.81E + 03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">18</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">6.21</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>7</sub>H<sub>6</sub>O<sub>4</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">153.019</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">153.019</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Protocatechuic acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−2</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">9.75E + 03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">19</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">6.91</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>19</sub>H<sub>19</sub>N<sub>7</sub>O<sub>6</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">440.132</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">440.132</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Folic acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.0</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">4.45E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">20</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">7.22</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>15</sub>H<sub>14</sub>O<sub>6</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">289.072</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">289.0715</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">(−)-Catechin hydrate</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.0</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">2.28E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">21</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">7.24</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>7</sub>H<sub>6</sub>O<sub>3</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">137.024</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">137.0241</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">3,4-Dihydroxybenzaldehyde</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−2.1</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">2.36E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">22</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">7.74</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>25</sub>H<sub>32</sub>O<sub>10</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">491.192</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">491.1919</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Massonianoside B</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−0.7</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">5.79E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">23</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">7.82</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>27</sub>H<sub>30</sub>O<sub>16</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">609.146</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">609.1447</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Rutin</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−2.3</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">2.13E + 03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">24</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">7.91</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>21</sub>H<sub>22</sub>O<sub>12</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">465.104</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">465.1035</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Dihydroquercetin-3-glucoside</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−0.8</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">3.70E + 03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">25</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">8.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>14</sub>H<sub>6</sub>O<sub>8</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">300.999</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">300.9985</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Ellagic acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.6</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">5.47E + 03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">26</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">8.07</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>7</sub>H<sub>6</sub>O<sub>2</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">121.029</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">121.0292</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Salicylaldehyde</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−2.2</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.26E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">27</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">8.23</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>9</sub>H<sub>8</sub>O<sub>3</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">163.040</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">163.0397</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">P-coumaric acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−2.0</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">7.01E + 03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">28</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">8.29</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>21</sub>H<sub>20</sub>O<sub>11</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">447.093</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">447.092</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Astragalin</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−2.8</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.31E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">29</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">8.32</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>25</sub>H<sub>32</sub>O<sub>11</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">507.187</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">507.1864</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Massonianoside D</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.5</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.45E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">30</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">8.53</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>21</sub>H<sub>22</sub>O<sub>11</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">449.109</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">449.1085</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Eriodictyol 3′-O-glucoside</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.0</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">5.15E + 03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">31</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">8.56</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>9</sub>H<sub>6</sub>O<sub>3</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">161.024</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">161.0242</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">7-Hydroxycoumarin</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.5</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.73E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">32</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">8.62</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>21</sub>H<sub>24</sub>O<sub>10</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">435.129</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">435.1294</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Phlorizin</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−0.6</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">3.22E + 03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">33</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">8.83</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>9</sub>H<sub>16</sub>O<sub>4</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">187.098</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">187.0974</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Azelaic acid</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.2</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">5.64E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">34</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">8.89</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>20</sub>H<sub>26</sub>O<sub>6</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">361.166</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">361.165</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">(−)-Secoisolariciresinol</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.7</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">2.76E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">35</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">9.27</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>15</sub>H<sub>10</sub>O<sub>4</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">253.051</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">253.0499</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Daidzein</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−2.9</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.10E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">36</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">9.44</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>15</sub>H<sub>10</sub>O<sub>7</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">301.035</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">301.0343</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Quercetin</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−3.7</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">7.19E + 03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">37</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">9.49</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>6</sub>H<sub>5</sub>NO<sub>3</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">138.019</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">138.0194</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">3-Nitrophenol</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−1.9</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">1.13E + 04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">38</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">11.16</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">C<sub>15</sub>H<sub>12</sub>O<sub>4</sub>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">255.066</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char=".">255.0657</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">[M − H]<sup>−</sup>
                           </oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="left">Isoliquiritigenin</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char=".">−2.3</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char=".">5.95E + 03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                     </oasis:tbody>
                  </oasis:tgroup>
               </oasis:table>
            </table-wrap>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0003-S2003" disp-level="2">
            <title>Effects on the growth of CHO cells</title>
            <p>Compared with the control, the viable cell density decreased significantly at 10 and 15 mg/L PNWE concentrations (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0002">Figure 2a</xref>), indicating the inhibition of the CHO cell growth. The VCD at the 5 mg/L PNWE was similar to that of the control, but it was significantly higher in the last three days, indicating that PNWE at this concentration might have a delaying effect on the death of CHO cells. At the last four days of the cell culture, the cell viability of the three PNWE concentrations was higher than that of the control (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0002">Figure 2d</xref>). The inhibitory effect observed in the PNWE extract may be associated with the higher percentage of the non-polysaccharide compounds (<xref ref-type="table" rid="t0001">Table 1</xref>). The effects of the PNEE extract on the VCD and cell viability were very similar to those of the PNWE extract (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0002">Figures 2b,e</xref>). The PNPE treatments had little effect on VCD and cell viability during the first 11 days (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0002">Figures 2c,f</xref>). However, the highest VCD reached 16.4 × 10<sup>6</sup> cells/mL at 5 mg/L concentration, and the highest VCD at all the PNPE concentrations exceeded that of the control group. On the 14th day, the PNPE treatments maintained a high VCD of about 12.0 × 10<sup>6</sup> cells/mL and viability of about 82.0%, compared to the VCD of 10.2 × 10<sup>6</sup> cells/mL, and the viability of 78.3% in the control. Apparently, the high polysaccharide levels may help maintain the higher VCD and cell viability (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0002">Figures 2c,f</xref>).</p>
            <fig id="F0002" position="float" orientation="portrait">
               <label>Figure 2. </label>
               <caption>
                  <p>Effects of the pine needle extracts on the growth and cell viability of CHO cells under Fed-batch culture conditions. The VCD (a) and cell viability (d) in 0 (control), 5, 10, and 15 mg/L PNWE; The VCD (b) and cell viability (e) in 0 (control), 5, 10, and 15 mg/L PNEE; The VCD (c) and cell viability (f) in 0 (control), 5, 50, and 100 mg/L PNPE.</p>
               </caption>
               <graphic href="lpbb_a_2166959_f0002_b.jpg" content-type="black-white" position="float" orientation="portrait"/>
            </fig>
            <p>The glucose consumption during the culture period was reduced when the 10 and 15 mg/L of PNWE and PNEE, respectively, were used, but it was similar in the other treatments (data not shown). The addition of three extracts did not impact the contents of glutamine, lactic acid, ammonium, and glutamic acid.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0003-S2004" disp-level="2">
            <title>Effects on the mAb titers</title>
            <p>The mAb titer increased significantly (<italic>p</italic> &amp;lt; 0.01) at the 5 mg/L PNWE, but tended to decrease with increased PNWE concentrations (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0003">Figure 3</xref>). A similar trend was also observed for the PNEE treatments. However, the effect of PNPE on the mAb titer was different from those of PNWE and PNEE. The mAb titer increased from 2.3 to 2.8 g/L with the PNPE concentrations increasing from 5 to 100 mg/L, showing a dose-dependent relationship. The <italic>p</italic>-values for the results of three PNPE concentrations were &amp;lt;0.001 compared to the control. The results indicate that the high levels of the non-polysaccharide compounds may have a negative impact, while the polysaccharides may have an enhanced effect on the mAb titers.</p>
            <fig id="F0003" position="float" orientation="portrait">
               <label>Figure 3. </label>
               <caption>
                  <p>The mAb titers produced by the CHO cells grown in the pine needle extracts in a fed-batch process. *, **, and *** indicate the significance at <italic>p</italic> &amp;lt; 0.05, <italic>p</italic> &amp;lt; 0.01, and <italic>p</italic> &amp;lt; 0.001, respectively, compared to the control.</p>
               </caption>
               <graphic href="lpbb_a_2166959_f0003_b.jpg" content-type="black-white" position="float" orientation="portrait"/>
            </fig>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0003-S2005" disp-level="2">
            <title>Effects on the mAb purity</title>
            <p>Besides the impact of genetic sequence, the mAb purity can be affected significantly by the upstream Fed-batch culture process and the downstream mAb purification process.<sup>[</sup>
               <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0021">
                  <sup>21</sup>
               </xref>
               <sup>]</sup> The addition of a pine needle changed the media composition that may impact the CHO cell growth and then the mAb purity. The purities of the main peaks (MP) by SEC were &amp;gt;99% for all the treatments including the control (<xref ref-type="table" rid="t0003">Table 3</xref>). There were no statistically significant differences in the SEC purity among all the treatments, indicating the pine needle did not impact the molecular size of the mAb.</p>
            <table-wrap id="t0003" orientation="portrait" position="float">
               <label>Table 3. </label>
               <caption>
                  <p>The purity (measured by SEC) of the mAb produced by the CHO cells grown in the three pine needle extracts.</p>
               </caption>
               <oasis:table frame="topbot">
                  <oasis:tgroup cols="4">
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:thead>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left" morerows="1"/>
                           <oasis:entry align="center" namest="col2" nameend="col4" rowsep="1">SEC</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="center">MP%</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">HMW%</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="center">LMW%</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                     </oasis:thead>
                     <oasis:tbody valign="top">
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNWE 5</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">99.18 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char=".">0.68 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">0.14 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNWE 10</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">99.16 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char=".">0.70 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">0.14 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNWE 15</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">99.22 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char=".">0.65 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">0.13 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNEE 5</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">99.16 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char=".">0.69 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">0.15 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNEE 10</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">99.18 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char=".">0.68 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">0.14 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNEE 15</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">99.20 ± 0.05</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char=".">0.67 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">0.13 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNPE 5</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">99.15 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char=".">0.68 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">0.17 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNPE 50</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">99.10 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char=".">0.73 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">0.17 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNPE 100</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">99.06 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char=".">0.81 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">0.13 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">Control</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char=".">99.14 ± 0.05</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char=".">0.69 ± 0.05</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char=".">0.17 ± 0.01</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                     </oasis:tbody>
                  </oasis:tgroup>
               </oasis:table>
               <table-wrap-foot>
                  <fn id="TF2">
                     <p>HMW: high molecular weight; LMW: low molecular weight.</p>
                  </fn>
               </table-wrap-foot>
            </table-wrap>
            <p>In CEX, the acidic peak levels decreased by 3.4–4.5% in the PNWE treatments and 3.4–4.8% in the PNEE treatments, while the basic peak levels increased by 2.0–6.0% in the PNWE treatments and 1.0–6.0% in the PNEE treatments (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0004">Figure 4</xref>). Many of these changes were statistically significant at the 0.01 and 0.001 significance levels. But these changes became more profound with the increased PNWE and PNEE concentrations from 5 to 15 mg/L. The additions of the PNWE and PNEE had minor influences on the main peak levels. The acidic peak levels in the PNPE treatments were all reduced significantly, and the largest decrease was at the concentration of 50 mg/L, reaching 3.9% (<italic>p</italic> &amp;lt; 0.001) (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0004">Figure 4</xref>). The basic peak levels increased with an increased PNPE concentration. The levels of the main species slightly decreased at the 100 mg/L concentration and increased slightly at 5 and 50 mg/L concentrations.</p>
            <fig id="F0004" position="float" orientation="portrait">
               <label>Figure 4. </label>
               <caption>
                  <p>The differences between control and treatments in the levels of the acidic peak, main peak, and basic peak of the mAb produced by the CHO cells grown in the pine needle extracts compared with the control. *, **, and *** indicate the significance at <italic>p</italic> &amp;lt; 0.05, <italic>p</italic> &amp;lt; 0.01, and <italic>p</italic> &amp;lt; 0.001, respectively compared to the control.</p>
               </caption>
               <graphic href="lpbb_a_2166959_f0004_c.jpg" content-type="color" position="float" orientation="portrait"/>
            </fig>
            <p>Apparently, the pine needle extracts were able to reduce the acidic charge variants of the mAbs, but did not significantly change the main species. This property is very important for regulating acidic and basic charge variants of a therapeutic protein, which allows us to achieve specific target levels during the production. Many studies have been reported that the presence of acidic charge variants may have a certain degree of influence on the effectiveness and function of the proteins.<sup>[</sup>
               <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0021 CIT0022 CIT0023">
                  <sup>21–23</sup>
               </xref>
               <sup>]</sup>
            </p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0003-S2006" disp-level="2">
            <title>Effects on the mAb glycosylation</title>
            <p>Protein glycosylation is an important post-translational modification event, and has a non-negligible impact on protein structure and function,<sup>[</sup>
               <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0024">
                  <sup>24</sup>
               </xref>
               <sup>,</sup>
               <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0025">
                  <sup>25</sup>
               </xref>
               <sup>]</sup> represents one of the most important critical quality attributes (CQAs). During the upstream production, glycosylation is altered by cell line, process conditions, and media and supplement formulations.<sup>[</sup>
               <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0026">
                  <sup>26</sup>
               </xref>
               <sup>]</sup> A total of ten glycoforms were found in the proteins produced in the experiments, of which G0F accounted for the highest percentage, reaching about 70% (<xref ref-type="table" rid="t0004">Table 4</xref>). PNWE and PNEE did not show any effect on glycoforms except G0, where G0 levels increased with the increased concentrations of both extracts. PNPE showed different effects on glycoforms. PNPE decreased the G0F level by 8.7% at the 100 mg/L concentration compared to the control. Decreases in G0 minus GlcNAc and G0F minus GlcNAc were also observed. However, the two glycoforms G1Fa and G1Fb increased with the increased PNPE concentrations, where G1Fa increased by 0.56, 4.41, and 6.7% at the three increased concentrations, respectively, and G1Fb increased by 0.96, 2.07, and 2.91%, respectively. G0 and G1F GlcNAc reached the highest level at the 50 mg/L concentration, and G0 glycoform decreased at the 100 mg/L concentration. While Man5 and Man6 reached the highest level at the 5 mg/L PNPE concentration. PNPE had more effect on glycosylation than the other two extracts. Therefore, PNPE could be an effective component used to control product quality associated with glycosylation.</p>
            <table-wrap id="t0004" orientation="landscape" position="float">
               <label>Table 4. </label>
               <caption>
                  <p>Percentage of glycan composition in the mAb produced by the CHO cells grown in the pine needle extracts.</p>
               </caption>
               <oasis:table frame="topbot">
                  <oasis:tgroup cols="11">
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="8" colname="col8" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="9" colname="col9" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="10" colname="col10" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:colspec colnum="11" colname="col11" colwidth="80pt"/>
                     <oasis:thead>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">Group</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="center">G0 minus GlcNAc</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="center">G0F minus GlcNAc</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="center">G0</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="center">G0F</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="center">G1F GlcNAc</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="center">G1Fa</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="center">G1Fb</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="center">G2F</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col10" align="center">Man5</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col11" align="center">Man6</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                     </oasis:thead>
                     <oasis:tbody valign="top">
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">Control</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char="±">0.70 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char="±">5.50 ± 0.12</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char="±">2.32 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char="±">75.28 ± 0.15</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="char" char="±">1.01 ± 0.01</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="char" char="±">6.54 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char="±">3.03 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char="±">0.22 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col10" align="char" char="±">4.04 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col11" align="char" char="±">1.36 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNWE5</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char="±">0.74 ± 0.01</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char="±">5.56 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char="±">2.64 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char="±">74.28 ± 0.25</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="char" char="±">1.03 ± 0.01</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="char" char="±">6.50 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char="±">3.78 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char="±">0.25 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col10" align="char" char="±">3.96 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col11" align="char" char="±">1.27 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNWE10</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char="±">0.68 ± 0.01</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char="±">5.41 ± 0.05</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char="±">2.58 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char="±">74.38 ± 0.22</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="char" char="±">0.93 ± 0.01</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="char" char="±">6.66 ± 0.05</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char="±">3.71 ± 0.08</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char="±">0.33 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col10" align="char" char="±">4.05 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col11" align="char" char="±">1.26 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNWE15</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char="±">0.70 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char="±">4.97 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char="±">2.79 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char="±">74.15 ± 0.23</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="char" char="±">0.92 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="char" char="±">7.00 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char="±">3.92 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char="±">0.32 ± 0.01</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col10" align="char" char="±">4.02 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col11" align="char" char="±">1.20 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNEE5</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char="±">0.84 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char="±">5.50 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char="±">2.48 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char="±">74.4 ± 0.25</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="char" char="±">0.77 ± 0.01</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="char" char="±">6.57 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char="±">3.70 ± 0.07</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char="±">0.27 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col10" align="char" char="±">4.19 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col11" align="char" char="±">1.28 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNEE10</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char="±">0.73 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char="±">5.23 ± 0.05</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char="±">2.66 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char="±">74.29 ± 0.27</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="char" char="±">0.81 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="char" char="±">6.73 ± 0.05</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char="±">3.80 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char="±">0.26 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col10" align="char" char="±">4.06 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col11" align="char" char="±">1.42 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNEE15</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char="±">0.66 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char="±">4.66 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char="±">2.86 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char="±">73.73 ± 0.20</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="char" char="±">1.03 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="char" char="±">7.57 ± 0.07</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char="±">4.17 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char="±">0.42 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col10" align="char" char="±">3.92 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col11" align="char" char="±">0.98 ± 0.01</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNPE5</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char="±">0.80 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char="±">5.26 ± 0.05</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char="±">2.67 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char="±">73.31 ± 0.22</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="char" char="±">0.81 ± 0.01</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="char" char="±">7.10 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char="±">3.99 ± 0.05</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char="±">0.32 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col10" align="char" char="±">4.32 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col11" align="char" char="±">1.42 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNPE50</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char="±">0.71 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char="±">4.05 ± 0.05</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char="±">3.16 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char="±">68.81 ± 0.25</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="char" char="±">1.24 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="char" char="±">10.95 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char="±">5.10 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char="±">0.79 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col10" align="char" char="±">3.89 ± 0.05</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col11" align="char" char="±">1.29 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                        <oasis:row>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col1" align="left">PNPE100</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col2" align="char" char="±">0.54 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col3" align="char" char="±">3.53 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col4" align="char" char="±">2.88 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col5" align="char" char="±">66.55 ± 0.31</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col6" align="char" char="±">1.20 ± 0.02</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col7" align="char" char="±">13.24 ± 0.07</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col8" align="char" char="±">5.94 ± 0.06</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col9" align="char" char="±">1.23 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col10" align="char" char="±">3.67 ± 0.04</oasis:entry>
                           <oasis:entry colname="col11" align="char" char="±">1.21 ± 0.03</oasis:entry>
                        </oasis:row>
                     </oasis:tbody>
                  </oasis:tgroup>
               </oasis:table>
            </table-wrap>
         </sec>
         <sec id="S0003-S2007" disp-level="2">
            <title>Effects on the mAb binding activity</title>
            <p>The binding activity of mAb has strong clinical relevance. The results of relative potency and EC50 are shown in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0005">Figure 5</xref>. Compared to the control, the same trend was observed, the binding activity was lower at two low extract concentrations and higher at the high extract concentration. However, according to the mAb requirement for CHO K1 cells cultured in this study, most of the results were within an acceptable range of 70–130%. Hence, the addition of the pine needle extract had no significant effect on the mAb binding activity.</p>
            <fig id="F0005" position="float" orientation="portrait">
               <label>Figure 5. </label>
               <caption>
                  <p>The effects of the pine needle extracts on the relative binding activity and EC50 of mAb produced by the CHO cells grown in the three extracts. No significant difference was observed.</p>
               </caption>
               <graphic href="lpbb_a_2166959_f0005_b.jpg" content-type="black-white" position="float" orientation="portrait"/>
            </fig>
         </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="S0004" disp-level="1" sec-type="discussion">
         <title>Discussion</title>
         <p>The differences in carbohydrate and flavonoid contents between PNWE and PNEE were relatively small, indicating the water and ethanol extraction had a limited effect on the components of the pine needles (<xref ref-type="table" rid="t0001">Table 1</xref>). PNPE with a much higher carbohydrate content was different from the other two extracts and appeared to be a better choice for cell culture.</p>
         <p>In the present fed-batch condition, the pine needle extracts increased the mAb yield. Therefore, it can be determined that the pine needle extracts may be suitable to increase the viable cell density and cell viability and then increase the production of the target protein. Among them, the results obtained by adding PNPE were by far the best. When the PNPE concentration reached 100 mg/L, the VCD and cell viability on the 14th day were still at a high level, and the target protein production reached the highest level (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0003">Figure 3</xref>), indicating that this may not be an optimal PNPE concentration. However, the PNWE and PNEE had obvious inhibitory effects on the growth of CHO cells at the concentration of 15 mg/L. Clearly it was not such a case for PNPE. The pine needle sugar components may have a positive effect on the cell growth and production. The results of this research can also be used in process scale-up to increase the mAb production.</p>
         <p>For charge variants, the complete elimination of both acidic and basic charge variants is impractical and unnecessary. Therefore, it is necessary to evaluate the differences in stability and function of acidic, basic, and main species and compare them with the final target to ensure the efficacy and safety of mAbs. Various flavonoids have been reported to significantly reduce the overall levels of acidic charge variants on recombinant proteins at specific concentrations.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0020">
               <sup>20</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> At the same time, there is a nominal drop in recombinant protein production. The pine needle extracts used in this study reduced the overall levels of acidic charge variants on the mAb proteins with increased tilters in 5 and 10 mg/L PNWE and PNEE, and three concentrations of PNPE (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0003">Figures 3</xref> and <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0004">4</xref>). Flavonoids in all three extracts were detected by the aluminum chloride colorimetric method and identified by the mass spectrometry (<xref ref-type="table" rid="t0002">Table 2</xref>). The reductions in the charge variants were related to relatively high flavonoid levels (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F0004">Figure 4</xref> and <xref ref-type="table" rid="t0001">Table 1</xref>). These results explained the reason for the reduction of acidic charge variants, which is similar to previous reports.</p>
         <p>Glycosylation characteristics can be affected by various conditions including cell lines, culture media composition, supplements,<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0027 CIT0028 CIT0029 CIT0030">
               <sup>27–30</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> and culture processes.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0031">
               <sup>31</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> An effective approach to control the glycosylation profile is to alter CHO cell culture media components to target specific oligosaccharide structures. The sugars in the media can meet the energy requirements of CHO cells and they are also the carbohydrate sources that enable the glycosylation pathway to proceed. Most of them rely on glucose for energy sources, but recent studies found that many uncommon sugars other than glucose also have a non-negligible effect on the glycosylation profile of recombinant proteins.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0019">
               <sup>19</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> This study illustrated that multiple types of sugars in PNPE changed the mAb glycosylation profile. Moreover, different types of mAbs produced by CHO cells have different requirements for glycosylation, and the appropriate glycosylation characteristics have to be achieved according to the desired mechanism of molecular action and desired proportion of antibody glycoforms.<sup>[</sup>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CIT0032 CIT0033 CIT0034">
               <sup>32–34</sup>
            </xref>
            <sup>]</sup> In the field of biosimilars, the glycosylation characteristics of the mAb produced need to match the original drug, so it is necessary to adjust the glycosylation characteristics of the generic drug. The PNPE can effectively modify the glycoforms (<xref ref-type="table" rid="t0004">Table 4</xref>), and therefore it can be used as a supplement to regulate the mAb glycosylation, such as changing the levels of G0F, G1F, G2F, etc.</p>
         <p>The use of the extracts is simple and cheap. The cost of each extract in each liter of the culture media is &amp;lt;1 cent, which is significantly lower than that of peptones. However, additional studies are needed to identify specific compound(s) responsible for the changes in mAb productivity and quality due to the addition of the pine needle extracts. Because of diversity in pine needle sources, the production of consistent manufacturing batches will be a major concern. Therefore, additional quality control for the manufacturing is needed when these extracts are used in the mAb production.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="S0005" disp-level="1" sec-type="conclusions">
         <title>Conclusion</title>
         <p>In this study, the contents of carbohydrates and flavonoids in the three pine needle extracts were determined, and 38 compounds in the pine needle polysaccharide extract were identified. It has been demonstrated that the pine needle polysaccharide extract can be used to improve the viable cell density and viability of CHO cells and increase the mAb production. Furthermore, the pine needle polysaccharide extract was able to reduce the level of acidic charge variants and modulate the glycosylation profile. The utilization of natural plant extracts is a new research area to develop new raw materials for controlling the quality of biopharmaceutical products, especially biosimilars. Our pioneering exploration provides a new direction for future cell culture process optimization and the development of a culture medium system.</p>
      </sec>
   </body>
   <back>
      <ack>
         <title>Acknowledgments</title>
         <p>The authors thank Thousand Oaks Biopharmaceuticals Co., Ltd. for the financial and platform support during this work.</p>
      </ack>
      <sec id="S0006" disp-level="1" sec-type="COI-statement">
         <title>Disclosure statement</title>
         <p>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the author(s).</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="S0007" disp-level="1" sec-type="data-availability">
         <title>Data availability statement</title>
         <p>All data generated or analyzed during this study are included in this published article. Raw data are available from the corresponding author upon reasonable request.</p>
      </sec>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="CIT0001">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ritacco</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>F. v.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Wu</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Y.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Khetan</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Cell Culture Media for Recombinant Protein Expression in Chinese Hamster Ovary (CHO) Cells: History, Key Components, and Optimization Strategies</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Biotechnol. Prog.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2018</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>34</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>1407</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>1426</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/btpr.2706</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0002">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Blondeel</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>E. J. M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ho</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>R.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Schulze</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Sokolenko</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Guillemette</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S. R.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Slivac</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>I.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Durocher</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Y.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Guillemette</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>J. G.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>McConkey</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>B. J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Chang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>D.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve">; et al. </x>
               <article-title>An Omics Approach to Rational Feed: Enhancing Growth in CHO Cultures with NMR Metabolomics and 2D-DIGE Proteomics</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>J. Biotechnol.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2016</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>234</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>127</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>138</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jbiotec.2016.07.027</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0003">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Pérez-Rodriguez</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ramírez-Lira</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M. d J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Trujillo-Roldán</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M. A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Valdez-Cruz</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>N. A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Nutrient Supplementation Strategy Improves Cell Concentration and Longevity, Monoclonal Antibody Production and Lactate Metabolism of Chinese Hamster Ovary Cells</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Bioengineered</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2020</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>11</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>463</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>471</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/21655979.2020.1744266</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0004">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Reinhart</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>D.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Damjanovic</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>L.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kaisermayer</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Sommeregger</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>W.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Gili</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>GaSSelhuber</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>B.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Castan</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Mayrhofer</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>P.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Grünwald-Gruber</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kunert</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>R.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Bioprocessing of Recombinant CHO-K1, CHO-DG44, and CHO-S: CHO Expression Hosts Favor Either MAb Production or Biomass Synthesis</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Biotechnol. J.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2019</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>14</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>1700686</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/biot.201700686</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0005">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ghaffari</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>N.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Jardon</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M. A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Krahn</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>N.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Butler</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kennard</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Turner</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>R. F. B.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Gopaluni</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>B.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Piret</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>J. M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Effects of Cysteine, Asparagine, or Glutamine Limitations in Chinese Hamster Ovary Cell Batch and Fed-Batch Cultures</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Biotechnol. Prog.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2020</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>36</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/btpr.2946</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0006">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Chun</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>B. H.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kim</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>J. H.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Lee</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>H. J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Chung</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>N.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Usability of Size-Excluded Fractions of Soy Protein Hydrolysates for Growth and Viability of Chinese Hamster Ovary Cells in Protein-Free Suspension Culture</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Bioresour. Technol.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2007</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>98</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>1000</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>1005</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2006.04.012</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0007">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Torkashvand</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>F.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Vaziri</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>B.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Maleknia</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Heydari</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Vossoughi</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Davami</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>F.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Mahboudi</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>F.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Designed Amino Acid Feed in Improvement of Production and Quality Targets of a Therapeutic Monoclonal Antibody</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>PLOS One</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2015</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>10</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>e0140597</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0140597</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0008">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kochanowski</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>N.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Siriez</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>G.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Roosens</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Malphettes</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>L.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Medium and Feed Optimization for Fed-Batch Production of a Monoclonal Antibody in CHO Cells</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>BMC Proc.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2011</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>5</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/1753-6561-5-S8-P75</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0009">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Pan</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>X.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Streefland</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Dalm</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Wijffels</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>R. H.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Martens</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>D. E.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Selection of Chemically Defined Media for CHO Cell Fed-Batch Culture Processes</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Cytotechnology</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2017</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>69</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>39</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>56</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s10616-016-0036-5</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0010">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ha</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>T. K.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kim</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>D.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kim</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>C. L.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Grav</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>L. M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Lee</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>G. M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Factors Affecting the Quality of Therapeutic Proteins in Recombinant Chinese Hamster Ovary Cell Culture</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Biotechnol. Adv.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2022</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>54</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>107831</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.biotechadv.2021.107831</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0011">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Li</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>B.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Shen</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Y.-H.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>He</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Y.-R.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Zhang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>W.-D.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> Chemical Constituents and Biological Activities of Pinus Species. </x>
               <italic>Chem. Biodivers</italic>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. 2013, </x>
               <italic>10</italic>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>2133</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>2160</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0012">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Xiao</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Y. C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Shi</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Z. F.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Yan</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>C. Q.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Tang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Q. X.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Zhao</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M. X.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Liu</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>L. T.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Huang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Q. S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ye</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>L.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Xu</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>K.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ke</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>X.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Isolation, X-Ray Crystal Structure of the New Diterpene and Identification of Others Lignans and Flavonoids from the Fresh Needles of Pinus Massoniana</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>J. Asian Nat. Prod. Res.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2020</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>22</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>707</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>715</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/10286020.2019.1642331</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0013">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Park</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Lee</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>B.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Choi</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>H.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kim</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>W.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kim</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>H. J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Cheong</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>H.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Antithrombosis Activity of Protocatechuic and Shikimic Acids from Functional Plant <italic>Pinus densiflora</italic> Sieb. et Zucc Needles</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>J. Nat. Med.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2016</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>70</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>492</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>501</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11418-015-0956-y</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0014">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Dziedziński</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kobus-Cisowska</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Stachowiak</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>B.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Pinus Species as Prospective Reserves of Bioactive Compounds with Potential Use in Functional Food—Current State of Knowledge</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Plants</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2021</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>10</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>1306</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/plants10071306</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0015">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kuo</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>P. C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Li</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Y. C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kusuma</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A. M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Tzen</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>J. T. C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Hwang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>T. L.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ye</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>G. H.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Yang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M. L.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Wang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S. Y.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Anti-Inflammatory Principles from the Needles of <italic>Pinus taiwanensis</italic> Hayata and <italic>In Silico</italic> Studies of Their Potential Anti-Aging Effects</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Antioxidants</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2021</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>10</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>598</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/antiox10040598</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0016">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Koutsaviti</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Toutoungy</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Saliba</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>R.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Loupassaki</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Tzakou</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>O.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Roussis</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>V.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ioannou</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>E.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Antioxidant Potential of Pine Needles: A Systematic Study on the Essential Oils and Extracts of 46 Species of the Genus <italic>Pinus</italic>
               </article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Foods</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2021</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>10</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>142</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/foods10010</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0017">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Chu</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>L.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Yang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>L.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Lin</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>L.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Wei</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Wang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>N.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Xu</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Qiao</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>G.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Zheng</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>G.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Chemical Composition, Antioxidant Activities of Polysaccharide from Pine Needle (<italic>Pinus massoniana</italic>) and Hypolipidemic Effect in High-Fat Diet-Induced Mice</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Int. J. Biol. Macromol.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2019</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>125</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>445</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>452</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2018.12.082</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0018">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Urquiza</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>L. T.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>James</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>D. C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Nagy</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>T.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Falconer</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>R. J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Screening Naturally Occurring Phenolic Antioxidants for Their Suitability as Additives to CHO Cell Culture Media Used to Produce Monoclonal Antibodies</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Antioxidants</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2019</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>8</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>159</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/antiox8060159</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0019">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Hossler</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>P.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Racicot</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Chumsae</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>McDermott</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Cochran</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>K.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Cell Culture Media Supplementation of Infrequently Used Sugars for the Targeted Shifting of Protein Glycosylation Profiles</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Biotechnol. Prog.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2017</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>33</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>511</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>522</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/btpr.2429</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0020">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Hossler</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>P.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Wang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Mcdermott</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Racicot</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Chemfe</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>K.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Zhang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Y.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Chumsae</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Manuilov</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Cell Culture Media Supplementation of Bioflavonoids for the Targeted Reduction of Acidic Species Charge Variants on Recombinant Therapeutic Proteins</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Biotechnol. Prog.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2015</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>31</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>1039</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>1052</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/btpr.2095</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0021">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ho</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S. C. L.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Nian</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>R.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Woen</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Chng</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Zhang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>P.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Yang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Y.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Impact of Hydrolysates on Monoclonal Antibody Productivity, Purification and Quality in Chinese Hamster Ovary Cells</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>J. Biosci. Bioeng.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2016</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>122</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>499</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>506</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jbiosc.2016.03.003</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0022">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Du</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Y.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Walsh</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ehrick</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>R.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Xu</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>W.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>May</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>K.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Liu</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>H.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Chromatographic Analysis of the Acidic and Basic Species of Recombinant Monoclonal Antibodies</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>mAbs</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2012</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>4</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>578</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>585</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4161/mabs.21328</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0023">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Torkashvand</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>F.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Vaziri</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>B.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Main Quality Attributes of Monoclonal Antibodies and Effect of Cell Culture Components</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Iran Biomed. J.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2017</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>21</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>131</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>141</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.18869/acadpub.ibj.21.3.131</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0024">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="book">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Wright</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Morrison</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S. L.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <source>Effect of Glycosylation on Antibody Function: Implications for Genetic Engineering</source>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <italic>Trends Biotechnol</italic>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. 1997, </x>
               <italic>15,</italic>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> 26–32. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0167-7799(96)10062-7</pub-id>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0025">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Keck</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>R.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Nayak</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>N.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Lerner</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>L.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Raju</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ma</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Schreitmueller</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>T.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Chamow</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Moorhouse</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>K.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kotts</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Jones</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Characterization of a Complex Glycoprotein Whose Variable Metabolic Clearance in Humans is Dependent on Terminal <italic>N</italic>-Acetylglucosamine Content</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Biologicals</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2008</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>36</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>49</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>60</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.biologicals.2007.05.004</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0026">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Tebbey</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>P. W.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Varga</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Naill</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Clewell</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Venema</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Consistency of Quality Attributes for the Glycosylated Monoclonal Antibody Humira<sup>®</sup> (Adalimumab)</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>mAbs</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2015</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>7</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>805</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>811</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/19420862.2015.1073429</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0027">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Brühlmann</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>D.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Muhr</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Parker</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>R.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Vuillemin</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>T.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Bucsella</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>B.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kalman</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>F.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Torre</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>la Neve</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>F.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Lembo</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Haas</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>T.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve">; et al. </x>
               <article-title>Cell Culture Media Supplemented with Raffinose Reproducibly Enhances High Mannose Glycan Formation</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>J. Biotechnol.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2017</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>252</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>32</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>42</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jbiotec.2017.04.026</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0028">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Chung</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>C. Y.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Wang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Q.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Yang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ponce</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S. A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kirsch</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>B. J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Zhang</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>H.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>BeteNBaugh</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M. J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Combinatorial Genome and Protein Engineering Yields Monoclonal Antibodies with Hypergalactosylation from CHO Cells</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Biotechnol. Bioeng.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2017</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>114</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>2848</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>2856</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/bit.26375</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0029">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Grainger</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>R. K.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>James</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>D. C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>CHO Cell Line Specific Prediction and Control of Recombinant Monoclonal Antibody <italic>N</italic>-Glycosylation</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Biotechnol. Bioeng.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2013</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>110</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>2970</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>2983</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/bit.24959</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0030">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Pande</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Rahardjo</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Livingston</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>B.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Mujacic</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Monensin, a Small Molecule Ionophore, Can Be Used to Increase High Mannose Levels on Monoclonal Antibodies Generated by Chinese Hamster Ovary Production Cell-Lines</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Biotechnol. Bioeng.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2015</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>112</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>1383</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>1394</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/bit.25551/abstract</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0031">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Gramer</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>M. J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Eckblad</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>J. J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Donahue</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>R.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Brown</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Shultz</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Vickerman</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>K.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Priem</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>P.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>van den Bremer</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>E. T. J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Gerritsen</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>van Berkel</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>P. H. C.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Modulation of Antibody Galactosylation through Feeding of Uridine, Manganese Chloride, and Galactose</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Biotechnol. Bioeng.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2011</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>108</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>1591</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>1602</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/bit.23075</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0032">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Jefferis</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>R.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Glycosylation as a Strategy to Improve Antibody-Based Therapeutics</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Nat. Rev. Drug Discov.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2009</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>8</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>226</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>234</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nrd2804</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0033">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Liu</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>L.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Antibody Glycosylation and Its Impact on the Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of Monoclonal Antibodies and Fc-Fusion Proteins</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>J. Pharma. Sci.</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2015</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>104</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>1866</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>1884</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jps.24444</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="CIT0034">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
               <person-group person-group-type="author">
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Hossler</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>P.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Khattak</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>S. F.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <x xml:space="preserve">; </x>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Li</surname>
                     <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
                     <given-names>Z. J.</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <article-title>Optimal and Consistent Protein Glycosylation in Mammalian Cell Culture</article-title>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. </x>
               <source>
                  <italic>Glycobiology</italic>
               </source>
               <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
               <year>2009</year>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <volume>
                  <italic>19</italic>
               </volume>
               <x xml:space="preserve">, </x>
               <fpage>936</fpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">–</x>
               <lpage>949</lpage>
               <x xml:space="preserve">. DOI: </x>
               <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/glycob/cwp079</pub-id>
               <x xml:space="preserve">.</x>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>]]></body>
  <back>
    <ref-list>
      <ref id="0">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Ritacco</surname>
              <given-names>F. v.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wu</surname>
              <given-names>Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Khetan</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Cell Culture Media for Recombinant Protein Expression in Chinese Hamster Ovary (CHO) Cells: History, Key Components, and Optimization Strategies</article-title>
          <source>Biotechnol. Prog.</source>
          <year>2018</year>
          <fpage>1407</fpage>
          <lpage>1426</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="1">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Blondeel</surname>
              <given-names>E. J. M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ho</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Schulze</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sokolenko</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Guillemette</surname>
              <given-names>S. R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Slivac</surname>
              <given-names>I.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Durocher</surname>
              <given-names>Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Guillemette</surname>
              <given-names>J. G.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>McConkey</surname>
              <given-names>B. J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chang</surname>
              <given-names>D.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>An Omics Approach to Rational Feed: Enhancing Growth in CHO Cultures with NMR Metabolomics and 2D-DIGE Proteomics</article-title>
          <source>J. Biotechnol.</source>
          <year>2016</year>
          <fpage>127</fpage>
          <lpage>138</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="2">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Pérez-Rodriguez</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ramírez-Lira</surname>
              <given-names>M. d J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Trujillo-Roldán</surname>
              <given-names>M. A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Valdez-Cruz</surname>
              <given-names>N. A.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Nutrient Supplementation Strategy Improves Cell Concentration and Longevity, Monoclonal Antibody Production and Lactate Metabolism of Chinese Hamster Ovary Cells</article-title>
          <source>Bioengineered</source>
          <year>2020</year>
          <fpage>463</fpage>
          <lpage>471</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="3">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Reinhart</surname>
              <given-names>D.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Damjanovic</surname>
              <given-names>L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kaisermayer</surname>
              <given-names>C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sommeregger</surname>
              <given-names>W.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gili</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>GaSSelhuber</surname>
              <given-names>B.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Castan</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Mayrhofer</surname>
              <given-names>P.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Grünwald-Gruber</surname>
              <given-names>C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kunert</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Bioprocessing of Recombinant CHO-K1, CHO-DG44, and CHO-S: CHO Expression Hosts Favor Either MAb Production or Biomass Synthesis</article-title>
          <source>Biotechnol. J.</source>
          <year>2019</year>
          <fpage>1700686</fpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="4">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Ghaffari</surname>
              <given-names>N.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Jardon</surname>
              <given-names>M. A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Krahn</surname>
              <given-names>N.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Butler</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kennard</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Turner</surname>
              <given-names>R. F. B.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gopaluni</surname>
              <given-names>B.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Piret</surname>
              <given-names>J. M.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Effects of Cysteine, Asparagine, or Glutamine Limitations in Chinese Hamster Ovary Cell Batch and Fed-Batch Cultures</article-title>
          <source>Biotechnol. Prog.</source>
          <year>2020</year>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="5">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Chun</surname>
              <given-names>B. H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kim</surname>
              <given-names>J. H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lee</surname>
              <given-names>H. J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chung</surname>
              <given-names>N.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Usability of Size-Excluded Fractions of Soy Protein Hydrolysates for Growth and Viability of Chinese Hamster Ovary Cells in Protein-Free Suspension Culture</article-title>
          <source>Bioresour. Technol.</source>
          <year>2007</year>
          <fpage>1000</fpage>
          <lpage>1005</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="6">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Torkashvand</surname>
              <given-names>F.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Vaziri</surname>
              <given-names>B.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Maleknia</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Heydari</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Vossoughi</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Davami</surname>
              <given-names>F.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Mahboudi</surname>
              <given-names>F.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Designed Amino Acid Feed in Improvement of Production and Quality Targets of a Therapeutic Monoclonal Antibody</article-title>
          <source>PLOS One</source>
          <year>2015</year>
          <fpage>e0140597</fpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="7">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Kochanowski</surname>
              <given-names>N.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Siriez</surname>
              <given-names>G.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Roosens</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Malphettes</surname>
              <given-names>L.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Medium and Feed Optimization for Fed-Batch Production of a Monoclonal Antibody in CHO Cells</article-title>
          <source>BMC Proc.</source>
          <year>2011</year>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="8">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Pan</surname>
              <given-names>X.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Streefland</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Dalm</surname>
              <given-names>C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wijffels</surname>
              <given-names>R. H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Martens</surname>
              <given-names>D. E.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Selection of Chemically Defined Media for CHO Cell Fed-Batch Culture Processes</article-title>
          <source>Cytotechnology</source>
          <year>2017</year>
          <fpage>39</fpage>
          <lpage>56</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="9">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Ha</surname>
              <given-names>T. K.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kim</surname>
              <given-names>D.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kim</surname>
              <given-names>C. L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Grav</surname>
              <given-names>L. M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lee</surname>
              <given-names>G. M.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Factors Affecting the Quality of Therapeutic Proteins in Recombinant Chinese Hamster Ovary Cell Culture</article-title>
          <source>Biotechnol. Adv.</source>
          <year>2022</year>
          <fpage>107831</fpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="10">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Li</surname>
              <given-names>B.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Shen</surname>
              <given-names>Y.-H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>He</surname>
              <given-names>Y.-R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zhang</surname>
              <given-names>W.-D.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <fpage>2133</fpage>
          <lpage>2160</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="11">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Xiao</surname>
              <given-names>Y. C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Shi</surname>
              <given-names>Z. F.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yan</surname>
              <given-names>C. Q.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Tang</surname>
              <given-names>Q. X.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zhao</surname>
              <given-names>M. X.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Liu</surname>
              <given-names>L. T.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Huang</surname>
              <given-names>Q. S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ye</surname>
              <given-names>L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Xu</surname>
              <given-names>K.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ke</surname>
              <given-names>X.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Isolation, X-Ray Crystal Structure of the New Diterpene and Identification of Others Lignans and Flavonoids from the Fresh Needles of Pinus Massoniana</article-title>
          <source>J. Asian Nat. Prod. Res.</source>
          <year>2020</year>
          <fpage>707</fpage>
          <lpage>715</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="12">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Park</surname>
              <given-names>J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lee</surname>
              <given-names>B.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Choi</surname>
              <given-names>H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kim</surname>
              <given-names>W.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kim</surname>
              <given-names>H. J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Cheong</surname>
              <given-names>H.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Antithrombosis Activity of Protocatechuic and Shikimic Acids from Functional Plant Pinus densiflora Sieb. et Zucc Needles</article-title>
          <source>J. Nat. Med.</source>
          <year>2016</year>
          <fpage>492</fpage>
          <lpage>501</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="13">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Dziedziński</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kobus-Cisowska</surname>
              <given-names>J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Stachowiak</surname>
              <given-names>B.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Pinus Species as Prospective Reserves of Bioactive Compounds with Potential Use in Functional Food—Current State of Knowledge</article-title>
          <source>Plants</source>
          <year>2021</year>
          <fpage>1306</fpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="14">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Kuo</surname>
              <given-names>P. C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Li</surname>
              <given-names>Y. C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kusuma</surname>
              <given-names>A. M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Tzen</surname>
              <given-names>J. T. C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hwang</surname>
              <given-names>T. L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ye</surname>
              <given-names>G. H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yang</surname>
              <given-names>M. L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>S. Y.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Anti-Inflammatory Principles from the Needles of Pinus taiwanensis Hayata and In Silico Studies of Their Potential Anti-Aging Effects</article-title>
          <source>Antioxidants</source>
          <year>2021</year>
          <fpage>598</fpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="15">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Koutsaviti</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Toutoungy</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Saliba</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Loupassaki</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Tzakou</surname>
              <given-names>O.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Roussis</surname>
              <given-names>V.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ioannou</surname>
              <given-names>E.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Antioxidant Potential of Pine Needles: A Systematic Study on the Essential Oils and Extracts of 46 Species of the Genus Pinus</article-title>
          <source>Foods</source>
          <year>2021</year>
          <fpage>142</fpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="16">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Chu</surname>
              <given-names>L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yang</surname>
              <given-names>L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lin</surname>
              <given-names>L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wei</surname>
              <given-names>J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>N.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Xu</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Qiao</surname>
              <given-names>G.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zheng</surname>
              <given-names>G.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Chemical Composition, Antioxidant Activities of Polysaccharide from Pine Needle (Pinus massoniana) and Hypolipidemic Effect in High-Fat Diet-Induced Mice</article-title>
          <source>Int. J. Biol. Macromol.</source>
          <year>2019</year>
          <fpage>445</fpage>
          <lpage>452</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="17">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Urquiza</surname>
              <given-names>L. T.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>James</surname>
              <given-names>D. C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Nagy</surname>
              <given-names>T.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Falconer</surname>
              <given-names>R. J.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Screening Naturally Occurring Phenolic Antioxidants for Their Suitability as Additives to CHO Cell Culture Media Used to Produce Monoclonal Antibodies</article-title>
          <source>Antioxidants</source>
          <year>2019</year>
          <fpage>159</fpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="18">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Hossler</surname>
              <given-names>P.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Racicot</surname>
              <given-names>C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chumsae</surname>
              <given-names>C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>McDermott</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Cochran</surname>
              <given-names>K.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Cell Culture Media Supplementation of Infrequently Used Sugars for the Targeted Shifting of Protein Glycosylation Profiles</article-title>
          <source>Biotechnol. Prog.</source>
          <year>2017</year>
          <fpage>511</fpage>
          <lpage>522</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="19">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Hossler</surname>
              <given-names>P.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Mcdermott</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Racicot</surname>
              <given-names>C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chemfe</surname>
              <given-names>K.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zhang</surname>
              <given-names>Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chumsae</surname>
              <given-names>C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Manuilov</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Cell Culture Media Supplementation of Bioflavonoids for the Targeted Reduction of Acidic Species Charge Variants on Recombinant Therapeutic Proteins</article-title>
          <source>Biotechnol. Prog.</source>
          <year>2015</year>
          <fpage>1039</fpage>
          <lpage>1052</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="20">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Ho</surname>
              <given-names>S. C. L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Nian</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Woen</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chng</surname>
              <given-names>J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zhang</surname>
              <given-names>P.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yang</surname>
              <given-names>Y.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Impact of Hydrolysates on Monoclonal Antibody Productivity, Purification and Quality in Chinese Hamster Ovary Cells</article-title>
          <source>J. Biosci. Bioeng.</source>
          <year>2016</year>
          <fpage>499</fpage>
          <lpage>506</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="21">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Du</surname>
              <given-names>Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Walsh</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ehrick</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Xu</surname>
              <given-names>W.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>May</surname>
              <given-names>K.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Liu</surname>
              <given-names>H.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Chromatographic Analysis of the Acidic and Basic Species of Recombinant Monoclonal Antibodies</article-title>
          <source>mAbs</source>
          <year>2012</year>
          <fpage>578</fpage>
          <lpage>585</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="22">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Torkashvand</surname>
              <given-names>F.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Vaziri</surname>
              <given-names>B.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Main Quality Attributes of Monoclonal Antibodies and Effect of Cell Culture Components</article-title>
          <source>Iran Biomed. J.</source>
          <year>2017</year>
          <fpage>131</fpage>
          <lpage>141</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="23">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Wright</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Morrison</surname>
              <given-names>S. L.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="24">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Keck</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Nayak</surname>
              <given-names>N.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lerner</surname>
              <given-names>L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Raju</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ma</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Schreitmueller</surname>
              <given-names>T.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chamow</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Moorhouse</surname>
              <given-names>K.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kotts</surname>
              <given-names>C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Jones</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Characterization of a Complex Glycoprotein Whose Variable Metabolic Clearance in Humans is Dependent on Terminal N-Acetylglucosamine Content</article-title>
          <source>Biologicals</source>
          <year>2008</year>
          <fpage>49</fpage>
          <lpage>60</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="25">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Tebbey</surname>
              <given-names>P. W.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Varga</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Naill</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Clewell</surname>
              <given-names>J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Venema</surname>
              <given-names>J.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Consistency of Quality Attributes for the Glycosylated Monoclonal Antibody Humira® (Adalimumab)</article-title>
          <source>mAbs</source>
          <year>2015</year>
          <fpage>805</fpage>
          <lpage>811</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="26">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Brühlmann</surname>
              <given-names>D.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Muhr</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Parker</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Vuillemin</surname>
              <given-names>T.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Bucsella</surname>
              <given-names>B.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kalman</surname>
              <given-names>F.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Torre</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>la Neve</surname>
              <given-names>F.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lembo</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Haas</surname>
              <given-names>T.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Cell Culture Media Supplemented with Raffinose Reproducibly Enhances High Mannose Glycan Formation</article-title>
          <source>J. Biotechnol.</source>
          <year>2017</year>
          <fpage>32</fpage>
          <lpage>42</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="27">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Chung</surname>
              <given-names>C. Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>Q.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yang</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ponce</surname>
              <given-names>S. A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kirsch</surname>
              <given-names>B. J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zhang</surname>
              <given-names>H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>BeteNBaugh</surname>
              <given-names>M. J.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Combinatorial Genome and Protein Engineering Yields Monoclonal Antibodies with Hypergalactosylation from CHO Cells</article-title>
          <source>Biotechnol. Bioeng.</source>
          <year>2017</year>
          <fpage>2848</fpage>
          <lpage>2856</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="28">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Grainger</surname>
              <given-names>R. K.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>James</surname>
              <given-names>D. C.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>CHO Cell Line Specific Prediction and Control of Recombinant Monoclonal Antibody N-Glycosylation</article-title>
          <source>Biotechnol. Bioeng.</source>
          <year>2013</year>
          <fpage>2970</fpage>
          <lpage>2983</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="29">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Pande</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Rahardjo</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Livingston</surname>
              <given-names>B.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Mujacic</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Monensin, a Small Molecule Ionophore, Can Be Used to Increase High Mannose Levels on Monoclonal Antibodies Generated by Chinese Hamster Ovary Production Cell-Lines</article-title>
          <source>Biotechnol. Bioeng.</source>
          <year>2015</year>
          <fpage>1383</fpage>
          <lpage>1394</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="30">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Gramer</surname>
              <given-names>M. J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Eckblad</surname>
              <given-names>J. J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Donahue</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Brown</surname>
              <given-names>J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Shultz</surname>
              <given-names>C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Vickerman</surname>
              <given-names>K.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Priem</surname>
              <given-names>P.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>van den Bremer</surname>
              <given-names>E. T. J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gerritsen</surname>
              <given-names>J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>van Berkel</surname>
              <given-names>P. H. C.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Modulation of Antibody Galactosylation through Feeding of Uridine, Manganese Chloride, and Galactose</article-title>
          <source>Biotechnol. Bioeng.</source>
          <year>2011</year>
          <fpage>1591</fpage>
          <lpage>1602</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="31">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Jefferis</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Glycosylation as a Strategy to Improve Antibody-Based Therapeutics</article-title>
          <source>Nat. Rev. Drug Discov.</source>
          <year>2009</year>
          <fpage>226</fpage>
          <lpage>234</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="32">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Liu</surname>
              <given-names>L.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Antibody Glycosylation and Its Impact on the Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of Monoclonal Antibodies and Fc-Fusion Proteins</article-title>
          <source>J. Pharma. Sci.</source>
          <year>2015</year>
          <fpage>1866</fpage>
          <lpage>1884</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="33">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Hossler</surname>
              <given-names>P.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Khattak</surname>
              <given-names>S. F.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Li</surname>
              <given-names>Z. J.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Optimal and Consistent Protein Glycosylation in Mammalian Cell Culture</article-title>
          <source>Glycobiology</source>
          <year>2009</year>
          <fpage>936</fpage>
          <lpage>949</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
    </ref-list>
  </back>
</article>