<article article-type="Journal Article">
  <front>
    <journal-meta>
      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher"/>
      <journal-title-group>
        <journal-title>Biotechnology Progress</journal-title>
      </journal-title-group>
      <issn>8756-7938</issn>
      <issn>1520-6033</issn>
      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/btpr.3176</article-id>
      <article-id pub-id-type="wtfid">007922633_0000001_211018062618931331</article-id>
      <article-id pub-id-type="pmid">34021724</article-id>
      <article-id pub-id-type="tdm">wiley_TDM-10.1002/btpr.3176</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title>Modulation of high mannose levels in N‐linked glycosylation through cell culture process conditions to increase antibody‐dependent cell‐mediated cytotoxicity activity for an antibody biosimilar</article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <surname>Rameez</surname>
          <given-names>Shahid</given-names>
          <aff>Process Development KBI Biopharma Inc.</aff>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <surname>Gowtham</surname>
          <given-names>Yogender K.</given-names>
          <aff>Process Development KBI Biopharma Inc.</aff>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <surname>Nayar</surname>
          <given-names>Gautam</given-names>
          <aff>Process Development KBI Biopharma Inc.</aff>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <surname>Mostafa</surname>
          <given-names>Sigma S.</given-names>
          <aff>Process Development KBI Biopharma Inc.</aff>
        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date pub-type="pub">
        <day>18</day>
        <month>10</month>
        <year>2021</year>
      </pub-date>
      <volume>37</volume>
      <issue>5</issue>
      <fpage>n/a</fpage>
      <lpage>n/a</lpage>
      <abstract>
        <p>Abstract The regulatory approval of a biosimilar product is contingent on the favorable comparability of its safety and efficacy to that of the innovator product. As such, it is important to match the critical quality attributes of the biosimilar product to that of the innovator product. The N‐glycosylation profile of a monoclonal antibody (mAb) can influence effector function activities such as antibody‐dependent cell‐mediated cytotoxicity (ADCC) and complement‐dependent cytotoxicity. In this study, we describe efforts to modulate the high‐mannose (HM) levels of a biosimilar mAb produced in a Chinese hamster ovary cell fed‐batch process. Because the HM level of the mAb was observed to impact ADCC activity, it was desirable to match it to the innovator mAb&apos;s levels. Several cell culture process related factors known to modulate the HM content of N‐glycosylation were investigated, including osmolality, ammonium chloride (NH4Cl) addition, glutamine concentration, monensin addition, and the addition of alternate sugars and amino sugars to the feed medium. The process conditions evaluated varied in impact on HM levels, process performance and product quality. One condition, the addition of alternate sugars and amino sugars to feed medium, was identified as the preferred method for increasing HM levels with minimal disruptions to process performance or other product quality attributes. Interestingly, a secondary interaction between sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds and osmolality was observed during process scale‐up. These studies demonstrate sugar and amino sugar concentrations and osmolality are critical variables to evaluate to match HM content in biosimilar and their innovator mAbs.</p>
      </abstract>
      <kwd-group>
        <kwd>ADCC</kwd>
        <kwd>biosimilar</kwd>
        <kwd>glycosylation</kwd>
        <kwd>mammalian cell culture</kwd>
        <kwd>monoclonal antibody</kwd>
      </kwd-group>
      <kwd-group kwd-group-type="MESH Chemical">
        <items>
          <chemical.registryNumber>0</chemical.registryNumber>
          <chemical.name>Antibodies, Monoclonal</chemical.name>
          <chemical.ui>D000911</chemical.ui>
        </items>
        <items>
          <chemical.registryNumber>0</chemical.registryNumber>
          <chemical.name>Biosimilar Pharmaceuticals</chemical.name>
          <chemical.ui>D059451</chemical.ui>
        </items>
        <items>
          <chemical.registryNumber>PHA4727WTP</chemical.registryNumber>
          <chemical.name>Mannose</chemical.name>
          <chemical.ui>D008358</chemical.ui>
        </items>
      </kwd-group>
      <kwd-group kwd-group-type="MESH Subject Heading">
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Animals</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Antibodies, Monoclonal</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>Y</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
          <meshHeading.qualifier>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.name>chemistry</meshHeading.qualifier.name>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.ui>Q000737</meshHeading.qualifier.ui>
            </items>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.name>metabolism</meshHeading.qualifier.name>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.ui>Q000378</meshHeading.qualifier.ui>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.qualifier>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Antibody-Dependent Cell Cytotoxicity</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
          <meshHeading.qualifier>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.name>physiology</meshHeading.qualifier.name>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>Y</meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.ui>Q000502</meshHeading.qualifier.ui>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.qualifier>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Biosimilar Pharmaceuticals</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>Y</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
          <meshHeading.qualifier>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.name>chemistry</meshHeading.qualifier.name>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.ui>Q000737</meshHeading.qualifier.ui>
            </items>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.name>metabolism</meshHeading.qualifier.name>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.ui>Q000378</meshHeading.qualifier.ui>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.qualifier>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>CHO Cells</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Cell Culture Techniques</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
          <meshHeading.qualifier>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.name>methods</meshHeading.qualifier.name>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>Y</meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.ui>Q000379</meshHeading.qualifier.ui>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.qualifier>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Cricetinae</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Cricetulus</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Glycosylation</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
        </items>
        <items>
          <meshHeading.descriptor>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.name>Mannose</meshHeading.descriptor.name>
              <meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>Y</meshHeading.descriptor.majorTopic>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.descriptor>
          <meshHeading.qualifier>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.name>chemistry</meshHeading.qualifier.name>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.ui>Q000737</meshHeading.qualifier.ui>
            </items>
            <items>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.name>metabolism</meshHeading.qualifier.name>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>N</meshHeading.qualifier.majorTopic>
              <meshHeading.qualifier.ui>Q000378</meshHeading.qualifier.ui>
            </items>
          </meshHeading.qualifier>
        </items>
      </kwd-group>
      <sec sec-type="intro">
        <p>INTRODUCTION  Therapeutic monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) and antibody‐like proteins continue to dominate the biopharmaceutical drug industry with an ever increasing number of marketed products and investigational products in the clinic.1 Additionally, biosimilars are becoming increasingly popular as several blockbuster biologics have expired patents or are near the end of protection period.2,3 Biosimilar molecules are expected to have highly comparable product quality attributes, such as N‐glycosylation, to the innovator product to minimize clinical differences and to obtain regulatory approval. This makes the development and manufacture of the biosimilar products challenging and difficult. A vast majority of mAbs are expressed recombinantly in Chinese hamster ovary (CHO) cell lines and have N‐linked glycosylation sites at the conserved asparagine (Asn) residue (N297) in the heavy chains of the immunoglobulin G (IgG). During post‐translational modification, multiple sugar moieties (e.g., N‐acetylglucosamine [GlcNAc], mannose [Man], fucose, galactose, and sialic acid) are assembled with complex combinations to form a repertoire of glycosylation patterns.1 The glycoforms produced in CHO cells are mainly core‐fucosylated complex oligosaccharides with 0, 1, or 2 terminal galactose and low levels of afucosylated complex oligosaccharides, HM oligosaccharides, and hybrid oligosaccharides.4 The pattern of N‐linked glycosylation is typically considered to be a critical quality attribute because it can influence the structural integrity, biological function (efficacy), pharmacokinetics (half‐life), and immunogenicity of the mAb.5–8 Glycans that have a major impact on half‐life and effector functions of mAbs include fucose, sialic acid, galactose, and mannose.9 The presence of a fucose residue in the N‐glycoform reduces binding of the IgG to low affinity IgG Fc receptor III‐A (FcγRIIIa) due to steric hindrance.10 Hence, antibody‐dependent cell‐mediated cytotoxicity (ADCC) activity can generally be increased by reducing the fucose content of the IgG.11–15 A high sialic acid content is desired to increase the pharmacokinetics of a circulating glycoprotein but can also result in reduced receptor binding for some proteins16 and lower complement‐dependent cytotoxicity (CDC) activity.16,17 Sialic acid content affects the charge distribution, stability, and bioactivity of glycoproteins.18–20 A higher terminal galactose content in the N‐glycan structure can increase CDC activity and to a lesser extent ADCC activity9,21–23; however, exposed galactose can increase the clearance of the mAb.9 HM content has been shown to influence the pharmacokinetic properties and effector function of mAbs.24 An increase in HM content results in increased serum clearance rate,6,8,9,22,25–27 increased ADCC activity primarily due to the absence of a core fucose,9,25,26,28–30 and reduced CDC activity.9,25 In this study, we describe our efforts to modulate the N‐glycan profile of a biosimilar mAb produced by a CHO cell line to match that of an innovator mAb. After initial process development efforts, the ADCC activity of the biosimilar mAb was observed to be lower than that of the innovator mAb. The decrease in ADCC activity was attributed to the lower levels of afucosylated species, primarily lower level of HM glycans, present in the biosimilar mAb when compared to the innovator mAb. Hence the focus of this work was on increasing the HM content of the biosimilar mAb to match the levels seen in the innovator mAb. To appropriately control the levels and profile of N‐glycosylation during mAb manufacture, it is important to understand the factors and mechanisms that affect N‐linked glycosylation. The mechanism of N‐glycosylation in CHO cells has been extensively studied and is well understood.31 A simplified illustration of the N‐glycosylation pathway is depicted in Figure 1. N‐linked glycosylation takes place in the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) and in the Golgi region of the mammalian cell. Nucleotide sugars (e.g., uridine diphosphate [UDP]‐GlcNAc, guanosine diphosphate [GDP]‐Man, and UDP‐glucose [Glc]) are synthesized in the cytosol and are transported into the ER or the Golgi to form the building blocks of N‐glycans. Dolichol‐diphosphate (P–P)‐(GlcNAc)2‐(Man)5 is synthesized on the cytosolic side of the ER and is translocated to the lumen of the ER by a flippase (FLIP), and four additional Man residues and three Glc residues are sequentially added by the respective glycosyltransferases (mannosyltransferases (ManT) and glucosyltransferase (GlcT)) to form dolichol‐P‐P‐(GlcNAc)2‐(Man)9‐(Glc)3. In the ER, the 14‐saccharide core, (GlcNAc)2‐(Man)9‐(Glc)3, is then transferred as a single block from the dolichol to the Asn in the Asn‐X‐serine/threonine consensus N‐glycosylation site (with X representing any amino acid except proline) of a nascent peptide by a transmembrane oligosaccharyltransferase (OST). The three Glc residues and one Man residue are trimmed to form glycoprotein Asn‐(GlcNAc)2‐(Man)8 via the action of α‐glucosidases (I and II) and ER α‐mannosidase I (α‐Man I). The polypeptide chain is folded with the help of lectin chaperones and enters the cis‐Golgi. The N‐glycan entering the cis‐Golgi may also contain nine Man residues if trimming by α‐mannosidase I is not completed. The Man residues are further trimmed in the cis‐Golgi by α‐mannosidases (α‐Man I A, B, and C) resulting in a (GlcNAc)2‐(Man)5 intermediate. A GlcNAc residue is then added to the glycan structure by N‐acetylglucosaminyltransferase I (GnT‐I) in the medial‐Golgi, and the (GlcNAc)2‐(Man)5‐(GlcNAc) intermediate is modified by α‐mannosidase II (α‐Man II) to form a (GlcNAc)2‐(Man)3‐(GlcNAc) intermediate. Different branches of complex N‐glycans are generated by the action of a series of N‐acetylglucosaminyltransferases (GnT‐II, GnT‐IV, and GnT‐V) in the medial‐Golgi. A fucose residue may be added to GlcNAc adjacent to Asn in the core by the action of α‐(1,6)‐fucosyltransferase (Fuc T). Some of the (GlcNAc)2‐(Man)5‐(GlcNAc) intermediate may be converted to hybrid type and bisecting N‐glycans (not shown in figure). In the trans‐Golgi, the enzymes galactosyltransferase and sialyltransferase catalyze the transfer of galactose and sialic acid to the complex and hybrid N‐glycans (not shown in figure). The mature glycoprotein is then secreted from the Golgi. Commonly seen HM glycoform structures, which all lack core fucose, are shown in Figure 1. Levels of HM glycans on recombinant mAbs can range from 1% to greater than 20%.9 1 FIGURE  Schematic of N‐linked glycosylation pathway and key HM glycoforms. Labels in red indicates different factors that can modulate glycosylation to increase levels of HM glycoforms. HM, high‐mannose HM N‐glycans are generated when glycosylation is disrupted in the early to middle stages of processing such that the protein is secreted before GnT‐I has an opportunity to act on the glycan.28 Zalai et al. observed that HM content increased with specific productivity presumably due to bottlenecks in the later stages of the glycosylation pathway.32 Although significant research has been performed to date to understand and control N‐linked glycosylation in cell culture processes, there has been limited knowledge on the control of HM glycoforms. Cell line engineering approaches26,28,33,34 and the use of enzyme inhibitors7,28,35–41 in the cell culture process have been successfully used to increase the level of HM glycoforms. However, for multiple reasons these approaches were impractical to implement for the specific biosimilar project and the focus was directed to the identification of suitable cell culture conditions that could increase HM without significantly affecting process performance and other product quality attributes. Cell culture medium or feed components that have been reported to modulate HM levels include metal ions (manganese,28,42–48 copper,49 and zinc50), ammonia,28,48 mannose,51–57 other alternate sugars,7,43,44,55,57–60 amino sugars,28 ornithine metabolic pathway intermediates,43,49 intracellular redox modulators,43,49 nucleoside sugar precursors, choline,61 monensin (a small molecule ionophore),7,28,36,43,62 and cell cycle inhibitors.63 Cell culture process parameters that have been reported to modulate HM levels include culture osmolality28,48 and culture duration.28,43,48,53,64–66 A screening experiment was performed initially, using shake flasks, to evaluate several cell culture process factors that were reported in literature to be effective in increasing N‐glycan HM content. The factors studied included osmolality, increasing glutamine concentration, NH4Cl, and monensin in the cell culture medium, and the supplementation of two infrequently used sugars (mannose and fructose) and two amino sugars (glucosamine and galactosamine) in the cell culture feed. Glutamine produces ammonia via chemical decomposition and cell metabolism, and therefore its impact was expected to be similar to the addition of NH4Cl. The potential impacts of these factors in the glycosylation pathway are identified in Figure 1. The screening experiment was followed up by the optimization of two factors (sugars and amino sugars) that were identified to have the highest potential for matching the desired product quality attributes without impacting cell culture performance. The optimization study performed with ambr® 250 bioreactors resulted in lower HM than predicted possibly due to differences in osmolality between the shake flask and bioreactor cultures. This hypothesis was verified by adjusting the osmolality in a follow up study using 3‐L bioreactors. The results from this work are useful to those interested in modulating the HM level in glycoproteins without sacrificing cell culture performance. Additionally, the work highlights the importance of understanding small changes in process parameters and their impacts on product quality for successful and consistent process scale‐up.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec sec-type="materials|methods">
        <p>Cell line and cell expansion process  A proprietary, serum‐free adapted CHO cell line provided by a client, expressing a biosimilar mAb, was used for the study. Cells were thawed and propagated in suspension using 125‐ml–2‐L shake flasks in ProCHO™ 5 Protein‐free CHO Medium (Lonza, Basel, Switzerland) supplemented with 4 mM L‐glutamine (Thermo Fisher Scientific, MA), 2% proprietary feed mixture, and a 0.2% cystine‐tyrosine based feed (Thermo Fisher Scientific). An initial viable cell density (VCD) target of 0.35 ± 0.05 × 106 cells/ml was used to passage cells every 3 days during the seed train process. The shake flasks were maintained in a cell culture incubator at 37.0°C, 5% CO2, and 120 rpm agitation (19 mm orbital shaker). Fed‐batch production processes  The 2‐L shake flask seed train cultures were used to initiate fed‐batch process cultures, which were performed in 250‐ml non‐baffled shake flasks (Corning, NY), 250‐ml single‐use ambr250 bioreactors (Sartorius Stedim, Gottingen, Germany), and 3‐L glass bioreactors (Applikon Biotechnology, CA) at initial working volumes of 60 ml, 180 ml, and 1.5 L, respectively. The 200‐L bioreactors (XDR‐200, Cytiva, MA) were conducted at initial working volume of 100 L and were inoculated using Wave bioreactor (Cytiva) cultures. The fed‐batch process used ProCHO five Protein‐free CHO Medium supplemented with 4 mM L‐glutamine, and cultures were inoculated at an initial VCD of 0.50 ± 0.10 × 106 cells/ml. The cultures were fed with a hypoxanthine thymidine (HT) supplement (Thermo Fisher Scientific) to 1× concentration on day 0 after inoculation and on day 4 before feeding. Control fed‐batch cultures were fed with proprietary feed medium (52% of the initial working volume in total over the culture duration) and a cystine‐tyrosine based feed (5.2% of the initial working volume in total over the culture duration) on day 0 and on days 3–15. Non‐control fed‐batch cultures used to evaluate the effect of a sugar and/or amino sugar supplementation were fed similarly to the control fed‐batch cultures except the sugar or amino sugar was dissolved in the proprietary feed medium at the required concentration. An alternate feed, ActiCHO™ Feed A (45.5% of the initial working volume in total over the culture duration) and ActiCHO™ Feed B (4.55% of the initial working volume in total over the culture duration) (Cytiva), was also investigated in the shake flask screening study. Temperature was initially controlled at 37°C and then shifted to 33°C on day 8 for all runs. The shake flask cultures were cultured in an incubator with 5% CO2 and 120 rpm agitation (19 mm orbital shaker). Dissolved oxygen was controlled at a setpoint of 40% for the ambr250, 3 and 200‐L bioreactors by sparging oxygen gas. The pH was controlled for the 3 and 200‐L bioreactors at a setpoint of 7.00 ± 0.30 for days 0–3 and at a setpoint of 6.85 ± 0.15 for days 3–16 by sparging carbon dioxide gas and by addition of 1 M sodium carbonate. The production cultures were sampled daily to measure VCD and viability, metabolites, and osmolality using a Vi‐CELL™ Cell Viability Analyzer (Beckman Coulter, CA), BioProfile® FLEX Analyzer (Nova Biomedical, MA), and single sample osmometer (Advanced Instruments, MA), respectively. Culture supernatants collected on days 8, 10, 12, 14, and 16 for the shake flask runs and days 8–16 for the bioreactor runs were measured for antibody titer using a HPLC system (Agilent Technologies, CA) equipped with a Poros A/20 μM column (Applied Biosystems, CA). All cultures were harvested by centrifugation for small‐scale runs (up to 3 L bioreactor scale) and by depth filtration (MilliporeSigma, MA) for large‐scale runs (200–2000 L scale) on day 16 or when the viability fell below 50%. Glycosylation analysis  Day 16 harvest samples were used for glycosylation analysis. Samples were bound to a solid‐phase cartridge (GlykoPrep®, ProZyme, CA) and reacted with an enzymatic de‐glycosylation reagent (e.g., N‐glycosidase PNGase F), which resulted in the release of N‐linked glycans from the protein backbone. These released N‐glycans were eluted from the solid‐phase resin, isolated, labeled with a fluorescent tag (InstantAB™, GlykoPrep, ProZyme), and purified by a second solid‐phase extraction to remove any unbound dye. The labeled N‐glycans were then chromatographically separated by hydrophilic interaction chromatography using a UPLC BEH Glycan 1.7 μM column (Waters, MA) and a fluorescence detector (Agilent Technologies). Injection of similarly labeled N‐glycan standards allowed for identification of the N‐glycans present in the harvest sample. ADCC reporter assay  ADCC activity was measured using an ADCC bioassay kit (Promega, WI), which consisted of effector cells and target mTNFα‐CHO‐K1 cells. The effector cells were Jurkat T‐cells engineered to stably express the FcγRIIIa [V158 variant] and a nuclear factor of activated T‐cells (NFAT) response element. Antibody biological activity was quantified through luciferase produced as a result of NFAT pathway activation in effector cells. Plated target cells were incubated for 16–20 h in a 37°C, 5% CO2 humified incubator and then dosed with the antibody. Effector cells were dispensed into the target cell‐antibody solution, and the mixture was incubated for 6 ± 0.25 h in a 37°C, 5% CO2 humified incubator. A luciferase substrate was added to the solution after the incubation period, and effector cell luminescence was measured with a SpectraMax® i3x plate reader (Molecular Devices, CA). The data were fit to a four‐parameter logistic curve using SoftMax® Pro Software (Molecular Devices), and the biological activity was calculated relative to the reference standard. Concanavalin A affinity chromatography  HM glycoforms of biosimilar and innovator were separated on a Con A Sepharose® 4B resin (Cytiva). Con A binds molecules containing α‐D‐mannopyranosyl, α‐D‐glucopyranosyl, and sterically related residues. Operation recommendations by the vendor for procedure, buffers, and flow rates were followed to capture the N‐glycan species from the biosimilar and innovator. The flow through and eluate samples from the Con A resin were tested by released N‐glycan analysis as described above. Statistical analysis  Statistical analysis was conducted using Design‐Expert® Software Version 10/12 (Stat‐Ease, MN) for the shake flask fed‐batch study, which implemented a DOE approach to analyze the sugar and amino sugar supplemented feed combinations. Additionally, a response surface‐based DOE was implemented for the ambr250 study, which was designed and analyzed by Design‐Expert software.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec sec-type="conclusions">
        <p>CONCLUSION  It is well established in the literature that extracellular conditions affect production and quality of therapeutic antibodies including their post‐translational modifications. To our knowledge, this study is one of the first studies to present a comprehensive parallel evaluation of multiple factors known to impact regulation and control of HM species in a biosimilar mAb. Specifically, this study demonstrates the effects of several process parameters that result in an increase in HM species via disruption of ER and Golgi environments and modulation of key glycosylation related enzyme activities. Several cell culture process related factors known to modulate the HM content of N‐glycans, such as osmolality, NH4Cl addition, glutamine concentration, monensin addition, and the addition of alternate sugars and amino sugars to the feed medium, are assessed in this study. The addition of alternate sugars and amino sugars to feed medium was identified as the preferred method to increase levels of HM species with minimal disruptions to process performance or other product quality attributes. However, further in‐depth studies are necessary to elucidate the mechanism by which sugars and amino sugars affect production of HM species and other glycoforms. Additionally, this article highlights the use of definitive screening designs, like the one utilized in the shake flask screening study, to optimize sugar and amino sugar supplementation to alter glycosylation. Although the choice of the expression system and the control of the production parameters in the process development phases are instrumental to ensure the production of glycoproteins with consistent structures, this study elucidated the importance of understanding small changes in process parameters and their impacts on product quality. A modest difference in osmolality (30–70 mOsm/kg) observed during the scale‐up of the cell culture process was involved in a secondary interaction to attain consistently HM levels and in turn was observed to significantly regulate the ADCC activity of the antibody. This highlights the need for a control strategy early in process development to characterize the effect of glycan composition on effector functions as well as a comprehensive understanding of process parameters to build an operating space to produce antibodies with consistent glycan profiles. Product quality attributes, such as glycosylation, play a critical role in pharmacokinetic and in vivo efficacy of therapeutic antibodies. Furthermore, a consistent product quality profile is critical to ensure regulatory success, especially for a biosimilar product. The extensive discussion of background literature and our evaluation of cell culture factors on glycosylation modulation is an added benefit that can be utilized by peers for the modulation of HM species in therapeutic antibodies.</p>
      </sec>
      <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
  <body><![CDATA[<component xmlns="http://www.wiley.com/namespaces/wiley" xmlns:wiley="http://www.wiley.com/namespaces/wiley/wiley" xml:id="btpr3176" version="2.0" xml:lang="en" type="serialArticle">
<header>
<publicationMeta level="product">
<publisherInfo>
<publisherName>John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons, Inc.</publisherName>
<publisherLoc>Hoboken, USA</publisherLoc>
</publisherInfo>
<doi origin="wiley" registered="yes">10.1021/(ISSN)1520-6033</doi>
<issn type="print">8756-7938</issn>
<issn type="electronic">1520-6033</issn>
<idGroup>
<id type="product" value="BTPR"/>
</idGroup>
<titleGroup>
<title type="main" sort="BIOTECHNOLOGY PROGRESS">Biotechnology Progress</title>
<title type="short">Biotechnol Progress</title>
</titleGroup>
</publicationMeta>
<publicationMeta level="part" position="50">
<doi>10.1021/btpr.v37.5</doi>
<copyright ownership="thirdParty">© 2021 American Institute of Chemical Engineers</copyright>
<numberingGroup>
<numbering type="journalVolume" number="37">37</numbering>
<numbering type="journalIssue">5</numbering>
</numberingGroup>
<coverDate startDate="2021-09">September/October 2021</coverDate></publicationMeta>
<publicationMeta level="unit" position="110" type="article" status="forIssue">
<doi>10.1002/btpr.3176</doi>
<idGroup>
<id type="unit" value="BTPR3176"/>
<id type="eLocator" value="e3176"/>
</idGroup>
<countGroup>
<count type="pageTotal" number="14"/>
</countGroup>
<titleGroup>
<title type="articleCategory">RESEARCH ARTICLE</title>
<title type="tocHeading1">RESEARCH ARTICLES</title>
<title type="tocHeading2">Cell Culture and Tissue Engineering</title>
</titleGroup>
<copyright ownership="thirdParty">© 2021 American Institute of Chemical Engineers</copyright>
<eventGroup><event type="publishedOnlineAccepted" date="2021-05-22"/><event type="firstOnline" date="2021-06-18"/><event type="manuscriptRevised" date="2021-03-13"/><event type="publishedOnlineFinalForm" date="2021-10-18"/><event type="xmlCreated" date="2021-05-25" agent="SPi Global"/><event type="manuscriptReceived" date="2020-11-22"/><event type="publishedOnlineEarlyUnpaginated" date="2021-06-18"/><event type="manuscriptAccepted" date="2021-05-20"/><event type="xmlConverted" agent="Converter:WML3G_To_WML3G version:6.0.8 mode:FullText,remove_FC" date="2021-10-18"/></eventGroup>
<numberingGroup>
<numbering type="pageFirst">n/a</numbering>
<numbering type="pageLast">n/a</numbering>
</numberingGroup>
<correspondenceTo>
<lineatedText>
<line><b>Correspondence</b></line>
<line>Yogender K. Gowtham, Process Development, KBI Biopharma Inc., 4117 Emperor Blvd., Suite 200, Durham, NC 27703, USA.</line>
<line>Email: <email>ygowtham@kbibiopharma.com</email>
</line>
</lineatedText>
</correspondenceTo>
<selfCitationGroup><citation type="self" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-9001"><author><familyName>Rameez</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Gowtham</familyName> <givenNames>YK</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Nayar</familyName> <givenNames>G</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Mostafa</familyName> <givenNames>SS</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Modulation of high mannose levels in <i>N</i>‐linked glycosylation through cell culture process conditions to increase antibody‐dependent cell‐mediated cytotoxicity activity for an antibody biosimilar</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Progress</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2021">2021</pubYear>;<vol>37</vol>(<issue>5</issue>):<eLocator>e3176</eLocator>. <url href="https://doi.org/10.1002/btpr.3176">https://doi.org/10.1002/btpr.3176</url></citation></selfCitationGroup>
<objectNameGroup>
<objectName elementName="tabular">TABLE</objectName>
<objectName elementName="figure">FIGURE</objectName>
</objectNameGroup>
<attributeValueGroup>
<attributeValue element="note" value="equal" attribute="type"/>
</attributeValueGroup>

</publicationMeta>
<contentMeta>
<countGroup>
<count type="figureTotal" number="5"/>
<count type="tableTotal" number="4"/>
<count type="wordTotal" number="11126"/>
</countGroup>
<titleGroup>
<title type="main">Modulation of high mannose levels in <i>N</i>‐linked glycosylation through cell culture process conditions to increase antibody‐dependent cell‐mediated cytotoxicity activity for an antibody biosimilar</title>
<title type="shortAuthors">Rameez et al.</title>
</titleGroup>
<creators>
<creator creatorRole="author" xml:id="btpr3176-cr-0001" currentRef="#btpr3176-curr-0001" affiliationRef="#btpr3176-aff-0001">
<personName>
<givenNames>Shahid</givenNames>
<familyName>Rameez</familyName>
</personName>
</creator>
<creator creatorRole="author" xml:id="btpr3176-cr-0002" affiliationRef="#btpr3176-aff-0001" corresponding="yes">
<idGroup>
<id type="orcid" value="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-9372-3317"/>
</idGroup>
<personName>
<givenNames>Yogender K.</givenNames>
<familyName>Gowtham</familyName>
</personName>
<contactDetails>
<email>ygowtham@kbibiopharma.com</email>
</contactDetails>
</creator>
<creator creatorRole="author" xml:id="btpr3176-cr-0003" affiliationRef="#btpr3176-aff-0001">
<personName>
<givenNames>Gautam</givenNames>
<familyName>Nayar</familyName>
</personName>
</creator>
<creator creatorRole="author" xml:id="btpr3176-cr-0004" affiliationRef="#btpr3176-aff-0001">
<personName>
<givenNames>Sigma S.</givenNames>
<familyName>Mostafa</familyName>
</personName>
</creator>
</creators>
<affiliationGroup>
<affiliation xml:id="btpr3176-aff-0001" countryCode="US" type="organization">
<orgDiv>Process Development</orgDiv>
<orgName>KBI Biopharma Inc.</orgName>
<address>
<city>Durham</city>
<countryPart>North Carolina</countryPart>
<country>USA</country>
</address>
</affiliation>
<affiliation xml:id="btpr3176-curr-0001" countryCode="US" type="organization">
<orgDiv>Biologics Process Development and Commercialization</orgDiv>
<orgName>Merck &amp;amp; Co.</orgName>
<address>
<city>West Point</city>
<countryPart>Pennsylvania</countryPart>
<country>USA</country>
</address>
</affiliation>
</affiliationGroup>
<keywordGroup type="author" xml:lang="en">
<keyword xml:id="btpr3176-kwd-0001">ADCC</keyword>
<keyword xml:id="btpr3176-kwd-0002">biosimilar</keyword>
<keyword xml:id="btpr3176-kwd-0003">glycosylation</keyword>
<keyword xml:id="btpr3176-kwd-0004">mammalian cell culture</keyword>
<keyword xml:id="btpr3176-kwd-0005">monoclonal antibody</keyword>
</keywordGroup>
<supportingInformation xml:id="btpr3176-supInfo-0001">
<supportingInfoItem xml:id="btpr3176-supitem-0001">
<mediaResource alt="supplementary data" mimeType="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document" rendition="webOriginal" href="urn-x:wiley:87567938:media:btpr3176:btpr3176-sup-0001-Supinfo"/>
<caption><p><b>Data S1.</b> Supporting Information.</p>
</caption>
</supportingInfoItem>
</supportingInformation>
<abstractGroup>
<abstract type="main" xml:lang="en">
<title type="main">Abstract</title>
<p>The regulatory approval of a biosimilar product is contingent on the favorable comparability of its safety and efficacy to that of the innovator product. As such, it is important to match the critical quality attributes of the biosimilar product to that of the innovator product. The <fi>N</fi>‐glycosylation profile of a monoclonal antibody (mAb) can influence effector function activities such as antibody‐dependent cell‐mediated cytotoxicity (ADCC) and complement‐dependent cytotoxicity. In this study, we describe efforts to modulate the high‐mannose (HM) levels of a biosimilar mAb produced in a Chinese hamster ovary cell fed‐batch process. Because the HM level of the mAb was observed to impact ADCC activity, it was desirable to match it to the innovator mAb's levels. Several cell culture process related factors known to modulate the HM content of <fi>N</fi>‐glycosylation were investigated, including osmolality, ammonium chloride (NH<sub>4</sub>Cl) addition, glutamine concentration, monensin addition, and the addition of alternate sugars and amino sugars to the feed medium. The process conditions evaluated varied in impact on HM levels, process performance and product quality. One condition, the addition of alternate sugars and amino sugars to feed medium, was identified as the preferred method for increasing HM levels with minimal disruptions to process performance or other product quality attributes. Interestingly, a secondary interaction between sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds and osmolality was observed during process scale‐up. These studies demonstrate sugar and amino sugar concentrations and osmolality are critical variables to evaluate to match HM content in biosimilar and their innovator mAbs.</p>
</abstract>
</abstractGroup>
</contentMeta>
<noteGroup xml:id="btpr3176-ntgp-0001">
<note xml:id="btpr3176-note-0001" type="equal" numbered="no">
<p>Shahid Rameez and Yogender K. Gowtham contributed equally to this study.</p>
</note>
</noteGroup>
</header>
<body xml:id="btpr3176-body-0001" sectionsNumbered="yes">
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0001">
<title type="main">INTRODUCTION</title>
<p>Therapeutic monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) and antibody‐like proteins continue to dominate the biopharmaceutical drug industry with an ever increasing number of marketed products and investigational products in the clinic.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0001"><sup>1</sup></link> Additionally, biosimilars are becoming increasingly popular as several blockbuster biologics have expired patents or are near the end of protection period.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0002 #btpr3176-bib-0003"><sup>2,3</sup></link> Biosimilar molecules are expected to have highly comparable product quality attributes, such as <i>N</i>‐glycosylation, to the innovator product to minimize clinical differences and to obtain regulatory approval. This makes the development and manufacture of the biosimilar products challenging and difficult. A vast majority of mAbs are expressed recombinantly in Chinese hamster ovary (CHO) cell lines and have <i>N</i>‐linked glycosylation sites at the conserved asparagine (Asn) residue (N297) in the heavy chains of the immunoglobulin G (IgG). During post‐translational modification, multiple sugar moieties (e.g., <i>N</i>‐acetylglucosamine [GlcNAc], mannose [Man], fucose, galactose, and sialic acid) are assembled with complex combinations to form a repertoire of glycosylation patterns.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0001"><sup>1</sup></link> The glycoforms produced in CHO cells are mainly core‐fucosylated complex oligosaccharides with 0, 1, or 2 terminal galactose and low levels of afucosylated complex oligosaccharides, HM oligosaccharides, and hybrid oligosaccharides.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0004"><sup>4</sup></link> The pattern of <i>N</i>‐linked glycosylation is typically considered to be a critical quality attribute because it can influence the structural integrity, biological function (efficacy), pharmacokinetics (half‐life), and immunogenicity of the mAb.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0005 #btpr3176-bib-0006 #btpr3176-bib-0007 #btpr3176-bib-0008"><sup>5–8</sup></link></p>
<p>Glycans that have a major impact on half‐life and effector functions of mAbs include fucose, sialic acid, galactose, and mannose.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0009"><sup>9</sup></link> The presence of a fucose residue in the <i>N</i>‐glycoform reduces binding of the IgG to low affinity IgG Fc receptor III‐A (FcγRIIIa) due to steric hindrance.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0010"><sup>10</sup></link> Hence, antibody‐dependent cell‐mediated cytotoxicity (ADCC) activity can generally be increased by reducing the fucose content of the IgG.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0011 #btpr3176-bib-0012 #btpr3176-bib-0013 #btpr3176-bib-0014 #btpr3176-bib-0015"><sup>11–15</sup></link> A high sialic acid content is desired to increase the pharmacokinetics of a circulating glycoprotein but can also result in reduced receptor binding for some proteins<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0016"><sup>16</sup></link> and lower complement‐dependent cytotoxicity (CDC) activity.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0016 #btpr3176-bib-0017"><sup>16,17</sup></link> Sialic acid content affects the charge distribution, stability, and bioactivity of glycoproteins.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0018 #btpr3176-bib-0019 #btpr3176-bib-0020"><sup>18–20</sup></link> A higher terminal galactose content in the <i>N</i>‐glycan structure can increase CDC activity and to a lesser extent ADCC activity<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0009 #btpr3176-bib-0021 #btpr3176-bib-0022 #btpr3176-bib-0023"><sup>9,21–23</sup></link>; however, exposed galactose can increase the clearance of the mAb.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0009"><sup>9</sup></link> HM content has been shown to influence the pharmacokinetic properties and effector function of mAbs.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0024"><sup>24</sup></link> An increase in HM content results in increased serum clearance rate,<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0006 #btpr3176-bib-0008 #btpr3176-bib-0009 #btpr3176-bib-0022 #btpr3176-bib-0025 #btpr3176-bib-0026 #btpr3176-bib-0027"><sup>6,8,9,22,25–27</sup></link> increased ADCC activity primarily due to the absence of a core fucose,<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0009 #btpr3176-bib-0025 #btpr3176-bib-0026 #btpr3176-bib-0028 #btpr3176-bib-0029 #btpr3176-bib-0030"><sup>9,25,26,28–30</sup></link> and reduced CDC activity.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0009 #btpr3176-bib-0025"><sup>9,25</sup></link></p>
<p>In this study, we describe our efforts to modulate the <i>N</i>‐glycan profile of a biosimilar mAb produced by a CHO cell line to match that of an innovator mAb. After initial process development efforts, the ADCC activity of the biosimilar mAb was observed to be lower than that of the innovator mAb. The decrease in ADCC activity was attributed to the lower levels of afucosylated species, primarily lower level of HM glycans, present in the biosimilar mAb when compared to the innovator mAb. Hence the focus of this work was on increasing the HM content of the biosimilar mAb to match the levels seen in the innovator mAb.</p>
<p>To appropriately control the levels and profile of <i>N</i>‐glycosylation during mAb manufacture, it is important to understand the factors and mechanisms that affect <i>N</i>‐linked glycosylation. The mechanism of <i>N</i>‐glycosylation in CHO cells has been extensively studied and is well understood.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0031"><sup>31</sup></link> A simplified illustration of the <i>N</i>‐glycosylation pathway is depicted in Figure <link href="#btpr3176-fig-0001">1</link>. <i>N</i>‐linked glycosylation takes place in the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) and in the Golgi region of the mammalian cell. Nucleotide sugars (e.g., uridine diphosphate [UDP]‐GlcNAc, guanosine diphosphate [GDP]‐Man, and UDP‐glucose [Glc]) are synthesized in the cytosol and are transported into the ER or the Golgi to form the building blocks of <i>N</i>‐glycans. Dolichol‐diphosphate (P–P)‐(GlcNAc)<sub>2</sub>‐(Man)<sub>5</sub> is synthesized on the cytosolic side of the ER and is translocated to the lumen of the ER by a flippase (FLIP), and four additional Man residues and three Glc residues are sequentially added by the respective glycosyltransferases (mannosyltransferases (ManT) and glucosyltransferase (GlcT)) to form dolichol‐P‐P‐(GlcNAc)<sub>2</sub>‐(Man)<sub>9</sub>‐(Glc)<sub>3</sub>. In the ER, the 14‐saccharide core, (GlcNAc)<sub>2</sub>‐(Man)<sub>9</sub>‐(Glc)<sub>3</sub>, is then transferred as a single block from the dolichol to the Asn in the Asn‐X‐serine/threonine consensus <i>N</i>‐glycosylation site (with X representing any amino acid except proline) of a nascent peptide by a transmembrane oligosaccharyltransferase (OST). The three Glc residues and one Man residue are trimmed to form glycoprotein Asn‐(GlcNAc)<sub>2</sub>‐(Man)<sub>8</sub> via the action of α‐glucosidases (I and II) and ER α‐mannosidase I (α‐Man I). The polypeptide chain is folded with the help of lectin chaperones and enters the cis‐Golgi. The <i>N</i>‐glycan entering the cis‐Golgi may also contain nine Man residues if trimming by α‐mannosidase I is not completed. The Man residues are further trimmed in the cis‐Golgi by α‐mannosidases (α‐Man I A, B, and C) resulting in a (GlcNAc)<sub>2</sub>‐(Man)<sub>5</sub> intermediate. A GlcNAc residue is then added to the glycan structure by <i>N</i>‐acetylglucosaminyltransferase I (GnT‐I) in the medial‐Golgi, and the (GlcNAc)<sub>2</sub>‐(Man)<sub>5</sub>‐(GlcNAc) intermediate is modified by α‐mannosidase II (α‐Man II) to form a (GlcNAc)<sub>2</sub>‐(Man)<sub>3</sub>‐(GlcNAc) intermediate. Different branches of complex <i>N</i>‐glycans are generated by the action of a series of <i>N</i>‐acetylglucosaminyltransferases (GnT‐II, GnT‐IV, and GnT‐V) in the medial‐Golgi. A fucose residue may be added to GlcNAc adjacent to Asn in the core by the action of α‐(1,6)‐fucosyltransferase (Fuc T). Some of the (GlcNAc)<sub>2</sub>‐(Man)<sub>5</sub>‐(GlcNAc) intermediate may be converted to hybrid type and bisecting <i>N</i>‐glycans (not shown in figure). In the trans‐Golgi, the enzymes galactosyltransferase and sialyltransferase catalyze the transfer of galactose and sialic acid to the complex and hybrid <i>N</i>‐glycans (not shown in figure). The mature glycoprotein is then secreted from the Golgi. Commonly seen HM glycoform structures, which all lack core fucose, are shown in Figure <link href="#btpr3176-fig-0001">1</link>. Levels of HM glycans on recombinant mAbs can range from 1% to greater than 20%.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0009"><sup>9</sup></link></p>
<figure xml:id="btpr3176-fig-0001">
<label>1</label>
<title type="figureName">FIGURE</title>
<mediaResourceGroup>
<mediaResource alt="image" href="urn:x-wiley:87567938:media:btpr3176:btpr3176-fig-0001"/>



</mediaResourceGroup>
<caption>Schematic of <i>N</i>‐linked glycosylation pathway and key HM glycoforms. Labels in red indicates different factors that can modulate glycosylation to increase levels of HM glycoforms. HM, high‐mannose</caption>
</figure>
<p>HM <i>N</i>‐glycans are generated when glycosylation is disrupted in the early to middle stages of processing such that the protein is secreted before GnT‐I has an opportunity to act on the glycan.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0028"><sup>28</sup></link> Zalai et al. observed that HM content increased with specific productivity presumably due to bottlenecks in the later stages of the glycosylation pathway.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0032"><sup>32</sup></link> Although significant research has been performed to date to understand and control <i>N</i>‐linked glycosylation in cell culture processes, there has been limited knowledge on the control of HM glycoforms. Cell line engineering approaches<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0026 #btpr3176-bib-0028 #btpr3176-bib-0033 #btpr3176-bib-0034"><sup>26,28,33,34</sup></link> and the use of enzyme inhibitors<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0007 #btpr3176-bib-0028 #btpr3176-bib-0035 #btpr3176-bib-0036 #btpr3176-bib-0037 #btpr3176-bib-0038 #btpr3176-bib-0039 #btpr3176-bib-0040 #btpr3176-bib-0041"><sup>7,28,35–41</sup></link> in the cell culture process have been successfully used to increase the level of HM glycoforms. However, for multiple reasons these approaches were impractical to implement for the specific biosimilar project and the focus was directed to the identification of suitable cell culture conditions that could increase HM without significantly affecting process performance and other product quality attributes. Cell culture medium or feed components that have been reported to modulate HM levels include metal ions (manganese,<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0028 #btpr3176-bib-0042 #btpr3176-bib-0043 #btpr3176-bib-0044 #btpr3176-bib-0045 #btpr3176-bib-0046 #btpr3176-bib-0047 #btpr3176-bib-0048"><sup>28,42–48</sup></link> copper,<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0049"><sup>49</sup></link> and zinc<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0050"><sup>50</sup></link>), ammonia,<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0028 #btpr3176-bib-0048"><sup>28,48</sup></link> mannose,<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0051 #btpr3176-bib-0052 #btpr3176-bib-0053 #btpr3176-bib-0054 #btpr3176-bib-0055 #btpr3176-bib-0056 #btpr3176-bib-0057"><sup>51–57</sup></link> other alternate sugars,<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0007 #btpr3176-bib-0043 #btpr3176-bib-0044 #btpr3176-bib-0055 #btpr3176-bib-0057 #btpr3176-bib-0058 #btpr3176-bib-0059 #btpr3176-bib-0060"><sup>7,43,44,55,57–60</sup></link> amino sugars,<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0028"><sup>28</sup></link> ornithine metabolic pathway intermediates,<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0043 #btpr3176-bib-0049"><sup>43,49</sup></link> intracellular redox modulators,<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0043 #btpr3176-bib-0049"><sup>43,49</sup></link> nucleoside sugar precursors, choline,<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0061"><sup>61</sup></link> monensin (a small molecule ionophore),<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0007 #btpr3176-bib-0028 #btpr3176-bib-0036 #btpr3176-bib-0043 #btpr3176-bib-0062"><sup>7,28,36,43,62</sup></link> and cell cycle inhibitors.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0063"><sup>63</sup></link> Cell culture process parameters that have been reported to modulate HM levels include culture osmolality<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0028 #btpr3176-bib-0048"><sup>28,48</sup></link> and culture duration.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0028 #btpr3176-bib-0043 #btpr3176-bib-0048 #btpr3176-bib-0053 #btpr3176-bib-0064 #btpr3176-bib-0065 #btpr3176-bib-0066"><sup>28,43,48,53,64–66</sup></link></p>
<p>A screening experiment was performed initially, using shake flasks, to evaluate several cell culture process factors that were reported in literature to be effective in increasing <i>N</i>‐glycan HM content. The factors studied included osmolality, increasing glutamine concentration, NH<sub>4</sub>Cl, and monensin in the cell culture medium, and the supplementation of two infrequently used sugars (mannose and fructose) and two amino sugars (glucosamine and galactosamine) in the cell culture feed. Glutamine produces ammonia via chemical decomposition and cell metabolism, and therefore its impact was expected to be similar to the addition of NH<sub>4</sub>Cl. The potential impacts of these factors in the glycosylation pathway are identified in Figure <link href="#btpr3176-fig-0001">1</link>. The screening experiment was followed up by the optimization of two factors (sugars and amino sugars) that were identified to have the highest potential for matching the desired product quality attributes without impacting cell culture performance. The optimization study performed with ambr® 250 bioreactors resulted in lower HM than predicted possibly due to differences in osmolality between the shake flask and bioreactor cultures. This hypothesis was verified by adjusting the osmolality in a follow up study using 3‐L bioreactors. The results from this work are useful to those interested in modulating the HM level in glycoproteins without sacrificing cell culture performance. Additionally, the work highlights the importance of understanding small changes in process parameters and their impacts on product quality for successful and consistent process scale‐up.</p>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0002">
<title type="main">MATERIALS AND METHODS</title>
<p>A screening study in shake flasks was used to investigate the impact of multiple factors on <i>N</i>‐glycan HM level modulation. This was followed by a response surface‐based design‐of‐experiments (DOE) approach using ambr250 bioreactors to optimize the mannose and glucosamine concentrations in the feed medium (data not shown). An additional experiment with 3‐L bioreactors was conducted to troubleshoot and establish fed‐batch process scalability. A schematic overview of experiments conducted as part of this manuscript is shown in the <link href="#btpr3176-supitem-0001">Data S1</link> (<link href="#btpr3176-supitem-0001">Figure S8</link>). Four 200‐L bioreactor runs were conducted using the baseline process (referred as the control condition) in the pilot plant (<i>n</i> = 2) and the current good manufacturing practice (cGMP) facility (<i>n</i> = 2).</p>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0003">
<title type="main">Cell line and cell expansion process</title>
<p>A proprietary, serum‐free adapted CHO cell line provided by a client, expressing a biosimilar mAb, was used for the study. Cells were thawed and propagated in suspension using 125‐ml–2‐L shake flasks in ProCHO™ 5 Protein‐free CHO Medium (Lonza, Basel, Switzerland) supplemented with 4 mM L‐glutamine (Thermo Fisher Scientific, MA), 2% proprietary feed mixture, and a 0.2% cystine‐tyrosine based feed (Thermo Fisher Scientific). An initial viable cell density (VCD) target of 0.35 ± 0.05 × 10<sup>6</sup> cells/ml was used to passage cells every 3 days during the seed train process. The shake flasks were maintained in a cell culture incubator at 37.0°C, 5% CO<sub>2</sub>, and 120 rpm agitation (19 mm orbital shaker).</p>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0004">
<title type="main">Fed‐batch production processes</title>
<p>The 2‐L shake flask seed train cultures were used to initiate fed‐batch process cultures, which were performed in 250‐ml non‐baffled shake flasks (Corning, NY), 250‐ml single‐use ambr250 bioreactors (Sartorius Stedim, Gottingen, Germany), and 3‐L glass bioreactors (Applikon Biotechnology, CA) at initial working volumes of 60 ml, 180 ml, and 1.5 L, respectively. The 200‐L bioreactors (XDR‐200, Cytiva, MA) were conducted at initial working volume of 100 L and were inoculated using Wave bioreactor (Cytiva) cultures. The fed‐batch process used ProCHO five Protein‐free CHO Medium supplemented with 4 mM L‐glutamine, and cultures were inoculated at an initial VCD of 0.50 ± 0.10 × 10<sup>6</sup> cells/ml. The cultures were fed with a hypoxanthine thymidine (HT) supplement (Thermo Fisher Scientific) to 1× concentration on day 0 after inoculation and on day 4 before feeding. Control fed‐batch cultures were fed with proprietary feed medium (52% of the initial working volume in total over the culture duration) and a cystine‐tyrosine based feed (5.2% of the initial working volume in total over the culture duration) on day 0 and on days 3–15. Non‐control fed‐batch cultures used to evaluate the effect of a sugar and/or amino sugar supplementation were fed similarly to the control fed‐batch cultures except the sugar or amino sugar was dissolved in the proprietary feed medium at the required concentration. An alternate feed, ActiCHO™ Feed A (45.5% of the initial working volume in total over the culture duration) and ActiCHO™ Feed B (4.55% of the initial working volume in total over the culture duration) (Cytiva), was also investigated in the shake flask screening study. Temperature was initially controlled at 37°C and then shifted to 33°C on day 8 for all runs. The shake flask cultures were cultured in an incubator with 5% CO<sub>2</sub> and 120 rpm agitation (19 mm orbital shaker). Dissolved oxygen was controlled at a setpoint of 40% for the ambr250, 3 and 200‐L bioreactors by sparging oxygen gas. The pH was controlled for the 3 and 200‐L bioreactors at a setpoint of 7.00 ± 0.30 for days 0–3 and at a setpoint of 6.85 ± 0.15 for days 3–16 by sparging carbon dioxide gas and by addition of 1 M sodium carbonate. The production cultures were sampled daily to measure VCD and viability, metabolites, and osmolality using a Vi‐CELL™ Cell Viability Analyzer (Beckman Coulter, CA), BioProfile® FLEX Analyzer (Nova Biomedical, MA), and single sample osmometer (Advanced Instruments, MA), respectively. Culture supernatants collected on days 8, 10, 12, 14, and 16 for the shake flask runs and days 8–16 for the bioreactor runs were measured for antibody titer using a HPLC system (Agilent Technologies, CA) equipped with a Poros A/20 μM column (Applied Biosystems, CA). All cultures were harvested by centrifugation for small‐scale runs (up to 3 L bioreactor scale) and by depth filtration (MilliporeSigma, MA) for large‐scale runs (200–2000 L scale) on day 16 or when the viability fell below 50%.</p>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0005">
<title type="main">Glycosylation analysis</title>
<p>Day 16 harvest samples were used for glycosylation analysis. Samples were bound to a solid‐phase cartridge (GlykoPrep®, ProZyme, CA) and reacted with an enzymatic de‐glycosylation reagent (e.g., <i>N</i>‐glycosidase PNGase F), which resulted in the release of <i>N</i>‐linked glycans from the protein backbone. These released <i>N</i>‐glycans were eluted from the solid‐phase resin, isolated, labeled with a fluorescent tag (InstantAB™, GlykoPrep, ProZyme), and purified by a second solid‐phase extraction to remove any unbound dye. The labeled <i>N</i>‐glycans were then chromatographically separated by hydrophilic interaction chromatography using a UPLC BEH Glycan 1.7 μM column (Waters, MA) and a fluorescence detector (Agilent Technologies). Injection of similarly labeled <i>N</i>‐glycan standards allowed for identification of the <i>N</i>‐glycans present in the harvest sample.</p>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0006">
<title type="main"><fc>ADCC</fc> reporter assay</title>
<p>ADCC activity was measured using an ADCC bioassay kit (Promega, WI), which consisted of effector cells and target mTNFα‐CHO‐K1 cells. The effector cells were Jurkat T‐cells engineered to stably express the FcγRIIIa [V158 variant] and a nuclear factor of activated T‐cells (NFAT) response element. Antibody biological activity was quantified through luciferase produced as a result of NFAT pathway activation in effector cells. Plated target cells were incubated for 16–20 h in a 37°C, 5% CO<sub>2</sub> humified incubator and then dosed with the antibody. Effector cells were dispensed into the target cell‐antibody solution, and the mixture was incubated for 6 ± 0.25 h in a 37°C, 5% CO<sub>2</sub> humified incubator. A luciferase substrate was added to the solution after the incubation period, and effector cell luminescence was measured with a SpectraMax® i3x plate reader (Molecular Devices, CA). The data were fit to a four‐parameter logistic curve using SoftMax® Pro Software (Molecular Devices), and the biological activity was calculated relative to the reference standard.</p>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0007">
<title type="main">Concanavalin A affinity chromatography</title>
<p>HM glycoforms of biosimilar and innovator were separated on a Con A Sepharose® 4B resin (Cytiva). Con A binds molecules containing α‐D‐mannopyranosyl, α‐D‐glucopyranosyl, and sterically related residues. Operation recommendations by the vendor for procedure, buffers, and flow rates were followed to capture the <i>N</i>‐glycan species from the biosimilar and innovator. The flow through and eluate samples from the Con A resin were tested by released <i>N</i>‐glycan analysis as described above.</p>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0008">
<title type="main">Statistical analysis</title>
<p>Statistical analysis was conducted using Design‐Expert® Software Version 10/12 (Stat‐Ease, MN) for the shake flask fed‐batch study, which implemented a DOE approach to analyze the sugar and amino sugar supplemented feed combinations. Additionally, a response surface‐based DOE was implemented for the ambr250 study, which was designed and analyzed by Design‐Expert software.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0009">
<title type="main">RESULTS AND DISCUSSION</title>
<p>The ADCC activity of the biosimilar drug substance (DS) produced in 200‐L clinical and pilot scale batches (<i>n</i> = 4) was found to be significantly lower than that of the innovator drug product (DP). Testing performed by a contract research organization showed that the biosimilar DS had up to 60% lower ADCC activity compared to the innovator DP (data not shown). Because the ADCC activity of the biosimilar mAb was considered a key component of its efficacy, additional process development studies had to be performed to increase ADCC activity of the biosimilar DS. In the literature, improvements in ADCC activity of up to 50‐fold have been attributed to increases in the afucosylated species in <i>N</i>‐glycosylation of mAbs.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0011"><sup>11</sup></link> The reduction in ADCC activity and the reduced FcγRIIIa binding of the biosimilar DS compared to the innovator DP indicated that modulating <i>N</i>‐glycosylation levels, especially afucosylation levels, of the biosimilar DS could increase its ADCC activity.</p>
<p>The relative fucose and HM levels in <i>N</i>‐linked glycoforms for innovator DP lots (<i>n</i> = 16) and biosimilar DS lots (<i>n</i> = 4) are compared in Figure <link href="#btpr3176-fig-0002">2</link>. The variability (SD) in 16 innovator DP lots sourced from five different countries was low, especially for afucosylation and HM levels (within ±7%). The afucosylation levels for biosimilar DS were observed to be up to 5‐fold lower compared to innovator DP. Interestingly, these differences in afucosylation levels were mainly due to differences in HM glycoforms between the biosimilar DS and the innovator DP. As observed in Figure <link href="#btpr3176-fig-0002">2</link>, biosimilar DS HM levels were up to 5‐fold lower than the innovator DP while other afucosylated species (G0 + G1 + G2) levels were comparable with the innovator DP. As a result, the difference in HM levels between the biosimilar DS and the innovator DP was hypothesized to be the main root cause for the difference in observed ADCC activity. Studies have shown that HM glycoforms, similar to other afucosylated species, exhibited higher ADCC activity and FcγRIIIa binding.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0025 #btpr3176-bib-0043"><sup>25,43</sup></link> Furthermore, for a biosimilar mAb to be considered comparable to an innovator mAb, it is important that the analytical characteristics of the biosimilar mAb, particularly critical quality attributes, and clinical data match closely with that of the innovator mAb.</p>
<figure xml:id="btpr3176-fig-0002">
<label>2</label>
<title type="figureName">FIGURE</title>
<mediaResourceGroup>
<mediaResource alt="image" href="urn:x-wiley:87567938:media:btpr3176:btpr3176-fig-0002"/>



</mediaResourceGroup>
<caption><i>N</i>‐linked glycosylation comparison between innovator DP lots and biosimilar DS lots manufactured at KBI Biopharma. The species levels that were compared between the two lots were fucosylation (first bar set), afucosylation (second bar set), afucosylation without HM (third bar set) and HM (fourth bar set). The error bars represent 1 standard deviation for each species in innovator and biosimilar. DS, drug substance; HM, high‐mannose</caption>
</figure>
<p>Prior to initiating studies to increase HM levels in the biosimilar DS, a study was conducted to test the hypothesis that increasing HM levels would result in higher ADCC activity. A Con A column, which consists of Sepharose coupled to a lectin that binds mannose, was used to isolate flow through and eluate fractions of varying HM species concentrations from the biosimilar DS and the innovator DP. The isolated fractions were used to create mixtures with different ratios of HM species in the biosimilar DS and innovator DP (Table <link href="#btpr3176-tbl-0001">1</link>). When the ADCC activities of the mixtures were measured, a direct correlation between the ADCC activity and the level of HM species in <i>N</i>‐glycosylation was observed for both molecules. In general, biosimilar mixtures with increased levels of HM species had higher ADCC activities compared to the biosimilar DS, and the innovator mixtures with reduced levels of HM species had lower ADCC activities compared to the innovator DP. However, the correlation between the levels of HM species in mixtures and their ADCC activities was not linear. This was evident in two biosimilar DS mixtures where levels of HM species increased from 45% to 70% compared to the innovator DP, but these two mixtures had similar ADCC activities. Since the Con A study was designed to be a rapid proof of concept demonstration to test the relationship between ADCC activity and HM levels, the nonlinear observation was not further evaluated. However, the experiment confirmed that the decrease in ADCC activity for the biosimilar DS could be attributed to the lower levels of HM species relative to the innovator DP. Typically, HM species such as Man 5 and Man 8/9 should be controlled at low levels to avoid immunogenicity and clearance concerns, which must be considered along with their effect on efficacy.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0025 #btpr3176-bib-0027 #btpr3176-bib-0067"><sup>25,27,67</sup></link> Hence, several cell culture related factors known to modulate the HM content of mAbs were investigated. The goals of these studies were to identify factor(s) least disruptive to process performance to achieve an appropriate increase in HM species to mitigate the lower ADCC activity in the biosimilar DS and to negate any efficacy concerns in vivo.</p>
<tabular xml:id="btpr3176-tbl-0001">
<label>1</label>
<titleGroup>
<title type="tabularName">TABLE</title>
<title type="main">HM and ADCC activity for various mixtures of Con A‐generated flow through (F) and eluate (E)</title>
</titleGroup>
<table rowsep="0" colsep="1" pgwide="1" frame="topbot">
<tgroup cols="4">
<colspec align="left" colname="col1" colnum="1"/>
<colspec align="char" colname="col2" colnum="2" char="."/>
<colspec align="char" colname="col3" colnum="3" char="."/>
<colspec align="char" colname="col4" colnum="4" char="."/>
<thead valign="bottom">
<row rowsep="1">
<entry colname="col1" align="left" rowsep="1" morerows="1">Source</entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left" rowsep="1" morerows="1">F:E ratio</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left" rowsep="1">HM</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left" rowsep="1" morerows="1">ADCC activity</entry>
</row>
<row rowsep="1">
<entry colname="col3" align="left">(% compared to innovator)</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col4">Innovator DP</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Untreated</entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left">‐</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left">100</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left">100</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Con A flow through</entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left">100:0</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left">5</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left">50</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Con A <i>eluate</i></entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left">0:100</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left">369</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left">Not tested</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Mixture 1</entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left">82:18</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left">72</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left">76</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col4">Biosimilar DS</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Untreated</entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left">‐</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left">17</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left">Not tested</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Con A <i>flow through</i></entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left">100:0</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left">0</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left">Not tested</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Con A <i>eluate</i></entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left">0:100</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left">221</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left">Not tested</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Mixture 1</entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left">90:10</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left">19</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left">55</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Mixture 2</entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left">78:22</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left">45</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left">78</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Mixture 3</entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left">67:33</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left">70</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left">74</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<noteGroup xml:id="btpr3176-ntgp-0002">
<note xml:id="btpr3176-note-0002" numbered="no">
<p>Abbreviations: ADCC, antibody‐dependent cell‐mediated cytotoxicity; DS, drug substance; HM, high‐mannose.</p>
</note>
</noteGroup>
</tabular>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0010">
<title type="main">Screening factors that modulate <fc>HM</fc> levels in <fi>N</fi>‐linked glycosylation</title>
<p>The shake flask screening study focused on factors that disrupted the glycosylation pathway to achieve the required increase in HM species. Cell culture process parameters that are known to disrupt glycan transport and maturation, specifically in or before the medial Golgi, such as osmolality, glutamine concentration, changing intracellular pH using NH<sub>4</sub>Cl, and monensin, were tested in 250‐ml shake flasks. In addition, feed medium was supplemented with different sugars (mannose and fructose) and amino sugars (glucosamine and galactosamine), which are known to change glycosylation pathway fluxes. Nine different combinations of these sugars and amino sugars were tested in this study to observe the impact on HM levels. Finally, an alternative feed media was also evaluated. Table <link href="#btpr3176-tbl-0002">2</link> summarizes the process outputs, including cell growth, metabolites, and titer yield, for the screening conditions tested in comparison to the control in the form of a heat map. Product quality attributes, such as HM and fucose content, are color‐coded in comparison to the innovator mAb levels. The visualization is presented to show the magnitude of impact and changes observed with the factors on the cell culture process attributes. The results from the shake flask screening study for the various factors are discussed in the following sections.</p>
<tabular xml:id="btpr3176-tbl-0002">
<label>2</label>
<titleGroup>
<title type="tabularName">TABLE</title>
<title type="main">Heat map comparing various cell culture process outputs, percent mannose relative to innovator, and percent ADCC activity relative to innovator from the shake flask screening study</title>
</titleGroup>
<table rowsep="0" colsep="0" pgwide="1" frame="topbot">
<tgroup cols="10">
<colspec align="left" colname="col1" colnum="1"/>
<colspec align="left" colname="col2" colnum="2"/>
<colspec align="left" colname="col3" colnum="3"/>
<colspec align="left" colname="col4" colnum="4"/>
<colspec align="left" colname="col5" colnum="5"/>
<colspec align="left" colname="col6" colnum="6"/>
<colspec align="left" colname="col7" colnum="7"/>
<colspec align="left" colname="col8" colnum="8"/>
<colspec align="left" colname="col9" colnum="9"/>
<colspec align="left" colname="col10" colnum="10"/>
<thead valign="bottom">
<row rowsep="1">
<entry colname="col1" align="left">Condition</entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left">% ADCC relative to innovator</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left">% HM relative to innovator</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left">Total fucose (%)</entry>
<entry colname="col5" align="left">Peak VCD (*10̂6 cells/ml)</entry>
<entry colname="col6" align="left">Harvest viability (%)</entry>
<entry colname="col7" align="left">Harvest lactate (g/L)</entry>
<entry colname="col8" align="left">Harvest ammonia (mM)</entry>
<entry colname="col9" align="left">Harvest osmolality (mOsm/kg)</entry>
<entry colname="col10" align="left">Harvest titer (g/L)</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry colname="col1">Control</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#203764"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#92D050"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col10">Osmolality increase using NaCl (mOsm/kg)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Bolus 100 Units</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#757171"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#203764"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#8EA9DB"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Bolus 200 Units</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#757171"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#203764"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#203764"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Gradual 200 Units</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#757171"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#203764"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#8EA9DB"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#203764"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col10">Intracellular pH modulation</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">NH<sub>4</sub>Cl (7.5 mM)</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#757171"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#203764"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#92D050"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">NH<sub>4</sub>Cl (15 mM)</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#757171"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#203764"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#92D050"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Glutamine (8 mM)</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#757171"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#203764"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#92D050"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col10">Small molecule ionophore (Monensin)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">100 nM</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#203764"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#203764"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">500 nM</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#757171"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#203764"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#203764"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col10">Different feeds</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">ActiCHO Feeds</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#203764"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#203764"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col10">Sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds (Mannose [M], Glucosamine [GA], Fructose [F], Galactosamine [GLA])</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">M (I)</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#92D050"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">GA and F (II)</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#8EA9DB"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#92D050"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">M, GA, and F (III)</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#8EA9DB"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#92D050"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">M, GA, GLA, and F (IV)</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#203764"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#92D050"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">M, GA, and GLA (V)</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#8EA9DB"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#92D050"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">M, GA, GLA, and F (VI)</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#FF0000"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#8EA9DB"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#92D050"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">M, GA, and F(VII)</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#203764"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#92D050"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">GLA and F(VIII)</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#757171"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#92D050"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">GA and GLA (IX)</entry>
<entry colname="col2" tint="#757171"/>
<entry colname="col3" tint="#203764"/>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF8B8B"/>
<entry colname="col5" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col6" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col7" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col8" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col9" tint="#92D050"/>
<entry colname="col10" tint="#92D050"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup cols="4" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
<colspec align="left" colname="col1" colnum="1"/>
<colspec align="left" colname="col2" colnum="2"/>
<colspec align="left" colname="col3" colnum="3"/>
<colspec align="left" colname="col4" colnum="4"/>
<thead valign="bottom">
<row rowsep="1">
<entry colname="col1" align="left">Process output</entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left">Comparison to</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left">Range</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left">Legend color</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry colname="col1" morerows="4">Peak VCD</entry>
<entry colname="col2" morerows="4">Control</entry>
<entry colname="col3">± 10%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050">Green</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3"><b>+15%</b></entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF8B8B"><b>Light red</b></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">Beyond +15%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF0000">Intense red</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">−15%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#8EAADB">Light blue</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">Beyond −15%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#002060">Intense blue</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" morerows="2">Viability</entry>
<entry colname="col2" morerows="2">Control</entry>
<entry colname="col3">± 10%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050">Green</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">−15%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#8EAADB">Light blue</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">Beyond −15%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#002060">Intense blue</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" morerows="4">Harvest ammonia, harvest osmolality, harvest titer</entry>
<entry colname="col2" morerows="4">Control</entry>
<entry colname="col3">± 20%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050">Green</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">+30%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF8B8B"><b>Light red</b></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">Beyond +30%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF0000">Intense red</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">−30%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#8EAADB">Light blue</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">Beyond −30%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#002060">Intense blue</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" morerows="2">Harvest lactate</entry>
<entry colname="col2" morerows="2">Control</entry>
<entry colname="col3">&amp;lt; 0.5 g/L</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050">Green</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">&amp;gt; 0.5 and &amp;lt;1.0 g/L</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF8B8B"><b>Light red</b></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">&amp;gt; 1.0 g/L</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF0000">Intense red</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" morerows="2">% total fucose</entry>
<entry colname="col2" morerows="2">Innovator</entry>
<entry colname="col3">± 10%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050">Green</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">+ 15%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF8B8B"><b>Light red</b></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">Beyond +15%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF0000">Intense red</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" morerows="3">% HM</entry>
<entry colname="col2" morerows="3">Innovator</entry>
<entry colname="col3">90%–150%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050">Green</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">150%–200%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF8B8B"><b>Light red</b></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">&amp;gt; 200%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF0000">Intense red</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">&amp;lt; 90%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#002060">Intense blue</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" morerows="2">% ADCC activity</entry>
<entry colname="col2" morerows="2">Innovator</entry>
<entry colname="col3">&amp;gt; 80%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#92D050">Green</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">&amp;lt; 80%</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#FF0000">Red</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col3">Not tested</entry>
<entry colname="col4" tint="#A6A6A6">Gray</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<noteGroup xml:id="btpr3176-ntgp-0003">
<note xml:id="btpr3176-note-0003" numbered="no">
<p>Abbreviations: ADCC, antibody‐dependent cell‐mediated cytotoxicity; HM, high‐mannose.</p>
</note>
</noteGroup>
</tabular>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0011">
<title type="main">Impact of osmolality</title>
<p>One of the factors tested to increase the HM species in the biosimilar mAb was osmolality. Reports have shown that high osmolality in a culture have resulted in increased HM species.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0048"><sup>48</sup></link> In this study, the impact of osmolality on increasing HM species was tested by either feeding a daily bolus of sodium chloride solution (3 M NaCl) gradually in equal increments from day 3 onwards up to day 15 to increase osmolality or by feeding a bolus of 3 M NaCl solution on day 8 prior to temperature shift. The level tested for the gradual osmolality increase was 200 mOsm/kg over the remaining culture duration (up to day 15) and levels tested for the step increase in osmolality were 100 and 200 mOsm/kg. Overall, HM glycoforms for all increased osmolality conditions were observed to be higher than the control process, which was consistent with the literature (Table <link href="#btpr3176-tbl-0002">2</link>). HM levels ranged from 100% to 140% of the innovator mAb levels for the three osmolality conditions tested. The condition with the largest step increase in osmolality (200 mOsm/kg) had the highest increase in HM species. Interestingly, the HM levels for the 100 mOsm/kg step increase were comparable to the gradual increase by 200 mOsm/kg. The osmolality conditions had minimal impact on VCD, which was observed to be consistent with the control. However, the change in osmolality negatively impacted culture viability at harvest. Culture viability correlated with the manner of change in osmolality (gradual vs. bolus) and the magnitude of osmolality increase (100 vs. 200 mOsm/kg). Final harvest viability on day 16 for the gradual increase by 200 mOsm/kg was 71% compared to 54% for the bolus increase by 200 mOsm/kg. Bolus increase by 100 mOsm/kg resulted in harvest viability of 66%. Waste metabolites, such as lactate, were comparable across different conditions to the control. However, peak lactate was observed on day 3, prior to the perturbations in osmolality initiated on day 3 or 8. The high osmolality conditions resulted in moderately higher lactate (0.5–0.8 g/L) at harvest compared to the control (0.2 g/L). Similarly, osmolality increase resulted in elevated ammonia (9.3–11.4 mM) at harvest compared to the control (7.5 mM). The increase in ammonia levels with an increase in osmolality has been postulated as the primary factor in the effect of osmolality on HM levels as ammonia levels are known to alter intracellular pH and consequently the activity of pH sensitive glycosyltransferases.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0048"><sup>48</sup></link> In general, ammonia levels can affect glycosylation pathways in multiple ways,<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0045 #btpr3176-bib-0047 #btpr3176-bib-0068 #btpr3176-bib-0069 #btpr3176-bib-0070"><sup>45,47,68–70</sup></link> and the observed data are consistent with the hypothesis that effect of osmolality is related to its effect on ammonia levels. An increase in osmolality resulted in a decrease in product concentration compared to the control. Final titer was 25%, 41%, and 32% lower compared to the control for bolus increase by 100 mOsm/kg, bolus increase by 200 mOsm/kg, and gradual increase by 200 mOsm/kg, respectively. The decrease in titer was due to the decrease in cell specific productivity. Due to the impact of osmolality on viability and product concentration, this condition was not chosen for further optimization.</p>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0012">
<title type="main">Impact of intracellular <fc>pH</fc> modulation</title>
<p>In the shake flask screening study, intracellular pH was altered to increase HM levels by the increase of cell culture ammonia concentration. Two approaches were tested. The first approach included the direct addition of NH<sub>4</sub>Cl on day 8 prior to temperature shift at two concentrations: 7.5 mM and 15 mM. The second approach included doubling the initial glutamine concentration in the basal medium from 4 to 8 mM to indirectly increase the ammonia concentration in the cell culture (see <link href="#btpr3176-supitem-0001">Data S1</link> for data and outputs from this study). Although the NH<sub>4</sub>Cl additions at both concentrations and the high glutamine condition resulted in increases in HM species compared to the control, the levels ranged from 65% to 85% of the innovator mAb, which were lower than the required increase needed to improve ADCC activity. NH<sub>4</sub>Cl addition at both concentrations had minimal impact on VCD and viability compared to the control condition. However, the increase in glutamine resulted in a slight increase in VCD compared to the control, while viability was comparable to the control. Initial lactate build‐up and peak lactate concentration for these conditions were comparable to the control, primarily because peak lactate was observed before the addition of NH<sub>4</sub>Cl on day 8. The lactate concentration at harvest was also comparable to the control (approximately 0.2 g/L) for all conditions tested except the condition with 15 mM addition of NH<sub>4</sub>Cl, which had a lactate concentration of 1 g/L. As expected, ammonia concentrations at harvest were high for these conditions and directly correlated with the amount of NH<sub>4</sub>Cl added: 14.5 mM for the 7.5 mM NH<sub>4</sub>Cl condition and 22.4 mM for the 15 mM NH<sub>4</sub>Cl condition. In contrast, the ammonia concentration at harvest for the high glutamine condition (8.5 mM) was similar to the control condition (7.5 mM). Titers were impacted by the amount of NH<sub>4</sub>Cl added. A decrease of approximately 14%–16% in titer was observed for conditions with added NH<sub>4</sub>Cl as compared to the control, irrespective of the NH<sub>4</sub>Cl concentrations added. The high glutamine condition resulted in a moderate titer increase of 9% compared to the control. However, due to lower levels of HM glycoforms observed compared to the innovator mAb, these conditions were not chosen for further optimization.</p>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0013">
<title type="main">Impact of small molecule ionophore (monensin)</title>
<p>Another factor tested to increase HM species content involved the addition of monensin, a small molecule ionophore, which has been reported to increase <i>N</i>‐glycan HM levels without significant impact on cell culture process performance.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0062"><sup>62</sup></link> The mechanism by which monensin acts is not fully understood, though it is believed that as a sodium–hydrogen ionophore it causes pH neutralization in Golgi and also inhibits the transport of glycosylated protein to the Golgi.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0036 #btpr3176-bib-0062"><sup>36,62</sup></link> In the shake flask study, a stock solution of monensin, prepared in methanol, was added on day 8 at two target concentrations: 100 and 500 nM. Consistent with published observations,<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0007 #btpr3176-bib-0028 #btpr3176-bib-0062"><sup>7,28,62</sup></link> monensin addition significantly increased the level of HM species in the biosimilar mAb. Monensin addition of 100 or 500 nM resulted in HM species levels of 280% and 200% relative to the innovator mAb, respectively (Table <link href="#btpr3176-tbl-0002">2</link>). However, the addition of monensin resulted in significant declines in viability at both concentrations tested. By day 14, the culture viabilities for monensin conditions were ≤50% and both cultures were harvested. Consistent with the disruption in growth, waste metabolites, such as lactate and ammonia, increased significantly after the addition of monensin. Cells switched from lactate consumption metabolism to lactate production metabolism resulting in 1.6–1.7 g/L of lactate at harvest on day 14 for both concentrations. Similarly, increased production of ammonia was observed after the introduction of monensin. The impact of monensin on growth and viability translated to lower titer. Titer decreased by 40%–50% for conditions with monensin compared to the control. These results contradict the report<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0062"><sup>62</sup></link> that monensin does not impact cell culture process performance. Although the addition of monensin significantly increased HM levels, the condition was not chosen for further optimization due to the negative impact on cell growth and metabolism.</p>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0014">
<title type="main">Impact of alternate feed system</title>
<p>An alternative feed system for the process was tested to observe the impact of changing feeds on the glycosylation pattern, particularly the effect on HM species. In the shake flask study, the ActiCHO feed system (Feed A and Feed B) was compared to the feed system used for the control process consisting of a proprietary feed and a cystine‐tyrosine feed. The ActiCHO feed system was chosen based on historical data from the media screening studies conducted during development where it was one of the top performers with respect to titer and productivity (data not shown). The ActiCHO feed system was also expected to result in differences in glucose metabolism and culture pH compared to the control process. In addition, the cumulative feed added differed between the two conditions. The ActiCHO feed system had lower cumulative feeds added (45.5%) compared to the control condition (52%). The addition of ActiCHO feeds to the culture resulted in increased HM species compared to the control (Table <link href="#btpr3176-tbl-0002">2</link>). The HM levels observed for ActiCHO feeds were 115% of the innovator mAb. The increase in HM levels was potentially due to a cumulative effect of higher osmolality and accumulation of lactate (and its impact on external culture pH) when compared to the control cultures. The addition of ActiCHO feeds had minimal impact on VCD and viability profiles. High lactate build‐up was observed for flasks with ActiCHO feeds added. Lactate was 1.9 g/L at harvest, which was much higher than the 0.2 g/L of lactate observed at harvest for the control. Ammonia concentration in the ActiCHO condition was comparable to the control condition. Due to significant efforts required to optimize the process with new feeds, specifically with respect to reducing waste accumulation, the ActiCHO feed system was not chosen for further optimization.</p>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0015">
<title type="main">Impact of sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds</title>
<p>Lastly, one of the major factors tested to increase the HM levels in the biosimilar mAb was the addition of alternate sugars and amino sugars in feed medium. In the shake flask study, nine different combinations of mannose, fructose, glucosamine, and galactosamine were supplemented at various concentrations to the existing proprietary feeds based on a definitive screening DOE (Table <link href="#btpr3176-tbl-0003">3</link>). The use of fructose and mannose instead of glucose as the carbon source have also been reported as means to increase HM.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0043 #btpr3176-bib-0052 #btpr3176-bib-0053"><sup>43,52,53</sup></link> All the sugars (fructose, glucose and mannose) present in the media are metabolized in the cells through the glycolysis pathway. Fructose, like glucose, enters the pathway directly as fructose 6‐phosphate and mannose enters glycolysis by first being converted to mannose 6‐phosphate and then isomerized to produce fructose 6‐phosphate. The increase in HM levels observed when using mannose as a carbon source maybe related to its direct effect or its intermediates on UDP‐GlcNAc biosynthesis (by enzyme inhibition), its transportation, or GnT‐I turnover rate. The use of fructose instead of glucose is believed to increase HM levels due to the slower transport of fructose into the cell via glucose transporters, which results in a reduced rate of formation of intermediates for energy production and glycan precursors.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0071"><sup>71</sup></link> The reduction in uptake rate is likely to affect the availability of other constituent nucleotide sugars involved in glycan synthesis. Finally, glucosamine and galactosamine additions may modulate HM levels by increasing the intracellular levels of nucleotide activated sugars, which can increase the level of nucleotide‐sugar donors or act as enzyme inhibitors in the Golgi.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0047 #btpr3176-bib-0053 #btpr3176-bib-0070 #btpr3176-bib-0072 #btpr3176-bib-0073 #btpr3176-bib-0074"><sup>47,53,70,72–74</sup></link></p>
<tabular xml:id="btpr3176-tbl-0003">
<label>3</label>
<titleGroup>
<title type="tabularName">TABLE</title>
<title type="main">Concentrations listed for the different combinations of sugar and amino sugars (mannose, fructose, glucosamine, and galactosamine) that were supplemented to the existing proprietary feeds for the shake flask screening study and the 3‐L bioreactor study</title>
</titleGroup>
<table rowsep="0" colsep="1" pgwide="1" frame="topbot">
<tgroup cols="5">
<colspec align="left" colname="col1" colnum="1"/>
<colspec align="char" colname="col2" colnum="2" char="."/>
<colspec align="char" colname="col3" colnum="3" char="."/>
<colspec align="char" colname="col4" colnum="4" char="."/>
<colspec align="char" colname="col5" colnum="5" char="."/>
<thead valign="bottom">
<row rowsep="1">
<entry colname="col1" align="left" rowsep="1" morerows="1">Condition</entry>
<entry align="left" rowsep="1" namest="col2" nameend="col5">Supplemented concentration</entry>
</row>
<row rowsep="1">
<entry colname="col2" align="left">Mannose (g/L)</entry>
<entry colname="col3" align="left">Glucosamine (g/L)</entry>
<entry colname="col4" align="left">Galactosamine (g/L)</entry>
<entry colname="col5" align="left">Fructose (g/L)</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col5">Shake Flask Study</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Mannose (I)</entry>
<entry colname="col2">30</entry>
<entry colname="col3">0</entry>
<entry colname="col4">0</entry>
<entry colname="col5">0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Glucosamine, fructose (II)</entry>
<entry colname="col2">0</entry>
<entry colname="col3">1</entry>
<entry colname="col4">0</entry>
<entry colname="col5">30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Mannose, glucosamine, fructose (III)</entry>
<entry colname="col2">30</entry>
<entry colname="col3">2</entry>
<entry colname="col4">0</entry>
<entry colname="col5">15</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Mannose, glucosamine, Galactosamine, fructose (IV)</entry>
<entry colname="col2">15</entry>
<entry colname="col3">2</entry>
<entry colname="col4">2</entry>
<entry colname="col5">30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Mannose, glucosamine, galactosamine (V)</entry>
<entry colname="col2">30</entry>
<entry colname="col3">1</entry>
<entry colname="col4">2</entry>
<entry colname="col5">0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Mannose, glucosamine, Galactosamine, fructose (VI)</entry>
<entry colname="col2">15</entry>
<entry colname="col3">1</entry>
<entry colname="col4">1</entry>
<entry colname="col5">15</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Mannose, glucosamine, fructose (VII)</entry>
<entry colname="col2">30</entry>
<entry colname="col3">0</entry>
<entry colname="col4">1</entry>
<entry colname="col5">30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Galactosamine, fructose (VIII)</entry>
<entry colname="col2">0</entry>
<entry colname="col3">0</entry>
<entry colname="col4">2</entry>
<entry colname="col5">15</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Glucosamine, galactosamine (IX)</entry>
<entry colname="col2">0</entry>
<entry colname="col3">2</entry>
<entry colname="col4">1</entry>
<entry colname="col5">0</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="col1" nameend="col5">3‐L study</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1" indentLevel="1">Mannose, glucosamine, galactosamine</entry>
<entry colname="col2">30</entry>
<entry colname="col3">2.5</entry>
<entry colname="col4">1</entry>
<entry colname="col5">0</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tabular>
<p>Overall, a significant increase in HM content compared to the control condition was observed for the various sugar and amino sugar supplemented feed conditions (Table <link href="#btpr3176-tbl-0002">2</link>). In reference to the innovator mAb, HM levels observed for the sugar and amino sugar supplemented conditions ranged between 72% and 174%. Specifically, conditions that involved feeds supplemented with the addition of mannose, glucosamine, and galactosamine consistently resulted in higher HM levels (120%–150% relative to the innovator mAb). VCD was consistent with the control for all conditions with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds. However, lower viability was observed for conditions with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds compared to the control. The viabilities of the test conditions ranged between 63% and 74%, which were lower than the harvest viability of 80% observed for the control condition. The peak lactate and lactate concentration at harvest were comparable to the control process. Similarly, ammonia profiles for the test conditions were consistent with ammonia profiles for the control process. Titer was not impacted by the different sugar and amino sugar supplemented feed conditions. Titer for the conditions tested ranged between 4.3 and 5.5 g/L, which was comparable to the 4.9 g/L obtained for the control process. It has been observed in another study that the accumulation of nucleotide precursors when using alternate sugars like mannose resulted in diminished production of activated nucleotide sugars, which suggested changes to the energy metabolism of the cells and reduced nucleic acid synthesis.<link href="#btpr3176-bib-0041"><sup>41</sup></link> However, similar to this study, no significant differences in viable cell densities were observed.</p>
<p>Figure <link href="#btpr3176-fig-0003">3</link> shows the ADCC activity and HM levels for the best conditions tested in the shake flask screening study. As mentioned earlier, HM levels for the conditions tested ranged from 90% to 280% relative to the innovator mAb. ADCC activities for the conditions tested were observed to be between 70% and 110% compared to the innovator mAb. Among these various conditions tested in the screening study, the condition with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds with a combination of mannose, glucosamine, and galactosamine was chosen for further scale‐up and optimization (Condition V). This was mainly due to the fact that they provided the most optimal and least disruptive path to mitigate the lower ADCC activity in the biosimilar mAb (Table <link href="#btpr3176-tbl-0002">2</link> and Figure <link href="#btpr3176-fig-0003">3</link>).</p>
<figure xml:id="btpr3176-fig-0003">
<label>3</label>
<title type="figureName">FIGURE</title>
<mediaResourceGroup>
<mediaResource alt="image" href="urn:x-wiley:87567938:media:btpr3176:btpr3176-fig-0003"/>



</mediaResourceGroup>
<caption>ADCC activity and HM levels for the conditions tested in the shake flask screening study. ~ Indicates the HM level for monensin (100 nM) condition was higher than 160% as indicated on the graph (actual value: 283%). The composition and concentrations of the various sugar and/or amino sugar supplemented feeds are detailed in Table <link href="#btpr3176-tbl-0003">3</link>. The error bars represent 1 standard deviation for ADCC activity and HM levels in control and ActiCHO feed conditions. ADCC, antibody‐dependent cell‐mediated cytotoxicity; HM, high‐mannose</caption>
</figure>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0016">
<title type="main">Process optimization and scale‐up in <fc>3‐L</fc> bench‐scale bioreactors</title>
<p>A response surface DOE in an ambr250 high throughput bioreactor system was used to optimize mannose, glucosamine, and galactosamine concentrations in feed medium, the factors that were identified to be most effective and practical to implement for scale‐up from the shake flask screening study (data not shown). While cell growth, key metabolites, and titer profiles for the conditions tested in the ambr250 study were comparable to the control, the absolute levels of HM species in the biosimilar mAb were much lower than the target required to match the innovator mAb. The percent HM for all the conditions tested at the ambr250 scale, including control conditions, ranged from 23% to 63% relative to the innovator mAb. In contrast, the levels of HM species observed among the sugar and amino sugar supplemented conditions tested in the shake flask screening study ranged between 72% and 154% relative to the innovator mAb. Further troubleshooting identified osmolality and total feed addition as the root causes for the differences in HM levels observed between the shake flasks and ambr250 bioreactors (data in Figures <link href="#btpr3176-supitem-0001">S1–S10</link>). The pH profiles may also have differed between the two scales; however, this could not be quantified as shake flask pH was not measured by offline methods. Based on these observations, it was hypothesized that a secondary interaction of sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds along with osmolality were necessary to obtain the absolute increase in HM species needed to match the innovator mAb.</p>
<p>To examine the interaction between osmolality and sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds and its impact on the levels of HM species in the biosimilar mAb, a study was conducted using four 3‐L bioreactors, which were considered as the representative model for large‐scale bioreactors (<link href="#btpr3176-supitem-0001">Figure S9</link>). Moreover, the study was designed to test the impact of increased cumulative feed addition. The mannose, glucosamine and galactosamine concentrations of the sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds was further adjusted based on the results obtained from the response surface DOE study conducted in ambr250 bioreactor system (Table <link href="#btpr3176-tbl-0003">3</link>). As shown in Table <link href="#btpr3176-tbl-0004">4</link>, the four conditions tested in the 3‐L scale included the following: control condition without sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds (B01), sugar and amino sugar supplemented feed condition with control feed scheme (B02), sugar and amino sugar supplemented feed condition with adjusted feed scheme (B03), and sugar and amino sugar supplemented feed condition with adjusted feed scheme and NaCl addition to increase osmolality (B04). As expected, incremental differences in final osmolality were observed across the conditions tested. The control condition had the lowest final osmolality (442 mOsm/kg), followed by the condition with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds with control feed scheme (491 mOsm/kg), and the condition with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds with adjusted feed scheme (514 mOsm/kg). The condition with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds with adjusted feed scheme and NaCl addition had the highest osmolality (560 mOsm/kg). The final osmolality of the conditions directly correlated with the levels of HM species, that is, the higher the osmolality, the higher the observed level of mannose species (Figure <link href="#btpr3176-fig-0004">4</link>). The condition with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds with adjusted feed scheme and increased osmolality (B04) had HM levels at 95% relative to the innovator mAb, which was significantly higher than the control condition at 44% relative to the innovator mAb. Similarly, the condition with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds with control feed scheme (B02) and the condition with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds with adjusted feed scheme (B03) had HM levels at 68% and 88% relative to the innovator mAb, respectively. As shown in Figure <link href="#btpr3176-fig-0005">5</link>, ADCC activity directly correlated with increase in osmolality. A 20% increase in ADCC activity relative to the ADCC activity for the control condition was observed for the condition using sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds with control feed scheme (B02). For conditions with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds with adjusted feed scheme (B03) and sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds with adjusted feed scheme and increased osmolality (B04), ADCC activity increased by 35% and 45%, respectively, compared to the control condition. The results from the 3‐L study confirmed the hypothesis of a synergistic impact of sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds and osmolality on the levels of HM in the biosimilar mAb.</p>
<tabular xml:id="btpr3176-tbl-0004">
<label>4</label>
<titleGroup>
<title type="tabularName">TABLE</title>
<title type="main">Conditions investigated in the 3‐L bioreactor study to test the impact of osmolality on HM levels</title>
</titleGroup>
<table rowsep="0" colsep="1" pgwide="1" frame="topbot">
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec align="left" colname="col1" colnum="1"/>
<colspec align="left" colname="col2" colnum="2"/>
<thead valign="bottom">
<row rowsep="1">
<entry colname="col1" align="left">Bioreactor number</entry>
<entry colname="col2" align="left">Test condition</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry colname="col1">B01</entry>
<entry colname="col2">Control feeding scheme.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1">B02</entry>
<entry colname="col2">Control feeding scheme with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1">B03</entry>
<entry colname="col2">Adjusted feeding scheme with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colname="col1">B04</entry>
<entry colname="col2">Adjusted feeding scheme with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds and osmolality increase by 3 M NaCl addition.</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<noteGroup xml:id="btpr3176-ntgp-0004">
<note xml:id="btpr3176-note-0004" numbered="no">
<p><i>Note</i>: Control feed scheme added 52% of proprietary feed and 5.2% of cystine‐ tyrosine based feed, while the adjusted feed scheme added 56% of proprietary feed and 5.6% of cystine tyrosine‐based feed. The concentrations of sugar and amino sugar added to the proprietary feed are listed in Table <link href="#btpr3176-tbl-0003">3</link>.</p>
</note>
<note xml:id="btpr3176-note-0005" numbered="no">
<p>Abbreviation: HM, high‐mannose.</p>
</note>
</noteGroup>
</tabular>
<figure xml:id="btpr3176-fig-0004">
<label>4</label>
<title type="figureName">FIGURE</title>
<mediaResourceGroup>
<mediaResource alt="image" href="urn:x-wiley:87567938:media:btpr3176:btpr3176-fig-0004"/>



</mediaResourceGroup>
<caption>Correlation between osmolality and relative change in HM compared to the 3‐L bioreactor control for the conditions tested in the 3‐L bioreactor study. (B01, control; B02, control with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds; B03, control with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds and adjusted feeding scheme; B04, control with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds and adjusted feeding scheme with NaCl addition). HM, high‐mannose</caption>
</figure>
<figure xml:id="btpr3176-fig-0005">
<label>5</label>
<title type="figureName">FIGURE</title>
<mediaResourceGroup>
<mediaResource alt="image" href="urn:x-wiley:87567938:media:btpr3176:btpr3176-fig-0005"/>



</mediaResourceGroup>
<caption>Correlation between osmolality and ADCC activity for the conditions tested in the 3‐L bioreactor study. (B01, control; B02, control with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds; B03, control with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds and adjusted feeding scheme; B04, control with sugar and amino sugar supplemented feeds and adjusted feeding scheme with NaCl addition). ADCC, antibody‐dependent cell‐mediated cytotoxicity</caption>
</figure>
</section>
</section>
<section xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0017">
<title type="main">CONCLUSION</title>
<p>It is well established in the literature that extracellular conditions affect production and quality of therapeutic antibodies including their post‐translational modifications. To our knowledge, this study is one of the first studies to present a comprehensive parallel evaluation of multiple factors known to impact regulation and control of HM species in a biosimilar mAb. Specifically, this study demonstrates the effects of several process parameters that result in an increase in HM species via disruption of ER and Golgi environments and modulation of key glycosylation related enzyme activities. Several cell culture process related factors known to modulate the HM content of <i>N</i>‐glycans, such as osmolality, NH<sub>4</sub>Cl addition, glutamine concentration, monensin addition, and the addition of alternate sugars and amino sugars to the feed medium, are assessed in this study.</p>
<p>The addition of alternate sugars and amino sugars to feed medium was identified as the preferred method to increase levels of HM species with minimal disruptions to process performance or other product quality attributes. However, further in‐depth studies are necessary to elucidate the mechanism by which sugars and amino sugars affect production of HM species and other glycoforms. Additionally, this article highlights the use of definitive screening designs, like the one utilized in the shake flask screening study, to optimize sugar and amino sugar supplementation to alter glycosylation.</p>
<p>Although the choice of the expression system and the control of the production parameters in the process development phases are instrumental to ensure the production of glycoproteins with consistent structures, this study elucidated the importance of understanding small changes in process parameters and their impacts on product quality. A modest difference in osmolality (30–70 mOsm/kg) observed during the scale‐up of the cell culture process was involved in a secondary interaction to attain consistently HM levels and in turn was observed to significantly regulate the ADCC activity of the antibody. This highlights the need for a control strategy early in process development to characterize the effect of glycan composition on effector functions as well as a comprehensive understanding of process parameters to build an operating space to produce antibodies with consistent glycan profiles.</p>
<p>Product quality attributes, such as glycosylation, play a critical role in pharmacokinetic and in vivo efficacy of therapeutic antibodies. Furthermore, a consistent product quality profile is critical to ensure regulatory success, especially for a biosimilar product. The extensive discussion of background literature and our evaluation of cell culture factors on glycosylation modulation is an added benefit that can be utilized by peers for the modulation of HM species in therapeutic antibodies.</p>
</section>
<section type="acknowledgments" xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0018" numbered="no">
<title type="main">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title>
<p>The authors would like to thank the clients, Gene Techno Science Co. and Itochu Chemical Frontier Corporation, for their support to conduct the studies at KBI. The authors would like to thank Venkata Tayi for providing technical inputs during the experiment design discussions and Dustin Costello, Srivatsan Gopalakrishnan, Jaspreet Notey and Mamudou Bah with lab execution of the experiments. The authors would like to acknowledge Derek Ryan, Melanie Priestman and Jimmy Smedley for analytical support and conducting ADCC assays related to this article. The authors would like to sincerely thank Teri Aldrich for her support with review of the article and Leah Farmer for her assistance with the glycosylation figure.</p>
</section>
<section type="conflictOfInterest" xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0019" numbered="no">
<title type="main">CONFLICT OF INTEREST</title>
<p>The authors have no conflict of interest, financial or otherwise, related to the work presented in the manuscript.</p>
</section>
<section type="openResearch" numbered="no" xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0020">
<section type="dataAvailability" numbered="no" xml:id="btpr3176-sec-0021">
<title type="main">DATA AVAILABILITY STATEMENT</title>
<p>The data that support the findings of this study are available on request from the corresponding author. The data are not publicly available due to privacy or ethical restrictions.</p>
</section>
</section>
<bibliography xml:id="btpr3176-bibl-0001" style="numbered" cited="yes">
<title type="main">REFERENCES</title>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0001"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0001"><author><familyName>Walsh</familyName> <givenNames>G</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Biopharmaceutical benchmarks 2018</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Nat Biotechnol</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2018">2018</pubYear>;<vol>36</vol>(<issue>12</issue>):<pageFirst>1136</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1145</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0002"><citation type="other" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0002"><author><familyName>Ahmad</familyName> <givenNames>A‐S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Olech</familyName> <givenNames>E</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>McClellan</familyName> <givenNames>JE</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Kirchhoff</familyName> <givenNames>CF</givenNames></author>. <otherTitle>Development of biosimilars</otherTitle>. Paper presented at: Seminars in arthritis and rheumatism, <pubYear year="2016">2016</pubYear>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0003"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0003"><author><familyName>Sokolov</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Ritscher</familyName> <givenNames>J</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>MacKinnon</familyName> <givenNames>N</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Robust factor selection in early cell culture process development for the production of a biosimilar monoclonal antibody</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Prog</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2017">2017</pubYear>;<vol>33</vol>(<issue>1</issue>):<pageFirst>181</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>191</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0004"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0004"><author><familyName>Ponniah</familyName> <givenNames>G</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Nowak</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Gonzalez</familyName> <givenNames>N</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Miano</familyName> <givenNames>D</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Liu</familyName> <givenNames>H</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Detection and quantitation of low abundance oligosaccharides in recombinant monoclonal antibodies</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Anal Chem</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2015">2015</pubYear>;<vol>87</vol>(<issue>5</issue>):<pageFirst>2718</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>2726</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0005"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0005"><author><familyName>Jefferis</familyName> <givenNames>R</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Posttranslational modifications and the immunogenicity of biotherapeutics</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>J Immunol Res</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2016">2016</pubYear>;<vol>2016</vol>:<eLocator>5358272</eLocator>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0006"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0006"><author><familyName>Jefferis</familyName> <givenNames>R</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Glycosylation as a strategy to improve antibody‐based therapeutics</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Nat Rev Drug Discov</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2009">2009</pubYear>;<vol>8</vol>(<issue>3</issue>):<pageFirst>226</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>234</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0007"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0007"><author><familyName>Ehret</familyName> <givenNames>J</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Zimmermann</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Eichhorn</familyName> <givenNames>T</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Zimmer</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Impact of cell culture media additives on IgG glycosylation produced in Chinese hamster ovary cells</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2019">2019</pubYear>;<vol>116</vol>(<issue>4</issue>):<pageFirst>816</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>830</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0008"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0008"><author><familyName>Higel</familyName> <givenNames>F</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Seidl</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Sorgel</familyName> <givenNames>F</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Friess</familyName> <givenNames>W</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>N‐glycosylation heterogeneity and the influence on structure, function and pharmacokinetics of monoclonal antibodies and fc fusion proteins</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Eur J Pharm Biopharm</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2016">2016</pubYear>;<vol>100</vol>:<pageFirst>94</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>100</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0009"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0009"><author><familyName>Liu</familyName> <givenNames>L</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Antibody glycosylation and its impact on the pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of monoclonal antibodies and fc‐fusion proteins</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>J Pharm Sci</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2015">2015</pubYear>;<vol>104</vol>(<issue>6</issue>):<pageFirst>1866</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1884</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0010"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0010"><author><familyName>Ferrara</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Grau</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Jäger</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Unique carbohydrate–carbohydrate interactions are required for high affinity binding between FcγRIII and antibodies lacking core fucose</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Proc Natl Acad Sci</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2011">2011</pubYear>;<vol>108</vol>(<issue>31</issue>):<eLocator>12669‐12674</eLocator>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0011"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0011"><author><familyName>Shinkawa</familyName> <givenNames>T</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Nakamura</familyName> <givenNames>K</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Yamane</familyName> <givenNames>N</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>The absence of fucose but not the presence of galactose or bisecting N‐acetylglucosamine of human IgG1 complex‐type oligosaccharides shows the critical role of enhancing antibody‐dependent cellular cytotoxicity</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>J Biol Chem</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2003">2003</pubYear>;<vol>278</vol>(<issue>5</issue>):<pageFirst>3466</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>3473</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0012"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0012"><author><familyName>Peipp</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Lammerts van Bueren</familyName> <givenNames>JJ</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Schneider‐Merck</familyName> <givenNames>T</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Antibody fucosylation differentially impacts cytotoxicity mediated by NK and PMN effector cells</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Blood</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2008">2008</pubYear>;<vol>112</vol>(<issue>6</issue>):<pageFirst>2390</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>2399</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0013"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0013"><author><familyName>Shoji‐Hosaka</familyName> <givenNames>E</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Kobayashi</familyName> <givenNames>Y</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Wakitani</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Enhanced fc‐dependent cellular cytotoxicity of fc fusion proteins derived from TNF receptor II and LFA‐3 by fucose removal from Asn‐linked oligosaccharides</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>J Biochem</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2006">2006</pubYear>;<vol>140</vol>(<issue>6</issue>):<pageFirst>777</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>783</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0014"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0014"><author><familyName>Shields</familyName> <givenNames>RL</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Lai</familyName> <givenNames>J</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Keck</familyName> <givenNames>R</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Lack of fucose on human IgG1 N‐linked oligosaccharide improves binding to human Fcgamma RIII and antibody‐dependent cellular toxicity</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>J Biol Chem</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2002">2002</pubYear>;<vol>277</vol>(<issue>30</issue>):<eLocator>26733‐26740</eLocator>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0015"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0015"><author><familyName>Mori</familyName> <givenNames>K</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Iida</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Yamane‐Ohnuki</familyName> <givenNames>N</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Non‐fucosylated therapeutic antibodies: the next generation of therapeutic antibodies</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Cytotechnology</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2007">2007</pubYear>;<vol>55</vol>(<issue>2‐3</issue>):<pageFirst>109</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>114</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0016"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0016"><author><familyName>Elliott</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Egrie</familyName> <givenNames>J</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Browne</familyName> <givenNames>J</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Control of rHuEPO biological activity: the role of carbohydrate</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Exp Hematol</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2004">2004</pubYear>;<vol>32</vol>(<issue>12</issue>):<pageFirst>1146</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1155</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0017"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0017"><author><familyName>Quast</familyName> <givenNames>I</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Keller</familyName> <givenNames>CW</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Maurer</familyName> <givenNames>MA</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Sialylation of IgG fc domain impairs complement‐dependent cytotoxicity</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>J Clin Invest</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2015">2015</pubYear>;<vol>125</vol>(<issue>11</issue>):<pageFirst>4160</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>4170</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0018"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0018"><author><familyName>Chen</familyName> <givenNames>X</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Liu</familyName> <givenNames>J</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Liu</familyName> <givenNames>X</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Fan</familyName> <givenNames>L</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Zhao</familyName> <givenNames>L</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Tan</familyName> <givenNames>W‐S</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Characterization and minimization of sialic acid degradation in an fc‐fusion protein‐producing CHO cell bioprocess</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Process Biochem</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2018">2018</pubYear>;<vol>73</vol>:<pageFirst>162</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>169</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0019"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0019"><author><familyName>Lin</familyName> <givenNames>CW</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Tsai</familyName> <givenNames>MH</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Li</familyName> <givenNames>ST</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>A common glycan structure on immunoglobulin G for enhancement of effector functions</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2015">2015</pubYear>;<vol>112</vol>(<issue>34</issue>):<eLocator>10611‐10616</eLocator>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0020"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0020"><author><familyName>Raju</familyName> <givenNames>TS</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Lang</familyName> <givenNames>SE</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Diversity in structure and functions of antibody sialylation in the fc</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Curr Opin Biotechnol</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2014">2014</pubYear>;<vol>30</vol>:<pageFirst>147</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>152</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0021"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0021"><author><familyName>Raju</familyName> <givenNames>TS</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Jordan</familyName> <givenNames>RE</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Galactosylation variations in marketed therapeutic antibodies</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>MAbs</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2012">2012</pubYear>;<vol>4</vol>(<issue>3</issue>):<pageFirst>385</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>391</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0022"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0022"><author><familyName>Reusch</familyName> <givenNames>D</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Tejada</familyName> <givenNames>ML</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Fc glycans of therapeutic antibodies as critical quality attributes</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Glycobiology</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2015">2015</pubYear>;<vol>25</vol>(<issue>12</issue>):<pageFirst>1325</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1334</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0023"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0023"><author><familyName>Chung</familyName> <givenNames>CY</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Wang</familyName> <givenNames>Q</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Yang</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Combinatorial genome and protein engineering yields monoclonal antibodies with hypergalactosylation from CHO cells</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2017">2017</pubYear>;<vol>114</vol>(<issue>12</issue>):<pageFirst>2848</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>2856</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0024"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0024"><author><familyName>Mastrangeli</familyName> <givenNames>R</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Audino</familyName> <givenNames>MC</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Palinsky</familyName> <givenNames>W</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Broly</familyName> <givenNames>H</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Bierau</familyName> <givenNames>H</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>The formidable challenge of controlling high mannose‐type N‐Glycans in therapeutic mAbs</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Trends Biotechnol</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2020">2020</pubYear>;<vol>38</vol>(<issue>10</issue>):<pageFirst>1154</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1168</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0025"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0025"><author><familyName>Yu</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Brown</familyName> <givenNames>D</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Reed</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Production, characterization, and pharmacokinetic properties of antibodies with N‐linked mannose‐5 glycans</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>MAbs</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2012">2012</pubYear>;<vol>4</vol>(<issue>4</issue>):<pageFirst>475</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>487</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0026"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0026"><author><familyName>Zhong</familyName> <givenNames>X</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Cooley</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Seth</familyName> <givenNames>N</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Engineering novel Lec1 glycosylation mutants in CHO‐DUKX cells: molecular insights and effector modulation of N‐acetylglucosaminyltransferase I</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2012">2012</pubYear>;<vol>109</vol>(<issue>7</issue>):<pageFirst>1723</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1734</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0027"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0027"><author><familyName>Goetze</familyName> <givenNames>AM</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Liu</familyName> <givenNames>YD</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Zhang</familyName> <givenNames>Z</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>High‐mannose glycans on the fc region of therapeutic IgG antibodies increase serum clearance in humans</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Glycobiology</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2011">2011</pubYear>;<vol>21</vol>(<issue>7</issue>):<pageFirst>949</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>959</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0028"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0028"><author><familyName>Shi</familyName> <givenNames>HH</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Goudar</familyName> <givenNames>CT</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Recent advances in the understanding of biological implications and modulation methodologies of monoclonal antibody N‐linked high mannose glycans</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2014">2014</pubYear>;<vol>111</vol>(<issue>10</issue>):<pageFirst>1907</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1919</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0029"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0029"><author><familyName>Liu</familyName> <givenNames>H</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Nowak</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Andrien</familyName> <givenNames>B</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Shao</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Ponniah</familyName> <givenNames>G</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Neill</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Impact of IgG fc‐oligosaccharides on recombinant monoclonal antibody structure, stability, safety, and efficacy</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Prog</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2017">2017</pubYear>;<vol>33</vol>(<issue>5</issue>):<pageFirst>1173</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1181</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0030"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0030"><author><familyName>Brady</familyName> <givenNames>LJ</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Velayudhan</familyName> <givenNames>J</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Visone</familyName> <givenNames>DB</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>The criticality of high‐resolution N‐linked carbohydrate assays and detailed characterization of antibody effector function in the context of biosimilar development</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>MAbs</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2015">2015</pubYear>;<vol>7</vol>(<issue>3</issue>):<pageFirst>562</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>570</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0031"><citation type="other" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0031"><author><familyName>Stanley</familyName> <givenNames>P</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Taniguchi</familyName> <givenNames>N</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Aebi</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>. <otherTitle>N‐glycans</otherTitle>. <i>Essentials of Glycobiology [Internet]</i> 3rd ed. <pubYear year="2017">2017</pubYear>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0032"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0032"><author><familyName>Zalai</familyName> <givenNames>D</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Hever</familyName> <givenNames>H</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Lovasz</familyName> <givenNames>K</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>A control strategy to investigate the relationship between specific productivity and high‐mannose glycoforms in CHO cells</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Appl Microbiol Biotechnol</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2016">2016</pubYear>;<vol>100</vol>(<issue>16</issue>):<pageFirst>7011</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>7024</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0033"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0033"><author><familyName>Wang</familyName> <givenNames>Q</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Chung</familyName> <givenNames>CY</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Chough</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Betenbaugh</familyName> <givenNames>MJ</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Antibody glycoengineering strategies in mammalian cells</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2018">2018</pubYear>;<vol>115</vol>(<issue>6</issue>):<pageFirst>1378</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1393</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0034"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0034"><author><familyName>Sealover</familyName> <givenNames>NR</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Davis</familyName> <givenNames>AM</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Brooks</familyName> <givenNames>JK</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>George</familyName> <givenNames>HJ</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Kayser</familyName> <givenNames>KJ</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Lin</familyName> <givenNames>N</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Engineering Chinese hamster ovary (CHO) cells for producing recombinant proteins with simple glycoforms by zinc‐finger nuclease (ZFN)‐mediated gene knockout of mannosyl (alpha‐1,3‐)‐glycoprotein beta‐1,2‐N‐acetylglucosaminyltransferase (Mgat1)</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>J Biotechnol</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2013">2013</pubYear>;<vol>167</vol>(<issue>1</issue>):<pageFirst>24</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>32</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0035"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0035"><author><familyName>Zhou</familyName> <givenNames>Q</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Shankara</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Roy</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Development of a simple and rapid method for producing non‐fucosylated oligomannose containing antibodies with increased effector function</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2008">2008</pubYear>;<vol>99</vol>(<issue>3</issue>):<pageFirst>652</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>665</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0036"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0036"><author><familyName>Kanda</familyName> <givenNames>Y</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Yamada</familyName> <givenNames>T</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Mori</familyName> <givenNames>K</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Comparison of biological activity among nonfucosylated therapeutic IgG1 antibodies with three different N‐linked fc oligosaccharides: the high‐mannose, hybrid, and complex types</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Glycobiology</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2007">2007</pubYear>;<vol>17</vol>(<issue>1</issue>):<pageFirst>104</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>118</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0037"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0037"><author><familyName>Shalel Levanon</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Aharonovitz</familyName> <givenNames>O</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Maor‐Shoshani</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Abraham</familyName> <givenNames>G</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Kenett</familyName> <givenNames>D</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Aloni</familyName> <givenNames>Y</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>An efficient method to control high mannose and core fucose levels in glycosylated antibody production using deoxymannojirimycin</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>J Biotechnol.</journalTitle> <pubYear year="2018">2018</pubYear>;<vol>276‐277</vol>:<pageFirst>54</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>62</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0038"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0038"><author><familyName>Zhang</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Tsang</familyName> <givenNames>VL</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Markely</familyName> <givenNames>LR</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Identifying the differences in mechanisms of mycophenolic acid controlling fucose content of glycoproteins expressed in different CHO cell lines</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2016">2016</pubYear>;<vol>113</vol>(<issue>11</issue>):<pageFirst>2367</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>2376</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0039"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0039"><author><familyNamePrefix>van</familyNamePrefix> <familyName>Berkel</familyName> <givenNames>PH</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Gerritsen</familyName> <givenNames>J</givenNames></author>, <author><familyNamePrefix>van</familyNamePrefix> <familyName>Voskuilen</familyName> <givenNames>E</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Rapid production of recombinant human IgG with improved ADCC effector function in a transient expression system</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2010">2010</pubYear>;<vol>105</vol>(<issue>2</issue>):<pageFirst>350</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>357</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0040"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0040"><author><familyName>Bruhlmann</familyName> <givenNames>D</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Vuillemin</familyName> <givenNames>T</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Satwekar</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Generation of site‐distinct N‐glycan variants for in vitro bioactivity testing</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2019">2019</pubYear>;<vol>116</vol>(<issue>5</issue>):<pageFirst>1017</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1028</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0041"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0041"><author><familyName>Brantley</familyName> <givenNames>TJ</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Mitchelson</familyName> <givenNames>FG</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Khattak</familyName> <givenNames>SF</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>A class of low‐cost alternatives to kifunensine for increasing high mannose N‐linked glycosylation for monoclonal antibody production in Chinese hamster ovary cells</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Prog</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2021">2021</pubYear>;<vol>37</vol>(<issue>1</issue>):<eLocator>e3076</eLocator>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0042"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0042"><author><familyName>St Amand</familyName> <givenNames>MM</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Radhakrishnan</familyName> <givenNames>D</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Robinson</familyName> <givenNames>AS</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Ogunnaike</familyName> <givenNames>BA</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Identification of manipulated variables for a glycosylation control strategy</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2014">2014</pubYear>;<vol>111</vol>(<issue>10</issue>):<pageFirst>1957</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1970</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0043"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0043"><author><familyName>Liu</familyName> <givenNames>H</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Nowak</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Shao</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Ponniah</familyName> <givenNames>G</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Neill</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Impact of cell culture on recombinant monoclonal antibody product heterogeneity</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Prog</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2016">2016</pubYear>;<vol>32</vol>(<issue>5</issue>):<pageFirst>1103</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1112</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0044"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0044"><author><familyName>Surve</familyName> <givenNames>T</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Gadgil</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Manganese increases high mannose glycoform on monoclonal antibody expressed in CHO when glucose is absent or limiting: implications for use of alternate sugars</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Prog</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2015">2015</pubYear>;<vol>31</vol>(<issue>2</issue>):<pageFirst>460</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>467</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0045"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0045"><author><familyName>Villiger</familyName> <givenNames>TK</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Roulet</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Perilleux</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Controlling the time evolution of mAb N‐linked glycosylation, part I: microbioreactor experiments</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Prog</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2016">2016</pubYear>;<vol>32</vol>(<issue>5</issue>):<pageFirst>1123</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1134</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0046"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0046"><author><familyName>Villiger</familyName> <givenNames>TK</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Scibona</familyName> <givenNames>E</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Stettler</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Broly</familyName> <givenNames>H</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Morbidelli</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Soos</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Controlling the time evolution of mAb N‐linked glycosylation ‐ part II: model‐based predictions</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Prog</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2016">2016</pubYear>;<vol>32</vol>(<issue>5</issue>):<pageFirst>1135</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1148</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0047"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0047"><author><familyName>Blondeel</familyName> <givenNames>EJM</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Aucoin</familyName> <givenNames>MG</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Supplementing glycosylation: a review of applying nucleotide‐sugar precursors to growth medium to affect therapeutic recombinant protein glycoform distributions</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Adv</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2018">2018</pubYear>;<vol>36</vol>(<issue>5</issue>):<pageFirst>1505</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1523</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0048"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0048"><author><familyName>Pacis</familyName> <givenNames>E</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Yu</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Autsen</familyName> <givenNames>J</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Bayer</familyName> <givenNames>R</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Li</familyName> <givenNames>F</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Effects of cell culture conditions on antibody N‐linked glycosylation–what affects high mannose 5 glycoform</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2011">2011</pubYear>;<vol>108</vol>(<issue>10</issue>):<pageFirst>2348</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>2358</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0049"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0049"><author><familyName>Kang</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Zhang</familyName> <givenNames>Z</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Richardson</familyName> <givenNames>J</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Metabolic markers associated with high mannose glycan levels of therapeutic recombinant monoclonal antibodies</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>J Biotechnol</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2015">2015</pubYear>;<vol>203</vol>:<pageFirst>22</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>31</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0050"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0050"><author><familyName>Prabhu</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Gadre</familyName> <givenNames>R</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Gadgil</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Zinc supplementation decreases galactosylation of recombinant IgG in CHO cells</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Appl Microbiol Biotechnol</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2018">2018</pubYear>;<vol>102</vol>(<issue>14</issue>):<pageFirst>5989</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>5999</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0051"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0051"><author><familyName>Slade</familyName> <givenNames>PG</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Caspary</familyName> <givenNames>RG</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Nargund</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Huang</familyName> <givenNames>CJ</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Mannose metabolism in recombinant CHO cells and its effect on IgG glycosylation</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2016">2016</pubYear>;<vol>113</vol>(<issue>7</issue>):<pageFirst>1468</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1480</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0052"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0052"><author><familyName>Zupke</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Brady</familyName> <givenNames>LJ</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Slade</familyName> <givenNames>PG</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Real‐time product attribute control to manufacture antibodies with defined N‐linked glycan levels</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Prog</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2015">2015</pubYear>;<vol>31</vol>(<issue>5</issue>):<pageFirst>1433</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1441</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0053"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0053"><author><familyName>Huang</familyName> <givenNames>CJ</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Lin</familyName> <givenNames>H</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Yang</familyName> <givenNames>JX</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>A robust method for increasing fc glycan high mannose level of recombinant antibodies</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2015">2015</pubYear>;<vol>112</vol>(<issue>6</issue>):<pageFirst>1200</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1209</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0054"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0054"><author><familyName>Zhang</familyName> <givenNames>L</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Wang</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Castan</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Glycan residues balance analysis ‐ GReBA: a novel model for the N‐linked glycosylation of IgG produced by CHO cells</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Metab Eng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2020">2020</pubYear>;<vol>57</vol>:<pageFirst>118</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>128</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0055"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0055"><author><familyName>Zhang</familyName> <givenNames>L</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Castan</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Stevenson</familyName> <givenNames>J</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Chatzissavidou</familyName> <givenNames>N</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Vilaplana</familyName> <givenNames>F</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Chotteau</familyName> <givenNames>V</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Combined effects of glycosylation precursors and lactate on the glycoprofile of IgG produced by CHO cells</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>J Biotechnol</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2019">2019</pubYear>;<vol>289</vol>:<pageFirst>71</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>79</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0056"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0056"><author><familyName>Kildegaard</familyName> <givenNames>HF</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Fan</familyName> <givenNames>Y</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Sen</familyName> <givenNames>JW</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Larsen</familyName> <givenNames>B</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Andersen</familyName> <givenNames>MR</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Glycoprofiling effects of media additives on IgG produced by CHO cells in fed‐batch bioreactors</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2016">2016</pubYear>;<vol>113</vol>(<issue>2</issue>):<pageFirst>359</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>366</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0057"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0057"><author><familyName>Hossler</familyName> <givenNames>P</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Racicot</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Chumsae</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>McDermott</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Cochran</familyName> <givenNames>K</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Cell culture media supplementation of infrequently used sugars for the targeted shifting of protein glycosylation profiles</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Prog</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2017">2017</pubYear>;<vol>33</vol>(<issue>2</issue>):<pageFirst>511</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>522</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0058"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0058"><author><familyName>Hossler</familyName> <givenNames>P</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>McDermott</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Racicot</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Cell culture media supplementation of uncommonly used sugars sucrose and tagatose for the targeted shifting of protein glycosylation profiles of recombinant protein therapeutics</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Prog</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2014">2014</pubYear>;<vol>30</vol>(<issue>6</issue>):<pageFirst>1419</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1431</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0059"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0059"><author><familyName>Hossler</familyName> <givenNames>P</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Chumsae</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Racicot</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Arabinosylation of recombinant human immunoglobulin‐based protein therapeutics</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>MAbs</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2017">2017</pubYear>;<vol>9</vol>(<issue>4</issue>):<pageFirst>715</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>734</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0060"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0060"><author><familyName>Bruhlmann</familyName> <givenNames>D</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Muhr</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Parker</familyName> <givenNames>R</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Cell culture media supplemented with raffinose reproducibly enhances high mannose glycan formation</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>J Biotechnol</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2017">2017</pubYear>;<vol>252</vol>:<pageFirst>32</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>42</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0061"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0061"><author><familyName>Kuwae</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Miyakawa</familyName> <givenNames>I</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Doi</familyName> <givenNames>T</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Development of a chemically defined platform fed‐batch culture media for monoclonal antibody‐producing CHO cell lines with optimized choline content</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Cytotechnology</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2018">2018</pubYear>;<vol>70</vol>(<issue>3</issue>):<pageFirst>939</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>948</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0062"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0062"><author><familyName>Pande</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Rahardjo</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Livingston</familyName> <givenNames>B</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Mujacic</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Monensin, a small molecule ionophore, can be used to increase high mannose levels on monoclonal antibodies generated by Chinese hamster ovary production cell‐lines</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2015">2015</pubYear>;<vol>112</vol>(<issue>7</issue>):<pageFirst>1383</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>1394</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0063"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0063"><author><familyName>Du</familyName> <givenNames>Z</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Treiber</familyName> <givenNames>D</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>McCarter</familyName> <givenNames>JD</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Use of a small molecule cell cycle inhibitor to control cell growth and improve specific productivity and product quality of recombinant proteins in CHO cell cultures</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2015">2015</pubYear>;<vol>112</vol>(<issue>1</issue>):<pageFirst>141</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>155</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0064"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0064"><author><familyName>Robinson</familyName> <givenNames>DK</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Chan</familyName> <givenNames>CP</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Yu Lp</familyName> <givenNames>C</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Characterization of a recombinant antibody produced in the course of a high yield fed‐batch process</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="1994">1994</pubYear>;<vol>44</vol>(<issue>6</issue>):<pageFirst>727</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>735</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0065"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0065"><author><familyName>Hooker</familyName> <givenNames>AD</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Goldman</familyName> <givenNames>MH</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Markham</familyName> <givenNames>NH</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>N‐glycans of recombinant human interferon‐gamma change during batch culture of chinese hamster ovary cells</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="1995">1995</pubYear>;<vol>48</vol>(<issue>6</issue>):<pageFirst>639</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>648</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0066"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0066"><author><familyName>Sumit</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Dolatshahi</familyName> <givenNames>S</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Chu</familyName> <givenNames>AA</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>Dissecting N‐glycosylation dynamics in Chinese hamster ovary cells fed‐batch cultures using time course omics analyses</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>iScience</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2019">2019</pubYear>;<vol>12</vol>:<pageFirst>102</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>120</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0067"><citation type="other" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0067"><author><familyName>Alessandri</familyName> <givenNames>L</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Ouellette</familyName> <givenNames>D</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Acquah</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, et al. <otherTitle>Increased serum clearance of oligomannose species present on a human IgG1 molecule</otherTitle>. Paper presented at: MAbs, <pubYear year="2012">2012</pubYear>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0068"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0068"><author><familyName>Chen</familyName> <givenNames>P</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Harcum</familyName> <givenNames>SW</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Effects of elevated ammonium on glycosylation gene expression in CHO cells</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Metab Eng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2006">2006</pubYear>;<vol>8</vol>(<issue>2</issue>):<pageFirst>123</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>132</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0069"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0069"><author><familyName>Gawlitzek</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Ryll</familyName> <givenNames>T</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Lofgren</familyName> <givenNames>J</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Sliwkowski</familyName> <givenNames>MB</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Ammonium alters N‐glycan structures of recombinant TNFR‐IgG: degradative versus biosynthetic mechanisms</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2000">2000</pubYear>;<vol>68</vol>(<issue>6</issue>):<pageFirst>637</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>646</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0070"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0070"><author><familyName>Grammatikos</familyName> <givenNames>SI</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Valley</familyName> <givenNames>U</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Nimtz</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Conradt</familyName> <givenNames>HS</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Wagner</familyName> <givenNames>R</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Intracellular UDP‐N‐acetylhexosamine pool affects N‐glycan complexity: a mechanism of ammonium action on protein glycosylation</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Prog</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="1998">1998</pubYear>;<vol>14</vol>(<issue>3</issue>):<pageFirst>410</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>419</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0071"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0071"><author><familyName>Wlaschin</familyName> <givenNames>KF</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Hu</familyName> <givenNames>W‐S</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Engineering cell metabolism for high‐density cell culture via manipulation of sugar transport</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>J Biotechnol</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2007">2007</pubYear>;<vol>131</vol>(<issue>2</issue>):<pageFirst>168</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>176</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0072"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0072"><author><familyName>Hills</familyName> <givenNames>AE</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Patel</familyName> <givenNames>A</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Boyd</familyName> <givenNames>P</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>James</familyName> <givenNames>DC</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Metabolic control of recombinant monoclonal antibody N‐glycosylation in GS‐NS0 cells</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2001">2001</pubYear>;<vol>75</vol>(<issue>2</issue>):<pageFirst>239</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>251</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0073"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0073"><author><familyName>Baker</familyName> <givenNames>KN</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Rendall</familyName> <givenNames>MH</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Hills</familyName> <givenNames>AE</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Hoare</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Freedman</familyName> <givenNames>RB</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>James</familyName> <givenNames>DC</givenNames></author>. <articleTitle>Metabolic control of recombinant protein N‐glycan processing in NS0 and CHO cells</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>Biotechnol Bioeng</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2001">2001</pubYear>;<vol>73</vol>(<issue>3</issue>):<pageFirst>188</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>202</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
<bib xml:id="btpr3176-bib-0074"><citation type="journal" xml:id="btpr3176-cit-0074"><author><familyName>Villiger</familyName> <givenNames>TK</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Steinhoff</familyName> <givenNames>RF</givenNames></author>, <author><familyName>Ivarsson</familyName> <givenNames>M</givenNames></author>, et al. <articleTitle>High‐throughput profiling of nucleotides and nucleotide sugars to evaluate their impact on antibody N‐glycosylation</articleTitle>. <journalTitle>J Biotechnol</journalTitle>. <pubYear year="2016">2016</pubYear>;<vol>229</vol>:<pageFirst>3</pageFirst>‐<pageLast>12</pageLast>.</citation></bib>
</bibliography>
</body>
</component>]]></body>
  <back>
    <ref-list>
      <ref id="0">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Walsh</surname>
              <given-names>G</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Nat Biotechnol</article-title>
          <year>2018</year>
          <volume>36</volume>
          <fpage>1136</fpage>
          <lpage>1145</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="1">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Ahmad</surname>
              <given-names>A‐S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Olech</surname>
              <given-names>E</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>McClellan</surname>
              <given-names>JE</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kirchhoff</surname>
              <given-names>CF</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <year>2016</year>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="2">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Sokolov</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ritscher</surname>
              <given-names>J</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>MacKinnon</surname>
              <given-names>N</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Prog</article-title>
          <year>2017</year>
          <volume>33</volume>
          <fpage>181</fpage>
          <lpage>191</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="3">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Ponniah</surname>
              <given-names>G</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Nowak</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gonzalez</surname>
              <given-names>N</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Miano</surname>
              <given-names>D</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Liu</surname>
              <given-names>H</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Anal Chem</article-title>
          <year>2015</year>
          <volume>87</volume>
          <fpage>2718</fpage>
          <lpage>2726</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="4">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Jefferis</surname>
              <given-names>R</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>J Immunol Res</article-title>
          <year>2016</year>
          <volume>2016</volume>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="5">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Jefferis</surname>
              <given-names>R</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Nat Rev Drug Discov</article-title>
          <year>2009</year>
          <volume>8</volume>
          <fpage>226</fpage>
          <lpage>234</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="6">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Ehret</surname>
              <given-names>J</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zimmermann</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Eichhorn</surname>
              <given-names>T</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zimmer</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2019</year>
          <volume>116</volume>
          <fpage>816</fpage>
          <lpage>830</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="7">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Higel</surname>
              <given-names>F</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Seidl</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sorgel</surname>
              <given-names>F</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Friess</surname>
              <given-names>W</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Eur J Pharm Biopharm</article-title>
          <year>2016</year>
          <volume>100</volume>
          <fpage>94</fpage>
          <lpage>100</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="8">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Liu</surname>
              <given-names>L</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>J Pharm Sci</article-title>
          <year>2015</year>
          <volume>104</volume>
          <fpage>1866</fpage>
          <lpage>1884</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="9">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Ferrara</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Grau</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Jäger</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Proc Natl Acad Sci</article-title>
          <year>2011</year>
          <volume>108</volume>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="10">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Shinkawa</surname>
              <given-names>T</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Nakamura</surname>
              <given-names>K</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yamane</surname>
              <given-names>N</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>J Biol Chem</article-title>
          <year>2003</year>
          <volume>278</volume>
          <fpage>3466</fpage>
          <lpage>3473</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="11">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Peipp</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lammerts van Bueren</surname>
              <given-names>JJ</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Schneider‐Merck</surname>
              <given-names>T</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Blood</article-title>
          <year>2008</year>
          <volume>112</volume>
          <fpage>2390</fpage>
          <lpage>2399</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="12">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Shoji‐Hosaka</surname>
              <given-names>E</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kobayashi</surname>
              <given-names>Y</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wakitani</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>J Biochem</article-title>
          <year>2006</year>
          <volume>140</volume>
          <fpage>777</fpage>
          <lpage>783</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="13">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Shields</surname>
              <given-names>RL</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lai</surname>
              <given-names>J</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Keck</surname>
              <given-names>R</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>J Biol Chem</article-title>
          <year>2002</year>
          <volume>277</volume>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="14">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Mori</surname>
              <given-names>K</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Iida</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yamane‐Ohnuki</surname>
              <given-names>N</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Cytotechnology</article-title>
          <year>2007</year>
          <volume>55</volume>
          <fpage>109</fpage>
          <lpage>114</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="15">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Elliott</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Egrie</surname>
              <given-names>J</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Browne</surname>
              <given-names>J</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Exp Hematol</article-title>
          <year>2004</year>
          <volume>32</volume>
          <fpage>1146</fpage>
          <lpage>1155</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="16">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Quast</surname>
              <given-names>I</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Keller</surname>
              <given-names>CW</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Maurer</surname>
              <given-names>MA</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>J Clin Invest</article-title>
          <year>2015</year>
          <volume>125</volume>
          <fpage>4160</fpage>
          <lpage>4170</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="17">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Chen</surname>
              <given-names>X</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Liu</surname>
              <given-names>J</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Liu</surname>
              <given-names>X</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Fan</surname>
              <given-names>L</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zhao</surname>
              <given-names>L</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Tan</surname>
              <given-names>W‐S</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Process Biochem</article-title>
          <year>2018</year>
          <volume>73</volume>
          <fpage>162</fpage>
          <lpage>169</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="18">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Lin</surname>
              <given-names>CW</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Tsai</surname>
              <given-names>MH</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Li</surname>
              <given-names>ST</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</article-title>
          <year>2015</year>
          <volume>112</volume>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="19">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Raju</surname>
              <given-names>TS</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lang</surname>
              <given-names>SE</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Curr Opin Biotechnol</article-title>
          <year>2014</year>
          <volume>30</volume>
          <fpage>147</fpage>
          <lpage>152</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="20">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Raju</surname>
              <given-names>TS</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Jordan</surname>
              <given-names>RE</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>MAbs</article-title>
          <year>2012</year>
          <volume>4</volume>
          <fpage>385</fpage>
          <lpage>391</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="21">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Reusch</surname>
              <given-names>D</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Tejada</surname>
              <given-names>ML</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Glycobiology</article-title>
          <year>2015</year>
          <volume>25</volume>
          <fpage>1325</fpage>
          <lpage>1334</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="22">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Chung</surname>
              <given-names>CY</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>Q</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yang</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2017</year>
          <volume>114</volume>
          <fpage>2848</fpage>
          <lpage>2856</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="23">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Mastrangeli</surname>
              <given-names>R</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Audino</surname>
              <given-names>MC</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Palinsky</surname>
              <given-names>W</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Broly</surname>
              <given-names>H</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Bierau</surname>
              <given-names>H</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Trends Biotechnol</article-title>
          <year>2020</year>
          <volume>38</volume>
          <fpage>1154</fpage>
          <lpage>1168</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="24">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Yu</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Brown</surname>
              <given-names>D</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Reed</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>MAbs</article-title>
          <year>2012</year>
          <volume>4</volume>
          <fpage>475</fpage>
          <lpage>487</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="25">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Zhong</surname>
              <given-names>X</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Cooley</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Seth</surname>
              <given-names>N</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2012</year>
          <volume>109</volume>
          <fpage>1723</fpage>
          <lpage>1734</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="26">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Goetze</surname>
              <given-names>AM</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Liu</surname>
              <given-names>YD</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zhang</surname>
              <given-names>Z</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Glycobiology</article-title>
          <year>2011</year>
          <volume>21</volume>
          <fpage>949</fpage>
          <lpage>959</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="27">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Shi</surname>
              <given-names>HH</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Goudar</surname>
              <given-names>CT</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2014</year>
          <volume>111</volume>
          <fpage>1907</fpage>
          <lpage>1919</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="28">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Liu</surname>
              <given-names>H</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Nowak</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Andrien</surname>
              <given-names>B</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Shao</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ponniah</surname>
              <given-names>G</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Neill</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Prog</article-title>
          <year>2017</year>
          <volume>33</volume>
          <fpage>1173</fpage>
          <lpage>1181</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="29">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Brady</surname>
              <given-names>LJ</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Velayudhan</surname>
              <given-names>J</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Visone</surname>
              <given-names>DB</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>MAbs</article-title>
          <year>2015</year>
          <volume>7</volume>
          <fpage>562</fpage>
          <lpage>570</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="30">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Stanley</surname>
              <given-names>P</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Taniguchi</surname>
              <given-names>N</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Aebi</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <year>2017</year>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="31">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Zalai</surname>
              <given-names>D</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hever</surname>
              <given-names>H</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lovasz</surname>
              <given-names>K</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Appl Microbiol Biotechnol</article-title>
          <year>2016</year>
          <volume>100</volume>
          <fpage>7011</fpage>
          <lpage>7024</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="32">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>Q</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chung</surname>
              <given-names>CY</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chough</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Betenbaugh</surname>
              <given-names>MJ</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2018</year>
          <volume>115</volume>
          <fpage>1378</fpage>
          <lpage>1393</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="33">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Sealover</surname>
              <given-names>NR</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Davis</surname>
              <given-names>AM</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Brooks</surname>
              <given-names>JK</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>George</surname>
              <given-names>HJ</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kayser</surname>
              <given-names>KJ</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lin</surname>
              <given-names>N</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>J Biotechnol</article-title>
          <year>2013</year>
          <volume>167</volume>
          <fpage>24</fpage>
          <lpage>32</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="34">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Zhou</surname>
              <given-names>Q</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Shankara</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Roy</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2008</year>
          <volume>99</volume>
          <fpage>652</fpage>
          <lpage>665</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="35">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Kanda</surname>
              <given-names>Y</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yamada</surname>
              <given-names>T</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Mori</surname>
              <given-names>K</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Glycobiology</article-title>
          <year>2007</year>
          <volume>17</volume>
          <fpage>104</fpage>
          <lpage>118</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="36">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Shalel Levanon</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Aharonovitz</surname>
              <given-names>O</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Maor‐Shoshani</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Abraham</surname>
              <given-names>G</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kenett</surname>
              <given-names>D</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Aloni</surname>
              <given-names>Y</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>J Biotechnol.</article-title>
          <year>2018</year>
          <volume>276‐277</volume>
          <fpage>54</fpage>
          <lpage>62</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="37">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Zhang</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Tsang</surname>
              <given-names>VL</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Markely</surname>
              <given-names>LR</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2016</year>
          <volume>113</volume>
          <fpage>2367</fpage>
          <lpage>2376</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="38">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Berkel</surname>
              <given-names>PH</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gerritsen</surname>
              <given-names>J</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Voskuilen</surname>
              <given-names>E</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2010</year>
          <volume>105</volume>
          <fpage>350</fpage>
          <lpage>357</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="39">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Bruhlmann</surname>
              <given-names>D</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Vuillemin</surname>
              <given-names>T</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Satwekar</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2019</year>
          <volume>116</volume>
          <fpage>1017</fpage>
          <lpage>1028</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="40">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Brantley</surname>
              <given-names>TJ</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Mitchelson</surname>
              <given-names>FG</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Khattak</surname>
              <given-names>SF</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Prog</article-title>
          <year>2021</year>
          <volume>37</volume>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="41">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>St Amand</surname>
              <given-names>MM</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Radhakrishnan</surname>
              <given-names>D</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Robinson</surname>
              <given-names>AS</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ogunnaike</surname>
              <given-names>BA</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2014</year>
          <volume>111</volume>
          <fpage>1957</fpage>
          <lpage>1970</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="42">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Liu</surname>
              <given-names>H</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Nowak</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Shao</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ponniah</surname>
              <given-names>G</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Neill</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Prog</article-title>
          <year>2016</year>
          <volume>32</volume>
          <fpage>1103</fpage>
          <lpage>1112</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="43">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Surve</surname>
              <given-names>T</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gadgil</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Prog</article-title>
          <year>2015</year>
          <volume>31</volume>
          <fpage>460</fpage>
          <lpage>467</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="44">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Villiger</surname>
              <given-names>TK</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Roulet</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Perilleux</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Prog</article-title>
          <year>2016</year>
          <volume>32</volume>
          <fpage>1123</fpage>
          <lpage>1134</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="45">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Villiger</surname>
              <given-names>TK</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Scibona</surname>
              <given-names>E</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Stettler</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Broly</surname>
              <given-names>H</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Morbidelli</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Soos</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Prog</article-title>
          <year>2016</year>
          <volume>32</volume>
          <fpage>1135</fpage>
          <lpage>1148</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="46">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Blondeel</surname>
              <given-names>EJM</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Aucoin</surname>
              <given-names>MG</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Adv</article-title>
          <year>2018</year>
          <volume>36</volume>
          <fpage>1505</fpage>
          <lpage>1523</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="47">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Pacis</surname>
              <given-names>E</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yu</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Autsen</surname>
              <given-names>J</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Bayer</surname>
              <given-names>R</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Li</surname>
              <given-names>F</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2011</year>
          <volume>108</volume>
          <fpage>2348</fpage>
          <lpage>2358</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="48">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Kang</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zhang</surname>
              <given-names>Z</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Richardson</surname>
              <given-names>J</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>J Biotechnol</article-title>
          <year>2015</year>
          <volume>203</volume>
          <fpage>22</fpage>
          <lpage>31</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="49">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Prabhu</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gadre</surname>
              <given-names>R</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gadgil</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Appl Microbiol Biotechnol</article-title>
          <year>2018</year>
          <volume>102</volume>
          <fpage>5989</fpage>
          <lpage>5999</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="50">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Slade</surname>
              <given-names>PG</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Caspary</surname>
              <given-names>RG</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Nargund</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Huang</surname>
              <given-names>CJ</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2016</year>
          <volume>113</volume>
          <fpage>1468</fpage>
          <lpage>1480</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="51">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Zupke</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Brady</surname>
              <given-names>LJ</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Slade</surname>
              <given-names>PG</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Prog</article-title>
          <year>2015</year>
          <volume>31</volume>
          <fpage>1433</fpage>
          <lpage>1441</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="52">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Huang</surname>
              <given-names>CJ</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lin</surname>
              <given-names>H</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yang</surname>
              <given-names>JX</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2015</year>
          <volume>112</volume>
          <fpage>1200</fpage>
          <lpage>1209</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="53">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Zhang</surname>
              <given-names>L</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Castan</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Metab Eng</article-title>
          <year>2020</year>
          <volume>57</volume>
          <fpage>118</fpage>
          <lpage>128</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="54">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Zhang</surname>
              <given-names>L</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Castan</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Stevenson</surname>
              <given-names>J</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chatzissavidou</surname>
              <given-names>N</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Vilaplana</surname>
              <given-names>F</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chotteau</surname>
              <given-names>V</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>J Biotechnol</article-title>
          <year>2019</year>
          <volume>289</volume>
          <fpage>71</fpage>
          <lpage>79</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="55">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Kildegaard</surname>
              <given-names>HF</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Fan</surname>
              <given-names>Y</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sen</surname>
              <given-names>JW</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Larsen</surname>
              <given-names>B</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Andersen</surname>
              <given-names>MR</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2016</year>
          <volume>113</volume>
          <fpage>359</fpage>
          <lpage>366</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="56">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Hossler</surname>
              <given-names>P</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Racicot</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chumsae</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>McDermott</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Cochran</surname>
              <given-names>K</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Prog</article-title>
          <year>2017</year>
          <volume>33</volume>
          <fpage>511</fpage>
          <lpage>522</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="57">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Hossler</surname>
              <given-names>P</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>McDermott</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Racicot</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Prog</article-title>
          <year>2014</year>
          <volume>30</volume>
          <fpage>1419</fpage>
          <lpage>1431</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="58">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Hossler</surname>
              <given-names>P</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chumsae</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Racicot</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>MAbs</article-title>
          <year>2017</year>
          <volume>9</volume>
          <fpage>715</fpage>
          <lpage>734</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="59">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Bruhlmann</surname>
              <given-names>D</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Muhr</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Parker</surname>
              <given-names>R</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>J Biotechnol</article-title>
          <year>2017</year>
          <volume>252</volume>
          <fpage>32</fpage>
          <lpage>42</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="60">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Kuwae</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Miyakawa</surname>
              <given-names>I</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Doi</surname>
              <given-names>T</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Cytotechnology</article-title>
          <year>2018</year>
          <volume>70</volume>
          <fpage>939</fpage>
          <lpage>948</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="61">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Pande</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Rahardjo</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Livingston</surname>
              <given-names>B</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Mujacic</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2015</year>
          <volume>112</volume>
          <fpage>1383</fpage>
          <lpage>1394</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="62">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Du</surname>
              <given-names>Z</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Treiber</surname>
              <given-names>D</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>McCarter</surname>
              <given-names>JD</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2015</year>
          <volume>112</volume>
          <fpage>141</fpage>
          <lpage>155</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="63">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Robinson</surname>
              <given-names>DK</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chan</surname>
              <given-names>CP</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yu Lp</surname>
              <given-names>C</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>1994</year>
          <volume>44</volume>
          <fpage>727</fpage>
          <lpage>735</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="64">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Hooker</surname>
              <given-names>AD</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Goldman</surname>
              <given-names>MH</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Markham</surname>
              <given-names>NH</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>1995</year>
          <volume>48</volume>
          <fpage>639</fpage>
          <lpage>648</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="65">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Sumit</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Dolatshahi</surname>
              <given-names>S</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chu</surname>
              <given-names>AA</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>iScience</article-title>
          <year>2019</year>
          <volume>12</volume>
          <fpage>102</fpage>
          <lpage>120</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="66">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Alessandri</surname>
              <given-names>L</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ouellette</surname>
              <given-names>D</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Acquah</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <year>2012</year>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="67">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Chen</surname>
              <given-names>P</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Harcum</surname>
              <given-names>SW</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Metab Eng</article-title>
          <year>2006</year>
          <volume>8</volume>
          <fpage>123</fpage>
          <lpage>132</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="68">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Gawlitzek</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ryll</surname>
              <given-names>T</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lofgren</surname>
              <given-names>J</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sliwkowski</surname>
              <given-names>MB</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2000</year>
          <volume>68</volume>
          <fpage>637</fpage>
          <lpage>646</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="69">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Grammatikos</surname>
              <given-names>SI</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Valley</surname>
              <given-names>U</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Nimtz</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Conradt</surname>
              <given-names>HS</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wagner</surname>
              <given-names>R</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Prog</article-title>
          <year>1998</year>
          <volume>14</volume>
          <fpage>410</fpage>
          <lpage>419</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="70">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Wlaschin</surname>
              <given-names>KF</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hu</surname>
              <given-names>W‐S</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>J Biotechnol</article-title>
          <year>2007</year>
          <volume>131</volume>
          <fpage>168</fpage>
          <lpage>176</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="71">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Hills</surname>
              <given-names>AE</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Patel</surname>
              <given-names>A</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Boyd</surname>
              <given-names>P</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>James</surname>
              <given-names>DC</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2001</year>
          <volume>75</volume>
          <fpage>239</fpage>
          <lpage>251</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="72">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Baker</surname>
              <given-names>KN</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Rendall</surname>
              <given-names>MH</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hills</surname>
              <given-names>AE</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hoare</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Freedman</surname>
              <given-names>RB</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>James</surname>
              <given-names>DC</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Biotechnol Bioeng</article-title>
          <year>2001</year>
          <volume>73</volume>
          <fpage>188</fpage>
          <lpage>202</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="73">
        <element-citation>
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Villiger</surname>
              <given-names>TK</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Steinhoff</surname>
              <given-names>RF</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ivarsson</surname>
              <given-names>M</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>J Biotechnol</article-title>
          <year>2016</year>
          <volume>229</volume>
          <fpage>3</fpage>
          <lpage>12</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
    </ref-list>
  </back>
</article>